<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_1_201" xtrc="" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title "> 
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">1.201</ph> Policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p "> 
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> An agency head may issue agency acquisition regulations that are necessary to implement the FAR, or to supplement the FAR to satisfy a specific agency need, according to 41 U.S.C. 1303(a)(2).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Agency acquisition regulations must not—</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Unnecessarily repeat, paraphrase, or otherwise restate material contained in the FAR or higher-level agency acquisition regulations; or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Conflict or be inconsistent with the FAR, except as required by law or as provided in <xref href="Subpart_1.3.dita#FAR_Subpart_1_3"
                                    class="- topic/xref "
                                    outputclass="fm:Subpart">subpart  1.3</xref>.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p "> 
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> If required by 41 U.S.C. 1707, agencies must publish their acquisition regulations for comment in the Federal Register. However, publication is not required for issuances that merely implement or supplement higher level issuances that have previously undergone the public comment process, unless such implementation or supplementation results in an additional significant cost or administrative impact on contractors or offerors or effect beyond the internal operating procedures of the issuing organization.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p "> 
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Agencies must also comply with other applicable statutes, (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. 3501, <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">et seq</i>.) and the Regulatory Flexibility Act (5 U.S.C. 601, <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">et seq</i>.)).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p "> 
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> An agency head may authorize internal agency guidance at any organizational level (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, designations and delegations of authority, assignments of responsibilities, work-flow procedures, and internal reporting requirements). Internal agency guidance does not need to be published in the Federal Register for comment, unless the agency guidance has a significant effect beyond the internal operating procedures of the agency or creates an additional significant cost or administrative impact on contractors or offerors.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p "/>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
