<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"><concept id="FAR_1_404" xtrc="" class="- topic/topic concept/concept "><title class="- topic/title "> 
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">1.404</ph> Contracting officer's representative.</title><conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody "><ol class="- topic/ol "><li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> 
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Designation</i>.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p "> 
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> The contracting officer’s representative (COR) must be nominated either by the requiring activity or according to agency procedures. The contracting officer designates and authorizes a COR, in writing and according to agency procedures. See 7.104(e), which directs the COR designation as early as possible.</p>
                  </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p "> 
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The COR designation must-</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Specify the extent of the COR's authority to act on behalf of the contracting officer;</p>
                        </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Specify the period covered by the designation;</p>
                        </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph> State the authority cannot be delegated further; and</p>
                        </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p "> <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph> State that the COR may be personally liable for unauthorized acts.</p>
                        </li></ol>
                  </li><li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                     </p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p "> 
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Contracting officers may not delegate to a COR responsibilities that are delegated to a contract administration office under 42.202. Contracting officers may assign the COR other duties described at 42.302.</p>
                        </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p "> 
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> The contracting officer must communicate the COR’s duties clearly and in writing.</p>
                        </li></ol>
                  </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> The contracting officer must send copies of the COR’s designation to the contractor and the contract administration office.</p>
                  </li></ol>
            </li><li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p "> 
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> 
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Types of contracts and orders</i>. The contracting officer must assign a COR to all contracts and orders other than firm fixed-price contracts and orders. For firm fixed-price contracts and orders, the contracting officer may assign a COR.</p>
            </li><li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> 
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">COR Qualifications</i>. The COR-</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Must be a Government employee, unless otherwise authorized in agency regulations;</p>
                  </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p "> 
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Must be certified and must maintain certification. The certification must align with the current Office of Management and Budget memorandum on the Federal Acquisition Certification for Contracting Officer Representatives (FAC-COR) guidance, or for DoD, according to DoD policy guidance; and</p>
                  </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p "> 
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Must be qualified by training and experience.</p>
                  </li></ol>
            </li><li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> 
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Lack of authority. </i>A COR has no authority to make any commitments or changes that affect price, quality, quantity, delivery, or other terms and conditions of the contract. The COR must not direct the contractor or its subcontractors to operate in conflict with the contract terms and conditions. </p>
            </li><li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph> 
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Responsibilities</i>.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> A COR assists in the technical monitoring or administration of a contract.</p>
                  </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The COR must maintain a file for each assigned contract. The file must include, at a minimum—</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol "><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> A copy of the contracting officer's letter of designation and other documents describing the COR's duties and responsibilities; and</p>
                        </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Documentation of COR actions taken according to the delegation of authority.</p>
                        </li></ol>
                  </li></ol>
            </li></ol></conbody></concept></dita>