<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_13_301" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">13.301</ph> Governmentwide commercial purchase card.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d743e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d770e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            Except as provided in <xref href="32.1108.dita#FAR_32_1108"
                        base="i1080782"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.1108</xref>(b)(2), the Governmentwide commercial purchase card is authorized for use in making and/or paying for purchases of supplies, services, or construction. The Governmentwide commercial purchase card may be used by contracting officers and other individuals designated in accordance with <xref href="1.603-3.dita#FAR_1_603_3"
                        base="i1126501"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">1.603-3</xref>. The card may be used only for purchases that are otherwise authorized by law or regulation.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d770e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            Agencies using the Governmentwide commercial purchase card shall establish procedures for use and control of the card that comply with the Treasury Financial Manual for Guidance of Departments and Agencies (TFM 4-4500) and that are consistent with the terms and conditions of the current GSA credit card contract. Agency procedures should not limit the use of the Governmentwide commercial purchase card to micro-purchases. Agency procedures should encourage use of the card in greater dollar amounts by contracting officers to place orders and to pay for purchases against contracts established under <xref href="Part_8.dita#FAR_Part_8"
                        base="i1118293"
                        outputclass="fm:Part"
                        class="- topic/xref ">part  8</xref> procedures, when authorized; and to place orders and/or make payment under other contractual instruments, when agreed to by the contractor. See <xref href="32.1110.dita#FAR_32_1110"
                        base="i1080821"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.1110</xref>(d) for instructions for use of the appropriate clause when payment under a written contract will be made through use of the card.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d770e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            The Governmentwide commercial purchase card may be used to-</p>
               <ol id="d743e53" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d770e38">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Make micro-purchases;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d770e43">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Place a task or delivery order (if authorized in the basic contract, basic ordering agreement, or blanket purchase agreement); or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d770e48">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
								                Make payments, when the contractor agrees to accept payment by the card (but see <xref href="32.1108.dita#FAR_32_1108"
                              base="i1080782"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">32.1108</xref>(b)(2)).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
