<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_14_209" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">14.209</ph> Cancellation of invitations before opening.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d814e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d841e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            The cancellation of an invitation for bids usually involves a loss of time, effort, and money spent by the Government and bidders. Invitations should not be cancelled unless cancellation is clearly in the public interest; <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>,</p>
               <ol id="d814e26" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d841e19">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Where there is no longer a requirement for the supplies or services; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d841e24">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Where amendments to the invitation would be of such magnitude that a new invitation is desirable.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d841e29">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            When an invitation issued other than electronically is cancelled, bids that have been received shall be returned unopened to the bidders and notice of cancellation shall be sent to all prospective bidders to whom invitations were issued. When an invitation issued electronically is cancelled, a general notice of cancellation shall be posted electronically, the bids received shall not be viewed, and the bids shall be purged from primary and backup data storage systems.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d841e34">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            The notice of cancellation shall-(1) identify the invitation for bids by number and short title or subject matter, (2) briefly explain the reason the invitation is being cancelled, and (3) where appropriate, assure prospective bidders that they will be given an opportunity to bid on any resolicitation of bids or any future requirements for the type of supplies or services involved. Cancellations shall be recorded in accordance with <xref href="14.403.dita#FAR_14_403"
                        base="i1109733"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">14.403</xref>(d).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
