<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_14_405" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">14.405</ph> Minor informalities or irregularities in bids.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">A minor informality or irregularity is one that is merely a matter of form and not of substance. It also pertains to some immaterial defect in a bid or variation of a bid from the exact requirements of the invitation that can be corrected or waived without being prejudicial to other bidders. The defect or variation is immaterial when the effect on price, quantity, quality, or delivery is negligible when contrasted with the total cost or scope of the supplies or services being acquired. The contracting officer either shall give the bidder an opportunity to cure any deficiency resulting from a minor informality or irregularity in a bid or waive the deficiency, whichever is to the advantage of the Government. Examples of minor informalities or irregularities include failure of a bidder to-</p>
         <ol id="d837e16" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e12">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            Return the number of copies of signed bids required by the invitation;</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e17">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            Furnish required information concerning the number of its employees;</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e22">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            Sign its bid, but only if-</p>
               <ol id="d837e44" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e28">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                The unsigned bid is accompanied by other material indicating the bidder’s intention to be bound by the unsigned bid (such as the submission of a bid guarantee or a letter signed by the bidder, with the bid, referring to and clearly identifying the bid itself); or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e33">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                The firm submitting a bid has formally adopted or authorized, before the date set for opening of bids, the execution of documents by typewritten, printed, or stamped signature and submits evidence of such authorization and the bid carries such a signature;</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e38">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            Acknowledge receipt of an amendment to an invitation for bids, but only if-</p>
               <ol id="d837e74" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e44">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                The bid received clearly indicates that the bidder received the amendment, such as where the amendment added another item to the invitation and the bidder submitted a bid on the item; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e49">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                The amendment involves only a matter of form or has either no effect or merely a negligible effect on price, quantity, quality, or delivery of the item bid upon; and</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d864e54">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
						            Execute the representations with respect to Equal Opportunity and Affirmative Action Programs, as set forth in the clauses at <xref href="52.222-22.dita#FAR_52_222_22"
                        base="i1055729"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.222-22</xref>, Previous Contracts and Compliance Reports, and <xref href="52.222-25.dita#FAR_52_222_25"
                        base="i1055782"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.222-25</xref>, Affirmative Action Compliance.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
