<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_15_507" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">15.507</ph> Protests against award.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d933e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d961e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            Protests against award in negotiated acquisitions shall be handled in accordance with <xref href="Part_33.dita#FAR_Part_33"
                        base="i1080637"
                        outputclass="fm:Part"
                        class="- topic/xref ">part  33</xref>. Use of agency protest procedures that incorporate the alternative dispute resolution provisions of Executive Order 12979 is encouraged for both preaward and postaward protests.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d961e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            If a protest causes the agency, within 1 year of contract award, to-</p>
               <ol id="d933e35" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d961e24">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Issue a new solicitation on the protested contract award, the contracting officer shall provide the information in paragraph (c) of this section to all prospective offerors for the new solicitation; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d961e29">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Issue a new request for revised proposals on the protested contract award, the contracting officer shall provide the information in paragraph (c) of this section to offerors that were in the competitive range and are requested to submit revised proposals.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d961e34">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            The following information will be provided to appropriate parties:</p>
               <ol id="d933e65" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d961e40">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Information provided to unsuccessful offerors in any debriefings conducted on the original award regarding the successful offeror’s proposal; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d961e45">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Other nonproprietary information that would have been provided to the original offerors.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
