<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <topic id="FAR_16_500" class="- topic/topic ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">16.500</ph> Scope of subpart.</title>
      <body class="- topic/body ">
         <ol id="d1010e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1038e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            This subpart prescribes policies and procedures for making awards of indefinite-delivery contracts and establishes a preference for making multiple awards of indefinite-quantity contracts.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1038e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            This subpart does not limit the use of other than competitive procedures authorized by <xref href="Part_6.dita#FAR_Part_6"
                        base="i1120119"
                        outputclass="fm:Part"
                        class="- topic/xref ">part  6</xref>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1038e23">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            Nothing in this subpart restricts the authority of the General Services Administration (GSA) to enter into schedule, multiple award, or task or delivery order contracts under any other provision of law. Therefore, GSA regulations and the coverage for the Federal Supply Schedule program in <xref href="Subpart_8.4.dita#FAR_Subpart_8_4"
                        base="i1117301"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  8.4</xref> and <xref href="Part_38.dita#FAR_Part_38"
                        base="i1077352"
                        outputclass="fm:Part"
                        class="- topic/xref ">part  38</xref> take precedence over this subpart.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1038e34">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            The statutory multiple award preference implemented by this subpart does not apply to architect-engineer contracts subject to the procedures in <xref href="Subpart_36.6.dita#FAR_Subpart_36_6"
                        base="i1078280"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  36.6</xref>. However, agencies are not precluded from making multiple awards for architect-engineer services using the procedures in this subpart, provided the selection of contractors and placement of orders are consistent with <xref href="Subpart_36.6.dita#FAR_Subpart_36_6"
                        base="i1078280"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  36.6</xref>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1038e45">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
						            See <xref href="Subpart_19.5.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_5"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  19.5</xref> for procedures to set aside part or parts of multiple-award contracts for small businesses; to reserve one or more awards for small business on multiple-award contracts; and to set aside orders for small businesses under multiple-award contracts.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </body>
   </topic>
</dita>
