<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_17_105_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">17.105-1</ph> Uses.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1040e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Except for DoD, NASA, and the Coast Guard, the contracting officer may enter into a multi-year contract if the head of the contracting activity determines that-</p>
               <ol id="d1040e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                The need for the supplies or services is reasonably firm and continuing over the period of the contract; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                A multi-year contract will serve the best interests of the United States by encouraging full and open competition or promoting economy in administration, performance, and operation of the agency’s programs.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            For DoD, NASA, and the Coast Guard, the head of the agency may enter into a multi-year contract for supplies if-</p>
               <ol id="d1040e53" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e32">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                The use of such a contract will result in significant savings of the total estimated costs of carrying out the program through annual contracts;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e37">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                The minimum need to be purchased is expected to remain substantially unchanged during the contemplated contract period in terms of production rate, procurement rate, and total quantities;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e42">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                There is a stable design for the supplies to be acquired, and the technical risks associated with such supplies are not excessive;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
								                There is a reasonable expectation that, throughout the contemplated contract period, the head of the agency will request funding for the contract at a level to avoid contract cancellation; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e52">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
								                The estimates of both the cost of the contract and the cost avoidance through the use of a multi-year contract are realistic.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e57">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The multi-year contracting method may be used for the acquisition of supplies or services.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1068e62">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            If funds are not appropriated to support the succeeding years’ requirements, the agency must cancel the contract.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
