<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_19_1505" xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">19.1505</ph> Set-aside procedures.</title>
      <conbody>
         <ol id="d1253e13">
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            The contracting officer-</p>
               <ol id="d1253e23">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e16">
                        (1)
                        
								                Shall comply with <xref href="19.203.dita#FAR_19_203"
                              base="i1101696"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.203</xref> before deciding to set aside an acquisition under the WOSB Program;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li props="Runin">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e24">
                        (2)
                     </p>
                     <ol id="d1253e45">
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e30">
                              (i) May set aside acquisitions exceeding the micro-purchase threshold for competition restricted to EDWOSB concerns when the acquisition is assigned a NAICS code in which SBA has determined that WOSB concerns are underrepresented in Federal procurement; or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e35">
                              (ii) Is assigned a NAICS code in which SBA has determined that WOSB concerns are substantially underrepresented in Federal procurement, as specified on SBA’s Web site at <xref href="http://www.sba.gov/WOSB" format="html" scope="external">http://www.sba.gov/WOSB</xref>.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e43">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            For requirements in NAICS codes designated by SBA as underrepresented, a contracting officer may restrict competition to EDWOSB concerns if the contracting officer has a reasonable expectation based on market research that-</p>
               <ol id="d1253e80">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e49">
                        (1)
                        
								                Two or more EDWOSB concerns will submit offers for the contract and;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e54">
                        (2)
                        
								                Contract award will be made at a fair and reasonable price.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e59">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            A contracting officer may restrict competition to WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program (including EDWOSB concerns), for requirements in NAICS codes designated by SBA as substantially underrepresented if there is a reasonable expectation based on market research that-</p>
               <ol id="d1253e110">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e65">
                        (1)
                        
								                Two or more WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program (including EDWOSB concerns), will submit offers and;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e70">
                        (2)
                        
								                Contract award may be made at a fair and reasonable price.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e74">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  An EDWOSB or WOSB concern may submit an offer under an EDWOSB or WOSB set-aside when the offeror—
               </p>
               <ol>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e83">
                        (1) Qualifies as a small business concern under the size standard corresponding to the NAICS code assigned to the contract; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li props="Runin">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e88">
                        (2)
                     </p>
                     <ol>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e93">
                              (i) For an EDWOSB set-aside, is certified pursuant to <xref href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.300"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external">13 CFR 127.300</xref> as an EDWOSB or has a pending application for EDWOSB certification in the DSBS (see <xref href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.504#p-127.504(a)"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external">13 CFR 127.504(a)</xref>); or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e104">
                              (ii) For a WOSB set-aside, is certified pursuant to <xref href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.300"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external">13 CFR 127.300</xref> as an EDWOSB or WOSB, or has a pending application for EDWOSB or WOSB certification in the DSBS (see <xref href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.504#p-127.504(a)"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external">13 CFR 127.504(a)</xref>).</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e115">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  The contracting officer shall verify that offers received are eligible for consideration for award by checking SAM to see if the EDWOSB or WOSB concern is designated as a certified concern or checking DSBS for a pending application for certification.
               </p>
               <ol>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e124">
                        (1) If the offeror is designated as certified in SAM or has a pending application for certification in DSBS, proceed with the offer evaluation.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e129">
                        (2) Unless the offeror is designated as certified in SAM or has a pending application for certification in DSBS, the offer is not eligible for award and shall be removed from consideration.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e134">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  Prior to award, the contracting officer shall verify the apparently successful offeror is certified in SAM, or has a pending application for certification in DSBS. If the apparently successful offeror's EDWOSB or WOSB certification is pending in DSBS, the contracting officer shall notify SBA's Director/Government Contracting by email at <i>
                     <xref href="mailto:WOSBpendingcertification@sba.gov"
                           format="gov"
                           scope="external">WOSBpendingcertification@sba.gov</xref>,</i> and request SBA's status determination. The contracting officer shall provide SBA with the offeror's name, unique entity identifier, type of set-aside, NAICS code, and solicitation number.
               </p>
               <ol>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e148">
                        (1) Within 15 calendar days from the date of the contracting officer's notification, SBA will make a determination regarding the offeror's status as an EDWOSB or WOSB eligible under the WOSB program.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e153">
                        (2) If the contracting officer does not receive a determination from SBA within 15 calendar days, the contracting officer at their discretion, may provide SBA additional time to make a determination, or may proceed with award to the next highest evaluated offeror.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e158">
                        (3) The contracting officer shall not make award to an offeror who is not a certified EDWOSB or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB program.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1289e163">
                  (g) The contracting officer may make an award, if only one acceptable offer is received from a qualified EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e88">
                  (h) If no acceptable offers are received from an EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program, the set-aside shall be withdrawn and the requirement, if still valid, must be considered for set aside in accordance with <xref href="19.203.dita#FAR_19_203"
                        base="i1101696"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.203</xref> and subpart <xref href="Subpart_19.5.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_5"
                        base="i1100723"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.5</xref>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e99">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                  The SBA procurement center representative (PCR) may recommend use of the WOSB Program. If the contracting officer rejects a recommendation by SBA's PCR—
               </p>
               <ol id="d1253e177">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e105">
                        (1)
                        The contracting officer shall notify the PCR as soon as practicable;
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e110">
                        (2)
                        
								                SBA shall notify the contracting officer of its intent to appeal the contracting officer’s decision no later than five business days after receiving notice of the contracting officer’s decision;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e115">
                        (3)
                        
								                The contracting officer shall suspend further action regarding the procurement until the head of the agency issues a written decision on the appeal, unless the head of the agency makes a written determination that urgent and compelling circumstances which significantly affect the interests of the United States compel award of the contract;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e120">
                        (4)
                        
								                Within 15 business days of SBA’s notification to the head of the contracting activity, SBA shall file a formal appeal to the head of the agency, or the appeal will be determined withdrawn; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1288e125">
                        (5)
                        
								                The head of the agency, or designee, shall specify in writing the reasons for a denial of an appeal brought under this section.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
