<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_19_202_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">19.202-1</ph> Encouraging small
business participation in acquisitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">Small business concerns shall be afforded an equitable
opportunity to compete for all contracts that they can perform to
the extent consistent with the Government’s interest. When applicable,
the contracting officer shall take the following actions:</p>
         <ol id="d1132e16" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e12">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> Divide
proposed acquisitions of supplies and services (except construction)
into reasonably small lots (not less than economic production runs)
to permit offers on quantities less than the total requirement.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e17">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  Plan acquisitions such that, if practicable, more than one small business concern may perform the work, if the work exceeds the amount for which a surety may be guaranteed by SBA against loss under <xref href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title15-section694&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">15 U.S.C. 694b</xref> (see definition of “Applicable Statutory Limit” at <xref href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-115.10"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">13 CFR 115.10</xref>).
               </p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e25">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> Ensure
that delivery schedules are established on a realistic basis that
will encourage small business participation to the extent consistent
with the actual requirements of the Government.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e30">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> Encourage
prime contractors to subcontract with small business concerns (see <xref href="Subpart_19.7.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_7"
                        base="i1100205"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  19.7</xref>).</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e38">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d1132e68" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e43">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Provide
a copy of the proposed acquisition package and other reasonably
obtainable information related to the acquisition to the SBA PCR
(or, if a PCR is not assigned, see <xref href="19.402.dita#FAR_19_402"
                              base="i1101041"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.402</xref>(a))
at least 30 days prior to the issuance of the solicitation if—</p>
                     <ol id="d1132e81" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e52">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> The
proposed acquisition is for supplies or services currently being
provided by a small business and the proposed acquisition is of
a quantity or estimated dollar value, the magnitude of which makes
it unlikely that small businesses can compete for the prime contract;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e57">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> The proposed
acquisition is for construction and seeks to package or consolidate
discrete construction projects and the magnitude of this consolidation
makes it unlikely that small businesses can compete for the prime
contract;
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e62">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph> The proposed
acquisition is for a consolidated or bundled requirement. (See <xref href="7.107-5.dita#FAR_7_107_5"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">7.107-5</xref>(a)
for mandatory 30-day notice requirement to incumbent small business
concerns.) The contracting officer shall provide all information relative
to the justification for the consolidation or bundling, including
the acquisition plan or strategy, and if the acquisition involves
substantial bundling, the information identified in <xref href="7.107-4.dita#FAR_7_107_4"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">7.107-4</xref>.
The contracting officer shall also provide the same information
to the agency Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization: or
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e73">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              The
acquisition will be reviewed at the PCR's discretion.
                           </p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e78">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        For acquisitions described
in paragraph (e)(1)(i) through (iii) of this section, provide a
statement explaining why the—
                     </p>
                     <ol id="d1132e135" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e84">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Proposed acquisition
cannot be divided into reasonably small lots (not less than economic
production runs) to permit offers on quantities less than the total
requirement;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e89">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Delivery
schedules cannot be established on a realistic basis that will encourage
small business participation to the extent consistent with the actual
requirements of the Government;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e94">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph> Proposed
acquisition cannot be structured so as to make it likely that small
businesses can compete for the prime contract;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e99">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph> Consolidated
construction project cannot be acquired as separate discrete projects;
or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e104">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph> Consolidation
or bundling is necessary and justified.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e109">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Process
the 30-day notification concurrently with other processing steps
required prior to the issuance of the solicitation.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1161e114">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> If the contracting officer rejects the SBA PCR’s recommendation made in accordance with <xref href="19.402.dita#FAR_19_402"
                              base="i1101041"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.402</xref>(c)(2), document the basis for the rejection and notify the SBA PCR in accordance with <xref href="19.502-8.dita#FAR_19_502_8"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.502-8</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
