<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_19_705_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">19.705-1</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1184e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1216e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The contracting officer may encourage the development of increased subcontracting opportunities in negotiated acquisition by providing monetary incentives such as payments based on actual subcontracting achievement or award-fee contracting (see the clause at <xref href="52.219-10.dita#FAR_52_219_10"
                        base="i1057667"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.219-10</xref>, Incentive Subcontracting Program, and <xref href="19.708.dita#FAR_19_708"
                        base="i1100497"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.708</xref>(c)). When using any contractual incentive provision based upon rewarding the contractor monetarily for exceeding goals in the subcontracting plan, the contracting officer must ensure that (a) the goals are realistic and (b) any rewards for exceeding the goals are commensurate with the efforts the contractor would not have otherwise expended. Incentive provisions should normally be negotiated after reaching final agreement with the contractor on the subcontracting plan.</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1216e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d1184e38" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1216e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Except where a contractor has a commercial plan, the contracting officer shall require a subcontracting plan for each indefinite-delivery, indefinite-quantity contract (including task or delivery order contracts, FSS, GWACs, and MACs), when the estimated value of the contract meets the subcontracting plan thresholds at <xref href="19.702.dita#FAR_19_702"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.702</xref>(a) and small business subcontracting opportunities exist.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1216e34">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Contracting officers placing orders may establish small business subcontracting goals for each order. Establishing goals shall not be in the form of a new subcontracting plan as a contract may not have more than one plan (<xref href="19.705-2.dita#FAR_19_705_2"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.705-2</xref>(e)).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
