<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_1503" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">22.1503</ph> Procedures for acquiring
end products on the List of Products Requiring Contractor Certification
as to Forced or Indentured Child Labor.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1457e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                   When issuing a solicitation for
supplies expected to exceed the micro-purchase threshold, the contracting
officer must check the List of Products Requiring Contractor Certification
as to Forced or Indentured Child Labor (the List) ( <xref href="http://www.dol.gov/ilab/"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">www.dol.gov/ilab/</xref>) (see <xref href="22.1505.dita#FAR_22_1505"
                        base="i1095872"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1505</xref>(a)). Appearance
of a product on the List is not a bar to purchase of any such product
mined, produced, or manufactured in the identified country, but
rather is an alert that there is a reasonable basis to believe that
such product may have been mined, produced, or manufactured by forced
or indentured child labor.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                   The requirements
of this subpart that result from the appearance of any end product
on the List do not apply to a solicitation or contract if the identified
country of origin on the List is-</p>
               <ol id="d1457e38" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e35">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        Israel, and the anticipated value of the acquisition is $50,000 or more (see <xref href="25.406.dita#FAR_25_406"
                              base="i1092824"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">25.406</xref>);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e43">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Mexico, and the anticipated
                        value of the acquisition is $102,280
                        or more (see <xref href="Subpart_25.4.dita#FAR_Subpart_25_4"
                              base="i1092400"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  25.4</xref>); or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e51">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Armenia, Aruba, Australia,
                        Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Canada, Croatia, Cyprus,
                        Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France,
                        Germany, Greece, Hong Kong, Hungary, Iceland, Ireland,
                        Italy, Japan, Korea, Latvia, Liechtenstein, Lithuania,
                        Luxembourg, Malta, Moldova, Montenegro, Netherlands, New
                        Zealand, North Macedonia, Norway, Poland, Portugal,
                        Romania, Singapore, Slovak Republic, Slovenia, Spain,
                        Sweden, Switzerland, Taiwan, Ukraine, or the United
                        Kingdom and the anticipated value of the acquisition is $174,000
                        or more (see <xref href="25.402.dita#FAR_25_402"
                              base="i1092636"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">25.402</xref>(b)).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e59">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                   Except
as provided in paragraph (b) of this section, before the contracting
officer may make an award for an end product (regardless of country
of origin) of a type identified by country of origin on the List
the offeror must certify that-</p>
               <ol id="d1457e98" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e65">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                         It will not
supply any end product on the List that was mined, produced, or
manufactured in a country identified on the List for that product,
as specified in the solicitation by the contracting officer in the
Certification Regarding Knowledge of Child Labor for Listed End
Products; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e70">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                     </p>
                     <ol id="d1457e117" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e75">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                               It
has made a good faith effort to determine whether forced or indentured
child labor was used to mine, produce, or manufacture any end product
to be furnished under the contract that is on the List and was mined,
produced, or manufactured in a country identified on the List for
that product; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e80">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                               On the
basis of those efforts, the offeror is unaware of any such use of
child labor.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e85">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                   Absent
any actual knowledge that the certification is false, the contracting
officer must rely on the offerors’ certifications in making award
decisions.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e90">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                   Whenever
a contracting officer has reason to believe that forced or indentured
child labor was used to mine, produce, or manufacture an end product
furnished pursuant to a contract awarded subject to the certification
required in paragraph (c) of this section, the contracting officer
must refer the matter for investigation by the agency’s Inspector
General, the Attorney General, or the Secretary of the Treasury,
whichever is determined appropriate in accordance with agency procedures,
except to the extent that the end product is from the country listed
in paragraph (b) of this section, under a contract exceeding the
applicable threshold.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1479e95">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                   Proper
certification will not prevent the head of an agency from imposing
remedies in accordance with section <xref href="22.1504.dita#FAR_22_1504"
                        base="i1095849"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1504</xref>(a)(4) if it is
later discovered that the contractor has furnished an end product
or component that has in fact been mined, produced, or manufactured,
wholly or in part, using forced or indentured child labor.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
