<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_1013" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">22.1013</ph> Review of wage determination.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1398e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1434e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Based on incumbent collective bargaining agreement.</i> (1)If wages, fringe benefits, or periodic increases provided for in a collective bargaining agreement vary substantially from those prevailing for similar services in the locality, the contracting officer shall immediately contact the agency labor advisor to consider instituting the procedures in <xref href="22.1021.dita#FAR_22_1021"
                        base="i1097053"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1021</xref>.</p>
               <ol id="d1398e29" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1434e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                If the contracting officer believes that an incumbent or predecessor contractor’s agreement was not the result of arm’s length negotiations, the contracting officer shall contact the agency labor advisor to determine appropriate action.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1434e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Based on other than incumbent collective bargaining agreement.</i> Upon receiving a wage determination not predicated upon a collective bargaining agreement, the contracting officer shall ascertain-</p>
               <ol id="d1398e53" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1434e34">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                If the wage determination does not conform with wages and fringe benefits prevailing for similar services in the locality; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1434e39">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                If the wage determination contains significant errors or omissions. If either subparagraph (b)(1) or (b)(2) of this section is evident, the contracting officer shall contact the agency labor advisor to determine appropriate action.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
