<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_1604" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">22.1604</ph> Compliance evaluation and complaint investigations and sanctions for violations.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1465e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1487e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The Secretary may conduct compliance evaluations or investigate complaints of any contractor or subcontractor to determine if any of the requirements of the clause at <xref href="52.222-40.dita#FAR_52_222_40"
                        base="i1056304"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.222-40</xref> have been violated.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1487e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Contracting departments and agencies shall cooperate with the Secretary and provide such information and assistance as the Secretary may require in the performance of the Secretary’s functions.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1487e23">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            If the Secretary determines that there has been a violation, the Secretary may take such actions as set forth in <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">29 CFR 471.14</ph>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1487e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            The Secretary may not terminate or suspend a contract or suspend or debar a contractor if the agency head has provided written objections, which must include a statement of reasons for the objection and a finding that the contractor’s performance is essential to the agency’s mission, and continues to object to the imposition of such sanctions and penalties. Procedures for enforcement by the Secretary are set out in <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">29 CFR 471.10</ph> through <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">29 CFR 471.16</ph>.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
