<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_1012_2" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">22.1012-2</ph> Wage determinations
based on collective bargaining agreements.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1397e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1433e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> In sealed bidding, a new or changed
collective bargaining agreement shall not be effective under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> if
the contracting agency has received notice of the terms of the new
or changed collective bargaining agreement less than 10 days before
bid opening and the contracting officer determines that there is
not reasonable time to incorporate the new or changed terms of the
collective bargaining agreement in the solicitation.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1433e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> For contractual
actions other than sealed bidding, a new or changed collective bargaining
agreement shall not be effective under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> if
notice of the terms of the new or changed collective bargaining
agreement is received by the contracting agency after award of a
successor contract or a modification as specified in <xref href="22.1007.dita#FAR_22_1007"
                        base="i1096782"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1007</xref>(b), provided that
the contract start of performance is within 30 days of the award
of the contract or of the specified modification. If the contract does
not specify a start of performance date which is within 30 days
of the award of the contract or of the specified modification, or
if contract performance does not commence within 30 days of the
award of the contract or of the specified modification, any notice
of the terms of a new or changed collective bargaining agreement
received by the agency not less than 10 days before commencement
of the work shall be effective for purposes of the successor contract
under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1433e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> The limitations
in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection shall apply only if
timely notification required in <xref href="22.1010.dita#FAR_22_1010"
                        base="i1096936"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1010</xref> has
been given.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1433e40">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> If the
contracting officer has submitted an e98 to Department of Labor
requesting a wage determination based on a collective bargaining
agreement and has not received a response from the Department of
Labor within 10 days, the contracting officer shall contact the
Wage and Hour Division by telephone to determine when the wage determination
can be expected. (The telephone number is provided on the e98 website.)
If the Department of Labor is unable to provide the wage determination
by the latest date needed to maintain the acquisition schedule,
the contracting officer shall incorporate the collective bargaining
agreement itself in a solicitation or other contract action (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> exercise
of option) and include a wage determination referencing that collective
bargaining agreement created by use of the Wage Determinations at <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">SAM.gov</i>
                   website
(see <xref href="22.1008-1.dita#FAR_22_1008_1"
                        base="i1096794"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1008-1</xref>(d)(2)).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
