<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_2104" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">22.2104</ph> Exclusions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">The following are excluded from coverage under this subpart:</p>
         <ol id="d1493e16" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1515e12">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Employees performing in connection with contracts covered by the E.O. for less than 20 percent of their work hours in a given workweek. This exclusion is inapplicable to employees performing on contracts covered by the E.O., i.e., those employees directly engaged in performing the specific work called for by the contract, at any point during the workweek (see 29 CFR <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref "
                        base="id1617MA02013"
                        href="Subpart_13.4.dita#FAR_Subpart_13_4">13.4</xref>(e)).</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1515e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Until the earlier of the date the agreement terminates or January 1, 2020, employees whose covered work is governed by a collective bargaining agreement ratified before September 30, 2016, that-</p>
               <ol id="d1493e35" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1515e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Already provides 56 hours (or 7 days, if the agreement refers to days rather than hours) of paid sick time (or paid time off that may be used for reasons related to sickness or health care) each year; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1515e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Provides less than 56 hours (or 7 days, if the agreement refers to days rather than hours) of paid sick time (or paid time off that may be used for reasons related to sickness or health care) each year, provided that each year the contractor provides covered employees with the difference between 56 hours (or 7 days) and the amount provided under the existing agreement in accordance with 29 CFR <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref "
                              base="id1617MA02013"
                              href="Subpart_13.4.dita#FAR_Subpart_13_4">13.4</xref>(f).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1515e39">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The Government's unilateral exercise of a pre-negotiated option to renew an existing contract that does not contain the clause at <xref href="52.222-62.dita#FAR_52_222_62"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.222-62</xref> will not automatically trigger the application of that clause. (See definition of "new contract" at 29 CFR <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref "
                        base="i1111868"
                        href="Subpart_13.2.dita#FAR_Subpart_13_2">13.2</xref>).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
