<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_503">
      <title>
         <ph props="autonumber">22.503</ph>
         <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024"><?FM MARKER [CaseNumber] FAR Case 2022–003?>Policy.<?FM MARKER [Why] Revise section 22.503.?></ph>
      </title>
      <conbody>
         <ol id="d1329e13">
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1365e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">Executive Order (E.O.) 14063, Use of Project Labor Agreements for Federal Construction Projects, requires agencies to use project labor agreements in large-scale construction projects to promote economy and efficiency in the administration and completion of Federal construction projects.</ph>
               </p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1365e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">When awarding a contract in connection with a large-scale construction project (see <xref href="22.502.dita#FAR_22_502" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">22.502</xref>), agencies shall require use of project labor agreements for contractors and subcontractors engaged in construction on the project, unless an exception at <xref href="22.504.dita#FAR_22_504" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">22.504</xref>(d) applies.</ph>
               </p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1365e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">An agency may require the use of a project labor agreement on projects where the total cost to the Federal Government is less than that for a large-scale construction project, if appropriate.</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d1329e62">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1365e37">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">An agency may, if appropriate, require that every contractor and subcontractor engaged in construction on the project agree, for that project, to negotiate or become a party to a project labor agreement with one or more labor organizations if the agency decides that the use of project labor agreements will—</ph>
                     </p>
                     <ol>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e45">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">Advance the Federal Government's interest in achieving economy and efficiency in Federal procurement, producing labor-management stability, and ensuring compliance with laws and regulations governing safety and health, equal employment opportunity, labor and employment standards, and other matters; and</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e51">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">Be consistent with law.</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1365e42">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">Agencies may consider the following factors in deciding whether the use of a project labor agreement is appropriate for a construction project where the total cost to the Federal Government is less than that for a large-scale construction project:</ph>
                     </p>
                     <ol>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e64">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">The project will require multiple construction contractors and/or subcontractors employing workers in multiple crafts or trades.</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e70">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">There is a shortage of skilled labor in the region in which the construction project will be sited.</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e76">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">Completion of the project will require an extended period of time.</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e82">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">Project labor agreements have been used on comparable projects undertaken by Federal, State, municipal, or private entities in the geographic area of the project.</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e88">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">A project labor agreement will promote the agency's long term program interests, such as facilitating the training of a skilled workforce to meet the agency's future construction needs.</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e94">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">Any other factors that the agency decides are appropriate.</ph>
                           </p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1368e100">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        <ph rev="FAC 2024-02 January 22, 2024">For indefinite-delivery indefinite-quantity (IDIQ) contracts the use of a project labor agreement may be required on an order-by-order basis rather than for the entire contract. For an order at or above $35 million an agency shall require the use of a project labor agreement unless an exception applies. See <xref href="22.504.dita#FAR_22_504" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">22.504</xref>(d)(3) and <xref href="22.505.dita#FAR_22_505" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">22.505</xref>(b)(3).</ph>
                     </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
