<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="FAR_25_201"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">25.201</ph> Policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1623e10" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  Except as provided in <xref href="25.202.dita#FAR_25_202"
                        base="i1093069"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">25.202</xref>, use only domestic
construction materials in construction contracts performed in the United
States.
               </p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1623e18" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>The Buy American statute restricts
the purchase of construction materials that are not domestic construction
materials. For manufactured construction materials, the Buy American
statute and E.O. 13881 use a two-part test to define domestic construction
materials.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1623e24" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        The article must be manufactured
in the United States; and
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1623e29" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                     </p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1623e34" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              Except for construction
material that consists wholly or predominantly of iron or steel
or a combination of both, the cost of domestic components must exceed
55 percent of the cost of all the components. In accordance with
41 U.S.C. 1907, this domestic content test of the Buy American statute
has been waived for acquisitions of COTS items (see 12.505(a)).
                           </p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1623e39" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>For construction material that
consists wholly or predominantly of iron or steel or a combination
of both, the cost of foreign iron and steel must constitute less
than 5 percent of the cost of all the components used in such construction
material (see the definition of "foreign iron and steel" at 25.003).
The cost of foreign iron and steel includes but is not limited to
the cost of foreign iron or steel mill products (such as bar, billet,
slab, wire, plate, or sheet), castings, or forgings utilized in
the manufacture of the construction material and a good faith estimate
of the cost of all foreign iron or steel components excluding COTS
fasteners. This domestic content test of the Buy American statute
has not been waived for acquisitions of COTS items in this category,
except for COTS fasteners.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
