<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_25_503" xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">25.503</ph> Group offers.</title>
      <conbody>
         <ol id="d1633e13">
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            If the solicitation or an offer specifies that award can be made only on a group of line items or on all line items contained in the solicitation or offer, reject the offer-</p>
               <ol id="d1633e23">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1656e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> If any part of the award
                        would consist of prohibited end products (see <xref href="Subpart_25.7.dita#FAR_Subpart_25_7"
                              base="i1091171"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart">subpart  25.7</xref>);
                        or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e24">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                If the acquisition is covered by the WTO GPA and any part of the offer consists of items restricted in accordance with <xref href="25.403.dita#FAR_25_403"
                              base="i1097710"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.403</xref>(c).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            If an offer restricts award to a group of line items or to all line items contained in the offer, determine for each line item whether to apply an evaluation factor (see <xref href="25.504-4.dita#FAR_25_504_4"
                        base="i1091812"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.504-4</xref>, Example 1).</p>
               <ol id="d1633e62">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e41">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                First, evaluate offers that do not specify an award restriction on a line item basis in accordance with <xref href="25.502.dita#FAR_25_502"
                              base="i1091565"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.502</xref>, determining a tentative award pattern by selecting for each line item the offer with the lowest evaluated price.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e49">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Evaluate an offer that specifies an award restriction against the offered prices of the tentative award pattern, applying the appropriate evaluation factor on a line item basis.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e54">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
								                Compute the total evaluated price for the tentative award pattern and the offer that specified an award restriction.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e59">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
								                Unless the total evaluated price of the offer that specified an award restriction is less than the total evaluated price of the tentative award pattern, award based on the tentative award pattern.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e64">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            If the solicitation specifies that award will be made only on a group of line items or all line items contained in the solicitation, determine the category of end products on the basis of each line item, but determine whether to apply an evaluation factor on the basis of the group of items (see <xref href="25.504-4.dita#FAR_25_504_4"
                        base="i1091812"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.504-4</xref>, Example 2).</p>
               <ol id="d1633e116">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e73">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                If the proposed price of domestic end products exceeds 50 percent of the total proposed price of the group, evaluate the entire group as a domestic offer. Evaluate all other groups as foreign offers.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e78">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                For foreign offers, if the proposed price of domestic end products and eligible products exceeds 50 percent of the total proposed price of the group, evaluate the entire group as an eligible offer.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1655e83">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
								                Apply the evaluation factor to the entire group in accordance with <xref href="25.502.dita#FAR_25_502"
                              base="i1091565"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.502</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1656e96">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  If no trade agreement applies to a
                     solicitation and the solicitation specifies that award will be made only on a
                     group of line items or all line items contained in the solicitation, determine
                     the category of end products ( <i>i.e.,</i> domestic or foreign) on the basis
                     of each line item, but determine whether to apply an evaluation factor on the
                     basis of the group of items ( <i>see</i>
                  <xref href="25.504-4.dita#FAR_25_504_4" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.504-4</xref>(c), Example
                     3).
               </p>
               <ol id="ol_nxj_tch_1vb">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1656e113">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        If the proposed price of domestic end
                           products exceeds 50 percent of the total proposed price of the group,
                           evaluate the entire group as a domestic offer. Evaluate all other groups
                           as foreign offers.
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1656e119">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        Apply the evaluation factor to the
                           entire group in accordance with <xref href="25.502.dita#FAR_25_502" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.502</xref>, except where <xref href="25.502.dita#FAR_25_502" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.502</xref>(c)(4) applies and the evaluated price of the low offer
                           remains less than the lowest domestic offer. Where the evaluated price of
                           the low offer remains less than the lowest domestic offer, treat as a
                           domestic offer any group where the proposed price of end products with a
                           domestic content of at least 55 percent exceeds 50 percent of the total
                           proposed price of the group.
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1656e131">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        Apply the evaluation factor to the
                           entire group in accordance with <xref href="25.502.dita#FAR_25_502" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">25.502</xref>(c)(4).
                     </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
