<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_26_101" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">26.101</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart-</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_26.101"
               xtrc="d1707e18"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Indian</i> means any person who is a member of any Indian tribe, band, group, pueblo, or community that is recognized by the Federal Government as eligible for services from the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) in accordance with <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title25-section1452(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                  scope="external"
                  format="html">25 U.S.C. 1452(c)</xref> and any "Native" as defined in the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title43-section1601&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                  scope="external"
                  format="html">43 U.S.C. 1601</xref>).</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_26.101"
               xtrc="d1707e30"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Indian organization</i> means the governing body of any Indian tribe or entity established or recognized by the governing body of an Indian tribe for the purposes of 25 U.S.C., Chapter 17.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_26.101"
               xtrc="d1707e39"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Indian-owned economic enterprise</i> means any Indian-owned (as determined by the Secretary of the Interior) commercial, industrial, or business activity established or organized for the purpose of profit, provided that Indian ownership constitutes not less than 51 percent of the enterprise.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_26.101"
               xtrc="d1707e45"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Indian tribe</i> means any Indian tribe, band, pueblo, or community, including native villages and native groups (including corporations organized by Kenai, Juneau, Sitka, and Kodiak) as defined in the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, that is recognized by the Federal Government as eligible for services from BIA in accordance with <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title25-section1452(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                  scope="external"
                  format="html">25 U.S.C. 1452(c)</xref>.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_26.101"
               xtrc="d1707e55"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Interested party</i> means a prime contractor or an actual or prospective offeror whose direct economic interest would be affected by the award of a subcontract or by the failure to award a subcontract.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
