<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"><concept id="FAR_26_603" class="- topic/topic concept/concept "><title class="- topic/title " rev="FAC 2024-05 May 22, 2024"> <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">26.603</ph> Definitions.</title><conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody "><p class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart-</p><p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term" xtrf="_26.603" xtrc="d1596e18" class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Driving</i>- <ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li ">
                  <ul class="- topic/ul "><li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2" id="d1592e18">1. Means operating a motor vehicle on an active roadway with the motor running, including while temporarily stationary because of traffic, a traffic light, stop sign, or otherwise.</p>
                     </li><li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2" id="d1592e21">2. Does not include operating a motor vehicle with or without the motor running when one has pulled over to the side of, or off, an active roadway and has halted in a location where one can safely remain stationary.</p>
                     </li></ul>
               </li></ul>
         </p><p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term" xtrf="_26.603" xtrc="d1596e30" class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Text messaging</i> means reading from or entering data into any handheld or other electronic device, including for the purpose of short message service texting, e-mailing, instant messaging, obtaining navigational information, or engaging in any other form of electronic data retrieval or electronic data communication. The term does not include glancing at or listening to a navigational device that is secured in a commercially designed holder affixed to the vehicle, provided that the destination and route are programmed into the device either before driving or while stopped in a location off the roadway where it is safe and legal to park.</p></conbody></concept></dita>