<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_28_101_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">28.101-1</ph> Policy on use.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1780e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1803e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            A contracting officer shall not require a bid guarantee unless a performance bond or a performance and payment bond is also required (see <xref href="28.102.dita#FAR_28_102"
                        base="i1088557"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">28.102</xref> and <xref href="28.103.dita#FAR_28_103"
                        base="i1088629"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">28.103</xref>). Except as provided in paragraph (c) of this subsection, bid guarantees shall be required whenever a performance bond or a performance and payment bond is required.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1803e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            All types of bid guarantees are acceptable for supply or service contracts (see annual bid bonds and annual performance bonds coverage in <xref href="28.001.dita#FAR_28_001"
                        base="i1088451"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">28.001</xref>). Only separate bid guarantees are acceptable in connection with construction contracts. Agencies may specify that only separate bid bonds are acceptable in connection with construction contracts.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1803e29">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The chief of the contracting office may waive the requirement to obtain a bid guarantee when a performance bond or a performance and payment bond is required if it is determined that a bid guarantee is not in the best interest of the Government for a specific acquisition (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> overseas construction, emergency acquisitions, sole-source contracts). Class waivers may be authorized by the agency head or designee.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
