<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_32_304_8" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">32.304-8</ph> Other borrowing.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2059e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2084e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Because of the limitations under guaranteed loans, some contractors seek to supplement the loan by other borrowing (outside the guarantee) from the financing institution or other sources. It has been recognized in practice that, while prohibition of borrowings outside the guaranteed loan is preferable when practicable in a given V-loan case, such other borrowings should be permitted when necessary.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2084e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            If the agency consents to the contractor obtaining other borrowing during the guaranteed loan period, the agency shall apply the following restrictions:</p>
               <ol id="d2059e32" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2084e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                A reasonable limit on the amount of other borrowing.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2084e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                If guaranteed and unguaranteed loans are made by the same financing institution, a requirement that any collateral security requested by the institution under the unguaranteed loan is also to be secondary collateral for the guaranteed loan.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2084e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                A requirement that the contractor provide appropriate documentation to the guaranteeing agency, at intervals not longer than 30 days, to disclose outstanding unguaranteed borrowings.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
