<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_33_213" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">33.213</ph> Obligation to continue performance.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2207e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2232e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            In general, before passage of the Disputes statute, the obligation to continue performance applied only to claims arising under a contract. However, the Disputes statute, at <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section7103(g)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">41 U.S.C. 7103(g)</xref>, authorizes agencies to require a contractor to continue contract performance in accordance with the contracting officer’s decision pending a final resolution of any claim arising under, or relating to, the contract. (A claim arising under a contract is a claim that can be resolved under a contract clause, other than the clause at <xref href="52.233-1.dita#FAR_52_233_1"
                        base="i1048610"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.233-1</xref>, Disputes, that provides for the relief sought by the claimant; however, relief for such claim can also be sought under the clause at <xref href="52.233-1.dita#FAR_52_233_1"
                        base="i1048610"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.233-1</xref>. A claim relating to a contract is a claim that cannot be resolved under a contract clause other than the clause at <xref href="52.233-1.dita#FAR_52_233_1"
                        base="i1048610"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.233-1</xref>.) This distinction is recognized by the clause with its AlternateI (see <xref href="33.215.dita#FAR_33_215"
                        base="i1080342"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">33.215</xref>).</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2232e30">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            In all contracts that include the clause at <xref href="52.233-1.dita#FAR_52_233_1"
                        base="i1048610"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.233-1</xref>, Disputes, with its AlternateI, in the event of a dispute not arising under, but relating to, the contract, the contracting officer shall consider providing, through appropriate agency procedures, financing of the continued performance; provided, that the Government’s interest is properly secured.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
