<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_37_114" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">37.114</ph> Special acquisition requirements.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">Contracts for services which require the contractor to provide advice, opinions, recommendations, ideas, reports, analyses, or other work products have the potential for influencing the authority, accountability, and responsibilities of Government officials. These contracts require special management attention to ensure that they do not result in performance of inherently governmental functions by the contractor and that Government officials properly exercise their authority. Agencies must ensure that-</p>
         <ol id="d2368e16" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2393e12">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            A sufficient number of qualified Government employees are assigned to oversee contractor activities, especially those that involve support of Government policy or decision making. During performance of service contracts, the functions being performed shall not be changed or expanded to become inherently governmental.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2393e17">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            A greater scrutiny and an appropriate enhanced degree of management oversight is exercised when contracting for functions that are not inherently governmental but closely support the performance of inherently governmental functions (see <xref href="7.503.dita#FAR_7_503"
                        base="i1118498"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">7.503</xref>(c)).</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2393e25">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            All contractor personnel attending meetings, answering Government telephones, and working in other situations where their contractor status is not obvious to third parties are required to identify themselves as such to avoid creating an impression in the minds of members of the public or Congress that they are Government officials, unless, in the judgment of the agency, no harm can come from failing to identify themselves. They must also ensure that all documents or reports produced by contractors are suitably marked as contractor products or that contractor participation is appropriately disclosed.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
