<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_4_2201" xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">4.2201</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody>
         <p>As used in this subpart—</p>
         <p>
            <i outputclass="Term" xtrf="_4.2201" xtrc="d1e18">Covered application</i> means the social networking service TikTok or any successor application or service developed or provided by ByteDance Limited or an entity owned by ByteDance Limited.</p>
         <p>
            <i outputclass="Term" xtrf="_4.2201" xtrc="d1e23">Information technology</i>, as defined in <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title40-section11101(6)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                  scope="external"
                  format="html">40 U.S.C. 11101(6)</xref>—<ol>
               <li class="- topic/li ">
                  <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d328e22">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>Means any equipment or interconnected system or subsystem of equipment, used in the automatic acquisition, storage, analysis, evaluation, manipulation, management, movement, control, display, switching, interchange, transmission, or reception of data or information by the executive agency, if the equipment is used by the executive agency directly or is used by a contractor under a contract with the executive agency that requires the use—</p>
                        <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d328e26">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>Of that equipment; or</p>
                           </li>
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d328e29">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>Of that equipment to a significant extent in the performance of a service or the furnishing of a product;</p>
                           </li>
                        </ol>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d328e32">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>Includes computers, ancillary equipment (including imaging peripherals, input, output, and storage devices necessary for security and surveillance), peripheral equipment designed to be controlled by the central processing unit of a computer, software, firmware and similar procedures, services (including support services), and related resources; but</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d328e35">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>Does not include any equipment acquired by a Federal contractor incidental to a Federal contract.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
