<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_42_1106" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">42.1106</ph> Reporting requirements.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2529e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2555e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            When information on contract performance status is needed, contracting officers may require contractors to submit production progress reports (see <xref href="42.1107.dita#FAR_42_1107"
                        base="i1074889"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">42.1107</xref>(a)). Reporting requirements shall be limited to that information essential to Government needs and shall take maximum advantage of data output generated by contractor management systems.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2555e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Contract administration offices shall review and verify the accuracy of contractor reports and advise the contracting officer of any required action. The accuracy of contractor-prepared reports shall be verified either by a program of continuous surveillance of the contractor’s report-preparation system or by individual review of each report.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2555e23">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The contract administration office may at any time initiate a report to advise the contracting officer (and the inventory manager, if one is designated in the contract) of any potential or actual delay in performance. This advice shall-</p>
               <ol id="d2529e44" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2555e29">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Be in writing;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2555e34">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Be provided in sufficient time for the contracting officer to take necessary action; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2555e39">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                Provide a definite recommendation, if action is appropriate.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
