<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_42_1303" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">42.1303</ph> Stop-work orders.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2541e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Stop-work orders may be used, when appropriate, in any negotiated fixed-price or cost-reimbursement supply, research and development, or service contract if work stoppage may be required for reasons such as advancement in the state-of-the-art, production or engineering breakthroughs, or realignment of programs.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Generally, a stop-work order will be issued only if it is advisable to suspend work pending a decision by the Government and a supplemental agreement providing for the suspension is not feasible. Issuance of a stop-work order shall be approved at a level higher than the contracting officer. Stop-work orders shall not be used in place of a termination notice after a decision to terminate has been made.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            Stop-work orders should include-</p>
               <ol id="d2541e41" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                A description of the work to be suspended;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Instructions concerning the contractor’s issuance of further orders for materials or services;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                Guidance to the contractor on action to be taken on any subcontracts; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e41">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
								                Other suggestions to the contractor for minimizing costs.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e46">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            Promptly after issuing the stop-work order, the contracting officer should discuss the stop-work order with the contractor and modify the order, if necessary, in light of the discussion.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e51">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
						            As soon as feasible after a stop-work order is issued, but before its expiration, the contracting officer shall take appropriate action to-</p>
               <ol id="d2541e98" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e57">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Terminate the contract;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e62">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Cancel the stop-work order (any cancellation of a stop-work order shall be subject to the same approvals as were required for its issuance); or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2567e67">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                Extend the period of the stop-work order if it is necessary and if the contractor agrees (any extension of the stop-work order shall be by a supplemental agreement).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
