<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_42_705_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">42.705-1</ph> Contracting officer determination procedure.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2499e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Applicability and responsibility.</i> Contracting officer determination shall be used for the following, with the indicated cognizant contracting officer (or cognizant Federal agency official) responsible for establishing the final indirect cost rates:</p>
               <ol id="d2499e26" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e18">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Business units of a multidivisional corporation under the cognizance of a corporate administrative contracting officer (see <xref href="Subpart_42.6.dita#FAR_Subpart_42_6"
                              base="i1075511"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  42.6</xref>), with that officer responsible for the determination, assisted, as required, by the administrative contracting officers, assigned to the individual business units. Negotiations may be conducted on a coordinated or centralized basis, depending upon the degree of centralization within the contractor’s organization.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Business units not under the cognizance of a corporate administrative contracting officer, but having a resident administrative contracting officer (see <xref href="42.602.dita#FAR_42_602"
                              base="i1075515"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">42.602</xref>), with that officer responsible for the determination. For this purpose, a nonresident administrative contracting officer is considered as resident if at least 75 percent of the administrative contracting officer’s time is devoted to a single contractor.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e34">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                For business units not included in paragraph (a)(1) or (a)(2) of this subsection, the contracting officer (or cognizant Federal agency official) will determine whether the rates will be contracting officer or auditor determined.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e39">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
								                Educational institutions (see <xref href="42.705-3.dita#FAR_42_705_3"
                              base="i1075270"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">42.705-3</xref>).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
								                State and local governments (see <xref href="42.705-4.dita#FAR_42_705_4"
                              base="i1075312"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">42.705-4</xref>).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e55">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
								                Nonprofit organizations other than educational and state and local governments (see <xref href="42.705-5.dita#FAR_42_705_5"
                              base="i1075318"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">42.705-5</xref>).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e63">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Procedures.</p>
               <ol id="d2499e108" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e69">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                In accordance with the Allowable Cost and Payment clause at <xref href="52.216-7.dita#FAR_52_216_7"
                              base="i1058307"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.216-7</xref>, the contractor is required to submit an adequate final indirect cost rate proposal to the contracting officer (or cognizant Federal agency official) and to the cognizant auditor.</p>
                     <ol id="d2499e121" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e78">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
										                    The required content of the proposal and supporting data will vary depending on such factors as business type, size, and accounting system capabilities. The contractor, contracting officer, and auditor must work together to make the proposal, audit, and negotiation process as efficient as possible.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e83">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
										                    Each contractor is required to submit the final indirect cost rate proposal within the six-month period following the expiration of each of its fiscal years. The contracting officer may grant, in writing, reasonable extensions, for exceptional circumstances only, when requested in writing by the contractor.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e88">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
										                    Upon receipt of the proposal-</p>
                           <ol id="d2499e149" class="- topic/ol ">
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e94">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph>
												                        The cognizant auditor will review the adequacy of the contractor’s proposal for audit in support of negotiating final indirect cost rates and will provide a written description of any inadequacies to the contractor and contracting officer.</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e99">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph>
												                        If the auditor and contractor are unable to resolve the proposal’s inadequacies identified by the auditor, the auditor will elevate the issue to the contracting office to resolve the inadequacies.</p>
                              </li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e104">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
										                    The proposal must be supported with adequate supporting data, some of which may be required subsequent to finding that the proposal is adequate for audit in support of negotiating final indirect cost rates (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, during the course of the performance of the advisory audit). See the clause at <xref href="52.216-7.dita#FAR_52_216_7"
                                    base="i1058307"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">52.216-7</xref>(d)(2) for the description of an adequate final indirect cost rate proposal and supporting data.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e115">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Once a proposal has been determined to be adequate for audit in support of negotiating final indirect cost rates, the auditor will audit the proposal and prepare an advisory audit report to the contracting officer (or cognizant Federal agency official), including a listing of any relevant advance agreements or restrictive terms of specific contracts.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e120">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                The contracting officer (or cognizant Federal agency official) shall head the Government negotiating team, which includes the cognizant auditor and technical or functional personnel as required. Contracting offices having significant dollar interest shall be invited to participate in the negotiation and in the preliminary discussion of critical issues. Individuals or offices that have provided a significant input to the Government position should be invited to attend.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e125">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> The Government negotiating team shall develop a negotiation position. Pursuant to 
                           <xref href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title10-section3745&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external">10 U.S.C. 3745</xref>
                           
                         and <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section4305&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              scope="external"
                              format="html">41 U.S.C.4305</xref>, the contracting officer shall-</p>
                     <ol id="d2499e220" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e137">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
										                    Not resolve any questioned costs until obtaining-</p>
                           <ol id="d2499e230" class="- topic/ol ">
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e143">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph>
												                        Adequate documentation on the costs; and</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e148">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph>
												                        The contract auditor’s opinion on the allowability of the costs.</p>
                              </li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e153">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
										                    Whenever possible, invite the contract auditor to serve as an advisor at any negotiation or meeting with the contractor on the determination of the contractor’s final indirect cost rates.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e158">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
								                The cognizant contracting officer shall-</p>
                     <ol id="d2499e271" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e164">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
										                    Conduct negotiations;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e169">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
										                    Prepare a written indirect cost rate agreement conforming to the requirements of the contracts;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e174">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
										                    Prepare, sign, and place in the contractor general file (see <xref href="4.801.dita#FAR_4_801"
                                    base="i1122317"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">4.801</xref>(c)(3)) a negotiation memorandum covering-</p>
                           <ol id="d2499e302" class="- topic/ol ">
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e183">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph>
												                        The disposition of significant matters in the advisory audit report;</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e188">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph>
												                        Reconciliation of all costs questioned, with identification of items and amounts allowed or disallowed in the final settlement as well as the disposition of period costing or allocability issues;</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e193">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(C)</ph>
												                        Reasons why any recommendations of the auditor or other Government advisors were not followed; and</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e198">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(D)</ph>
												                        Identification of certified cost or pricing data submitted during the negotiations and relied upon in reaching a settlement; and</p>
                              </li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e203">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
										                    Distribute resulting documents in accordance with <xref href="42.706.dita#FAR_42_706"
                                    base="i1075321"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">42.706</xref>.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2522e211">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
										                    Notify the contractor of the individual costs which were considered unallowable and the respective amounts of the disallowance.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
