<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_49_502" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">49.502</ph> Termination for convenience of the Government.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2924e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Fixed-price contracts that do not exceed the simplified acquisition threshold (short form)-</p>
               <ol id="d2924e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General use</i>. The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="52.249-1.dita#FAR_52_249_1"
                              base="i1044605"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.249-1</xref>, Termination for Convenience of the Government (Fixed-Price) (Short Form), in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price contract is contemplated and the contract amount is not expected to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold, except-</p>
                     <ol id="d2924e39" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e27">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
										                    If use of the clause at <xref href="52.249-4.dita#FAR_52_249_4"
                                    base="i1044787"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">52.249-4</xref>, Termination for Convenience of the Government (Services) (Short Form) is appropriate,</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e35">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
										                    In contracts for research and development work with an educational or nonprofit institution on a no-profit basis,</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e40">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
										                    In contracts for architect-engineer services, or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e45">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
										                    If one of the clauses prescribed or cited at <xref href="49.505.dita#FAR_49_505"
                                    base="i1067927"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">49.505</xref>(a) or (c), is appropriate.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e53">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Dismantling and demolition.</i> If the contract is for dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements, the contracting officer shall use the clause with its AlternateI.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e60">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Fixed-price contracts that exceed the simplified acquisition threshold-</p>
               <ol id="d2924e107" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e66">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                     </p>
                     <ol id="d2924e117" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e71">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General use.</i> The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="52.249-2.dita#FAR_52_249_2"
                                    base="i1044622"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">52.249-2</xref>, Termination for Convenience of the Government (Fixed-Price), in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price contract is contemplated and the contract amount is expected to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold except in contracts for -</p>
                           <ol id="d2924e133" class="- topic/ol ">
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e82">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph>
												                        Dismantling and demolition,</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e87">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph>
												                        Research and development work with an educational or nonprofit institution on a no-profit basis, or</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e92">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(C)</ph>
												                        Architect-engineer services; it shall not be used if	the clause at <xref href="52.249-4.dita#FAR_52_249_4"
                                          base="i1044787"
                                          outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">52.249-4</xref>, Termination for Convenience of	the Government (Services) (Short Form), is	appropriate (see <xref href="#FAR_49_502"
                                          base="i1067820"
                                          outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">49.502</xref>(c)), or one of	the clauses prescribed or cited at <xref href="49.505.dita#FAR_49_505"
                                          base="i1067927"
                                          outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">49.505</xref>(a) or (c), is appropriate.</p>
                              </li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e106">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Construction.</i> If the contract is for construction, the contracting officer shall use the clause with its AlternateI.</p>
                     <ol id="d2924e195" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e114">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Partial payments.</i> If the contract is with an agency of the U.S. Government or with State, local, or foreign governments or their agencies, and if the contracting officer determines that the requirement to pay interest on excess partial payments is inappropriate, the contracting officer shall use the clause with its AlternateII. In such contracts for construction, the contracting officer shall use the clause with its AlternateIII.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e121">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Dismantling and demolition.</i> The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="52.249-3.dita#FAR_52_249_3"
                                    base="i1044720"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">52.249-3</xref>, Termination for Convenience of the Government (Dismantling, Demolition, or Removal of Improvements) in solicitations and contracts for dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements, when a fixed-price contract is contemplated and the contract amount is expected to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold. If the contract is with an agency of the U.S. Government or with State, local, or foreign governments or their agencies, and if the contracting officer determines that the requirement to pay interest on excess partial payments is inappropriate, the contracting officer shall use the clause with its AlternateI.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e131">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Service contracts (short form).</i> The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="52.249-4.dita#FAR_52_249_4"
                        base="i1044787"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.249-4</xref>, Termination for Convenience of the Government (Services) (Short Form), in solicitations and contracts for services, regardless of value, when a fixed-price contract is contemplated and the contracting officer determines that because of the kind of services required, the successful offeror will not incur substantial charges in preparation for and in carrying out the contract, and would, if terminated for the convenience of the Government, limit termination settlement charges to services rendered before the date of termination. Examples of services where this clause may be appropriate are contracts for rental of unreserved parking space, laundry and dry cleaning, etc.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e141">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Research and development contracts.</i> The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="52.249-5.dita#FAR_52_249_5"
                        base="i1044796"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.249-5</xref>, Termination for the Convenience of the Government (Educational and Other Nonprofit Institutions), in solicitations and contracts when either a fixed-price or cost-reimbursement contract is contemplated for research and development work with an educational or nonprofit institution on a nonprofit or no-fee basis.</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e151">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
						            Subcontracts-</p>
               <ol id="d2924e269" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e157">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General use.</i> The prime contractor may find the clause at <xref href="52.249-1.dita#FAR_52_249_1"
                              base="i1044605"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.249-1</xref>, Termination for Convenience of the Government (Fixed-Price) (Short Form), or at <xref href="52.249-2.dita#FAR_52_249_2"
                              base="i1044622"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.249-2</xref>, Termination for Convenience of the Government (Fixed-Price), as appropriate, suitable for use in fixed-price subcontracts, except as noted in paragraph (e)(2) of this section; provided, that the relationship between the contractor and subcontractor is clearly indicated. Inapplicable conditions (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> paragraph (d)) in <xref href="52.249-2.dita#FAR_52_249_2"
                              base="i1044622"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.249-2</xref> should be deleted and the periods reduced for submitting the subcontractor’s termination settlement proposal (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>6 months), and for requesting an equitable price adjustment (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>45 days).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2951e183">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Research and development.</i> The prime contractor may find the clause at <xref href="52.249-5.dita#FAR_52_249_5"
                              base="i1044796"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.249-5</xref>, Termination for the Convenience of the Government (Educational and Other Nonprofit Institutions), suitable for use in subcontracts placed with educational or nonprofit institutions on a no-profit or no-fee basis; provided, that the relationship between the contractor and subcontractor is clearly indicated. Inapplicable conditions (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> paragraph (h)) should be deleted, the period for submitting the subcontractor’s termination settlement proposal should be reduced (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>6 months), the subcontract should be placed on a no-profit or no-fee basis, and the subcontract should incorporate or be negotiated on the basis of the cost principles in <xref href="Part_31.dita#FAR_Part_31"
                              base="i1086363"
                              outputclass="fm:Part"
                              class="- topic/xref ">part  31</xref> of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
