<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_104" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.104</ph> Procedures for modifying and completing provisions and clauses.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d3016e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3046e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The contracting officer must not modify provisions and clauses unless the FAR authorizes their modification. For example-</p>
               <ol id="d3016e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3046e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                "The contracting officer may use a period shorter than 60 days (but not less than 30 days) in paragraph (x) of the clause"; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3046e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                "The contracting officer may substitute the words ‘task order’ for the word ‘Schedule’ wherever that word appears in the clause."</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3046e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            When modifying provisions or clauses incorporated by reference, insert the changed wording directly below the title of the provision or clause identifying to the lowest level necessary (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> paragraph, sentence, word), to clearly indicate what is being modified.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3046e34">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            When modifying provisions or clauses incorporated in full text, modify the language directly by substituting the changed wording as permitted.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3046e39">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            When completing blanks in provisions or clauses incorporated by reference, insert the fill-in information directly below the title of the provision or clause identifying to the lowest level necessary to clearly indicate the blanks being filled in.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3046e44">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
						            When completing blanks in provisions or clauses incorporated in full text, insert the fill-in information in the blanks of the provision or clause.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
