<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_222_40" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.222-40</ph> Notification of Employee Rights Under the National Labor Relations Act.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="22.1605.dita#FAR_22_1605"
                     base="i1095761"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">22.1605</xref>
            </ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3348e14">Notification of Employee Rights Under the National Labor Relations Act <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Dec 2010)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3309e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            During the term of this contract, the Contractor shall post an employee notice, of such size and in such form, and containing such content as prescribed by the Secretary of Labor, in conspicuous places in and about its plants and offices where employees covered by the National Labor Relations Act engage in activities relating to the performance of the contract, including all places where notices to employees are customarily posted both physically and electronically, in the languages employees speak, in accordance with 29 CFR471.2 (d) and (f).</p>
               <ol id="d3309e35" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Physical posting of the employee notice shall be in conspicuous places in and about the Contractor’s plants and offices so that the notice is prominent and readily seen by employees who are covered by the National Labor Relations Act and engage in activities related to the performance of the contract.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                If the Contractor customarily posts notices to employees electronically, then the Contractor shall also post the required notice electronically by displaying prominently, on any website that is maintained by the Contractor and is customarily used for notices to employees about terms and conditions of employment, a link to the Department of Labor’s website that contains the full text of the poster. The link to the Department’s website, as referenced in (b)(3) of this section, must read, "Important Notice about Employee Rights to Organize and Bargain Collectively with Their Employers."</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e36">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            This required employee notice, printed by the Department of Labor, may be-</p>
               <ol id="d3309e65" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e42">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Obtained from the Division of Interpretations and Standards, Office of Labor-Management Standards, U.S. Department of Labor, 200 Constitution Avenue, NW., Room N-5609, Washington, DC 20210, (202) 693-0123, or from any field office of the Office of Labor–Management Standards or Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Provided by the Federal contracting agency if requested;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e52">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Downloaded from the Office of Labor–Management Standards Web site at <xref href="http://www.dol.gov/olms/regs/compliance/EO%2013496.htm"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref "
                              format="html">http://www.dol.gov/olms/regs/compliance/EO 13496.htm</xref>; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e60">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
								                Reproduced and used as exact duplicate copies of the Department of Labor’s official poster.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e65">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The required text of the employee notice referred to in this clause is located at Appendix A, Subpart A, <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">29 CFR Part 471</ph>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e73">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            The Contractor shall comply with all provisions of the employee notice and related rules, regulations, and orders of the Secretary of Labor.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e78">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
						            In the event that the Contractor does not comply with the requirements set forth in paragraphs (a) through (d) of this clause, this contract may be terminated or suspended in whole or in part, and the Contractor may be suspended or debarred in accordance with <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">29 CFR 471.14</ph> and subpart <xref href="Subpart_9.4.dita#FAR_Subpart_9_4"
                        base="i1115147"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">9.4</xref>. Such other sanctions or remedies may be imposed as are provided by <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">29 CFR part 471</ph>, which implements Executive Order 13496 or as otherwise provided by law.</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e92">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
						            Subcontracts. </p>
               <ol id="d3309e147" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e98">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                The Contractor shall include the substance of this clause, including this paragraph (f), in every subcontract that exceeds $10,000 and will be performed wholly or partially in the United States, unless exempted by the rules, regulations, or orders of the Secretary of Labor issued pursuant to section 3 of Executive Order 13496 of January 30, 2009, so that such provisions will be binding upon each subcontractor.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e103">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                The Contractor shall not procure supplies or services in a way designed to avoid the applicability of Executive Order 13496 or this clause.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e108">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                The Contractor shall take such action with respect to any such subcontract as may be directed by the Secretary of Labor as a means of enforcing such provisions, including the imposition of sanctions for noncompliance.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3348e113">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
								                However, if the Contractor becomes involved in litigation with a subcontractor, or is threatened with such involvement, as a result of such direction, the Contractor may request the United States, through the Secretary of Labor, to enter into such litigation to protect the interests of the United States.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
