<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_232_9"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            xtrc=" Editable">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.232-9</ph> Limitation on Withholding of Payments.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3507e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="32.111.dita#FAR_32_111"
                     base="i1083775"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">32.111</xref>(b)(2)</ph>, insert a clause substantially as follows, appropriately modified with respect to payment due dates in accordance with agency regulations, in solicitations and contracts when a supply contract, service contract, time-and-materials contract, labor-hour contract, or research and development contract is contemplated that includes two or more terms authorizing the temporary withholding of amounts otherwise payable to the contractor for supplies delivered or services performed:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3507e15">Limitation on Withholding of Payments <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">If more than one clause or Schedule term of this contract authorizes the temporary withholding of amounts otherwise payable to the Contractor for supplies delivered or services performed, the total of the amounts withheld at any one time shall not exceed the greatest amount that may be withheld under any one clause or Schedule term at that time; <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">provided</i>, that this limitation shall not apply to-</p>
         <ol id="d3463e31" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3507e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Withholdings pursuant to any clause relating to wages or hours of employees;</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3507e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Withholdings not specifically provided for by this contract;</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3507e36">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The recovery of overpayments; and</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3507e41">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            Any other withholding for which the Contracting Officer determines that this limitation is inappropriate.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
