<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_208_5" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.208-5</ph> Condition of Leased Vehicles.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3116e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="8.1104.dita#FAR_8_1104"
                     base="i1116763"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">8.1104</xref>(b)</ph>, insert the following clause in solicitations and contracts for leasing motor vehicles, unless the motor vehicles are leased in foreign countries:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3116e15">Condition of Leased Vehicles <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">Each vehicle furnished under this contract shall be of good quality and in safe operating condition, and shall comply with the Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards (49 CFR571) and State safety regulations applicable to the vehicle. The Government shall accept or reject the vehicles promptly after receipt. If the Contracting Officer determines that any vehicle furnished is not in compliance with this contract, the Contracting Officer shall promptly inform the Contractor in writing. If the Contractor fails to replace the vehicle or correct the defects as required by the Contracting Officer, the Government may-</p>
         <ol id="d3082e28" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3116e23">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            By contract or otherwise, correct the defect or arrange for the lease of a similar vehicle and shall charge or set off against the Contractor any excess costs occasioned thereby; or</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3116e28">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Terminate the contract under the Default clause of this contract.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
