<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_204_25" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.204-25</ph> Prohibition on Contracting
for Certain Telecommunications and Video Surveillance Services or Equipment.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e8">As prescribed
in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="4.2105.dita#FAR_4_2105"
                     base="FAR_4_2105"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">4.2105</xref>(b)</ph>, insert
the following clause:</p>
         <p id="d3100e15" outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Prohibition on Contracting for Certain
Telecommunications and Video Surveillance Services or Equipment (Nov
2021)</p>
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e19">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions.</i> As
used in this clause—</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e25">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d21e32"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Backhaul</i> means intermediate
links between the core network, or backbone network, and the small
subnetworks at the edge of the network (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, connecting
cell phones/towers to the core telephone network). Backhaul can
be wireless (e.g., microwave) or wired (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, fiber optic,
coaxial cable, Ethernet).</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e35">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d3097e37"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Covered foreign country</i> means
The People’s Republic of China.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e39">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d3097e43"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Covered
telecommunications equipment or services</i> means–<ol class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e45">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Telecommunications
equipment produced by Huawei Technologies Company or ZTE Corporation
(or any subsidiary or affiliate of such entities);</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e50">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> For the
purpose of public safety, security of Government facilities, physical
security surveillance of critical infrastructure, and other national
security purposes, video surveillance and telecommunications equipment
produced by Hytera Communications Corporation, Hangzhou Hikvision
Digital Technology Company, or Dahua Technology Company (or any
subsidiary or affiliate of such entities);</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e55">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Telecommunications
or video surveillance services provided by such entities or using
such equipment; or</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e60">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> Telecommunications
or video surveillance equipment or services produced or provided
by an entity that the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with
the Director of National Intelligence or the Director of the Federal
Bureau of Investigation, reasonably believes to be an entity owned
or controlled by, or otherwise connected to, the government of a
covered foreign country.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e64">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d3097e88"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Critical
technology</i> means–<ol class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e70">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Defense
articles or defense services included on the United States Munitions
List set forth in the International Traffic in Arms Regulations
under subchapter M of chapter I of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations;</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e75">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Items included
on the Commerce Control List set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part
774 of the Export Administration Regulations under subchapter C
of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, and controlled-</p>
                        <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e81">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Pursuant
to multilateral regimes, including for reasons relating to national
security, chemical and biological weapons proliferation, nuclear
nonproliferation, or missile technology; or</p>
                           </li>
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e86">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> For reasons
relating to regional stability or surreptitious listening;</p>
                           </li>
                        </ol>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e91">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Specially
designed and prepared nuclear equipment, parts and components, materials,
software, and technology covered by part 810 of title 10, Code of
Federal Regulations (relating to assistance to foreign atomic energy
activities);</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e96">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> Nuclear
facilities, equipment, and material covered by part 110 of title
10, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to export and import of
nuclear equipment and material);</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e101">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph> Select
agents and toxins covered by part 331 of title 7, Code of Federal
Regulations, part 121 of title 9 of such Code, or part 73 of title
42 of such Code; or</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e106">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph> Emerging
and foundational technologies controlled pursuant to section 1758
of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title50-section4817&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                                 scope="external"
                                 format="html">50 U.S.C. 4817</xref>).</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e110">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d21e119"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Interconnection arrangements</i> means arrangements
governing the physical connection of two or more networks to allow the
use of another's network to hand off traffic where it is ultimately
delivered (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, connection of a customer of telephone provider
A to a customer of telephone company B) or sharing data and other
information resources.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e117">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d21e127"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Reasonable inquiry</i> means
an inquiry designed to uncover any information in the entity's possession
about the identity of the producer or provider of covered telecommunications
equipment or services used by the entity that excludes the need to
include an internal or third-party audit.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e121">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d21e132"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Roaming</i> means
cellular communications services (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, voice, video, data)
received from a visited network when unable to connect to the facilities
of the home network either because signal coverage is too weak or
because traffic is too high.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e128">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.204-25"
                     xtrc="d3097e174"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Substantial
or essential component</i> means any component necessary for the
proper function or performance of a piece of equipment, system,
or service.</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e133">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Prohibition</i>.  </p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e141">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Section
889(a)(1)(A) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization
Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (Pub. L. 115-232) prohibits the head of
an executive agency on or after August 13, 2019, from procuring
or obtaining, or extending or renewing a contract to procure or
obtain, any equipment, system, or service that uses covered telecommunications
equipment or services as a substantial or essential component of
any system, or as critical technology as part of any system. The
Contractor is prohibited from providing to the Government any equipment,
system, or service that uses covered telecommunications equipment
or services as a substantial or essential component of any system,
or as critical technology as part of any system, unless an exception
at paragraph (c) of this clause applies or the covered telecommunication
equipment or services are covered by a waiver described in FAR <xref href="4.2104.dita#FAR_4_2104"
                              base="FAR_4_2104"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">4.2104</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e149">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Section
889(a)(1)(B) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization
Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (Pub. L. 115-232) prohibits the head of
an executive agency on or after August 13, 2020, from entering into
a contract, or extending or renewing a contract, with an entity
that uses any equipment, system, or service that uses covered telecommunications
equipment or services as a substantial or essential component of
any system, or as critical technology as part of any system, unless
an exception at paragraph (c) of this clause applies or the covered
telecommunication equipment or services are covered by a waiver
described in FAR <xref href="4.2104.dita#FAR_4_2104"
                              base="FAR_4_2104"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">4.2104</xref>.
This prohibition applies to the use of covered telecommunications
equipment or services, regardless of whether that use is in performance
of work under a Federal contract.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e157">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Exceptions.</i> This
clause does not prohibit contractors from providing—</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e165">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> A service
that connects to the facilities of a third-party, such as backhaul,
roaming, or interconnection arrangements; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e170">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Telecommunications
equipment that cannot route or redirect user data traffic or permit
visibility into any user data or packets that such equipment transmits
or otherwise handles.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e175">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> Reporting
requirement.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e181">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> In
the event the Contractor identifies covered telecommunications equipment
or services used as a substantial or essential component of any
system, or as critical technology as part of any system, during contract
performance, or the Contractor is notified of such by a subcontractor
at any tier or by any other source, the Contractor shall report
the information in paragraph (d)(2) of this clause to the Contracting
Officer, unless elsewhere in this contract are established procedures
for reporting the information; in the case of the Department of
Defense, the Contractor shall report to the website at <xref href="https://dibnet.dod.mil"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">https://dibnet.dod.mil</xref>.
For indefinite delivery contracts, the Contractor shall report to
the Contracting Officer for the indefinite delivery contract and
the Contracting Officer(s) for any affected order or, in the case
of the Department of Defense, identify both the indefinite delivery
contract and any affected orders in the report provided at <xref href="https://dibnet.dod.mil"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">https://dibnet.dod.mil</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e192">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The Contractor
shall report the following information pursuant to paragraph (d)(1)
of this clause</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e198">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Within
one business day from the date of such identification or notification:
the contract number; the order number(s), if applicable; supplier
name; supplier unique entity identifier (if known); supplier Commercial
and Government Entity (CAGE) code (if known); brand; model number
(original equipment manufacturer number, manufacturer part number,
or wholesaler number); item description; and any readily available
information about mitigation actions undertaken or recommended.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e203">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Within
10 business days of submitting the information in paragraph (d)(2)(i)
of this clause: any further available information about mitigation
actions undertaken or recommended. In addition, the Contractor shall
describe the efforts it undertook to prevent use or submission of
covered telecommunications equipment or services, and any additional
efforts that will be incorporated to prevent future use or submission
of covered telecommunications equipment or services.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3100e208">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Subcontracts.</i> The
Contractor shall insert the substance of this clause, including
this paragraph (e) and excluding paragraph (b)(2), in all subcontracts
and other contractual instruments, including subcontracts for the
acquisition of commercial
products or commercial services.
               </p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
