<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_225_3" xtrc="GFI" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.225-3</ph> Buy American-Free Trade Agreements-Israeli Trade Act.
      </title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref base="i1090819"
                     href="25.1101.dita#FAR_25_1101"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">25.1101</xref>
            </ph>(b)(1)(i),
insert the following clause:</p>
         <p id="d3401e14" outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p "> Buy American-Free Trade Agreements-Israeli Trade Act (Nov 2023) </p>
         <ol id="d3362e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>.
As used in this clause—</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e24">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e40"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">
                     Bahraini, Moroccan, Omani, Panamanian, or Peruvian end product</i> means an article that—<ol id="d3362e47" class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e30">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Is wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of Bahrain, Morocco, Oman, Panama, or Peru; or</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e35">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> In the case of an article that consists in whole or in part of materials from another country, has been substantially transformed in Bahrain, Morocco, Oman, Panama, or Peru into a new and different article of commerce with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which it was transformed. The term refers to a product offered for purchase under a supply contract, but for purposes of calculating the value of the end product includes services (except transportation services) incidental to the article, provided that the value of those incidental services does not exceed that of the article itself.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e39">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e67"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Commercially
available off-the-shelf (COTS) item</i>—<ol class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e45">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                            Means any item of supply (including
construction material) that is-</p>
                        <ol id="d3362e84" class="- topic/ol ">
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e51">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                                  A commercial
product (as defined in paragraph (1) of the definition of “commercial
product” at Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) <xref base="i1125359"
                                       href="2.101.dita#FAR_2_101"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref>);</p>
                           </li>
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e59">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                                  Sold in
substantial quantities in the commercial marketplace; and</p>
                           </li>
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e64">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                                  Offered
to the Government, under a contract or subcontract at any tier,
without modification, in the same form in which it is sold in the
commercial marketplace; and</p>
                           </li>
                        </ol>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e69">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                            Does not
include bulk cargo, as defined in <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title46-section40102(4)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                                 scope="external"
                                 format="html"
                                 class="- topic/xref ">46 U.S.C. 40102(4)</xref>, such as agricultural
products and petroleum products.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e73">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e127"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Component</i> means
an article, material, or supply incorporated directly into an end
product.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e77">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e133"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Cost of components</i> means—<ol class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e83">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                            For components
purchased by the Contractor, the acquisition cost, including transportation
costs to the place of incorporation into the end product (whether
or not such costs are paid to a domestic firm), and any applicable
duty (whether or not a duty-free entry certificate is issued); or</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e88">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                            For components
manufactured by the Contractor, all costs associated with the manufacture
of the component, including transportation costs as described in
paragraph (1) of this definition, plus allocable overhead costs,
but excluding profit. Cost of components does not include any costs
associated with the manufacture of the end product.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3402e94">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d15e97"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Critical component</i> means a component
that is mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States and
deemed critical to the U.S. supply chain. The list of critical components
is at FAR <xref href="25.105.dita#FAR_25_105"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">25.105</xref>.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e92">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e161"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Domestic end product</i> means— <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e98">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                            For an end
product that does not consist wholly or predominantly of iron or
steel or a combination of both–</p>
                        <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e104">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                                  An unmanufactured end product
mined or produced in the United States;</p>
                           </li>
                           <li class="- topic/li ">
                              <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e109">
                                 <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                                  An end
product manufactured in the United States, if—</p>
                              <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                                 <li class="- topic/li ">
                                    <p class="- topic/p " id="d3402e127">
                                       <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph>
                                       The cost of its components
mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States exceeds 60
percent of the cost of all its components, except that the percentage
will be 65 percent for items delivered in calendar years 2024 through
2028 and 75 percent for items delivered starting in calendar year
2029. Components of foreign origin of the same class or kind
as those that the agency determines are not mined, produced, or
manufactured in sufficient and reasonably available commercial quantities
of a satisfactory quality are treated as domestic. Components of
unknown origin are treated as foreign. Scrap generated, collected,
and prepared for processing in the United States is considered domestic;
or</p>
                                 </li>
                                 <li class="- topic/li ">
                                    <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e120">
                                       <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph>
                                        The end
product is a COTS item; or</p>
                                 </li>
                              </ol>
                           </li>
                        </ol>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e125">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                            For an
end product that consists wholly or predominantly of iron or steel
or a combination of both, an end product manufactured in the United
States, if the cost of foreign iron and steel constitutes less than
5 percent of the cost of all the components used in the end product.
The cost of foreign iron and steel includes but is not limited to
the cost of foreign iron or steel mill products (such as bar, billet,
slab, wire, plate, or sheet), castings, or forgings utilized in
the manufacture of the end product and a good faith estimate of
the cost of all foreign iron or steel components excluding COTS
fasteners. Iron or steel components of unknown origin are treated
as foreign. If the end product contains multiple components, the
cost of all the materials used in such end product is calculated
in accordance with the definition of "cost of components".</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e129">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e209"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">End product</i> means those articles, materials,
and supplies to be acquired under the contract for public use.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e133">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d7e152"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Fastener</i> means a hardware device that
mechanically joins or affixes two or more objects together. Examples
of fasteners are nuts, bolts, pins, rivets, nails, clips, and screws.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e137">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e215"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Foreign end product</i> means an end product
other than a domestic end product.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e141">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d7e164"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Foreign
iron and steel</i> means iron or steel products not produced in
the United States. Produced in the United States means that all
manufacturing processes of the iron or steel must take place in
the United States, from the initial melting stage through the application
of coatings, except metallurgical processes involving refinement
of steel additives. The origin of the elements of the iron or steel
is not relevant to the determination of whether it is domestic or
foreign.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e145">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e221"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Free Trade Agreement country</i> means Australia, Bahrain, Chile, Colombia, Costa Rica, Dominican Republic, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Korea (Republic of), Mexico, Morocco, Nicaragua, Oman, Panama, Peru, or Singapore.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e150">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e227"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Free Trade Agreement country end product</i> means
an article that-<ol id="d3362e206" class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e156">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                            Is wholly the growth, product,
or manufacture of a Free Trade Agreement country; or</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e161">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                            In the
case of an article that consists in whole or in part of materials
from another country, has been substantially transformed in a Free
Trade Agreement country into a new and different article of commerce
with a name, character, or use distinct from that of the article
or articles from which it was transformed. The term refers to a
product offered for purchase under a supply contract, but for purposes
of calculating the value of the end product includes services (except transportation
services) incidental to the article, provided that the value of
those incidental services does not exceed that of the article itself.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e165">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e254"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Israeli end product</i> means an article
that—<ol id="d3362e231" class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e171">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                            Is wholly the growth, product,
or manufacture of Israel; or</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e176">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                            In the
case of an article that consists in whole or in part of materials
from another country, has been substantially transformed in Israel
into a new and different article of commerce with a name, character,
or use distinct from that of the article or articles from which
it was transformed.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e180">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d7e205"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Predominantly
of iron or steel or a combination of both</i> means that the cost
of the iron and steel content exceeds 50 percent of the total cost
of all its components. The cost of iron and steel is the cost of
the iron or steel mill products (such as bar, billet, slab, wire,
plate, or sheet), castings, or forgings utilized in the manufacture
of the product and a good faith estimate of the cost of iron or
steel components excluding COTS fasteners.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e184">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d7e211"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Steel</i> means
an alloy that includes at least 50 percent iron, between 0.02 and
2 percent carbon, and may include other elements.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e188">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.225-3"
                     xtrc="d3397e282"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">United
States</i> means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and outlying
areas.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e193">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Components
of foreign origin</i>. Offerors may obtain from the Contracting
Officer a list of foreign articles that the Contracting Officer
will treat as domestic for this contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e200">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Delivery of end products</i>. <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid%3AUSC-prelim-title41-chapter83&amp;saved=%7CZ3JhbnVsZWlkOlVTQy1wcmVsaW0tdGl0bGU0MC1jaGFwdGVyMzctZnJvbnQ%3D%7C%7C%7C0%7Cfalse%7Cprelim&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html"
                        class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 83</xref>, Buy American statute, provides a preference for domestic end products for supplies acquired for use in the United States. In accordance with <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section1907&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html"
                        class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. 1907</xref>, the domestic content test of the Buy American statute is waived for an end product that is a COTS item (see <xref base="i1112949"
                        href="12.505.dita#FAR_12_505"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">12.505</xref>(a)(1)), except that for an end product that consists wholly or predominantly of iron or steel or a combination of both, the domestic content test is applied only to the iron and steel content of the end product,
                  excluding COTS fasteners. Unless otherwise specified, these trade agreements apply to all items in the Schedule. The Contractor shall deliver under this contract only domestic end products except to the extent that, in its offer, it specified delivery of foreign end products in the provision entitled "Buy American-Free Trade Agreements-Israeli Trade Act Certificate." If the Contractor specified in its offer that the Contractor would supply a Free Trade Agreement country end product (other than a Bahraini, Moroccan, Omani, Panamanian, or Peruvian end product) or an Israeli end product, then the Contractor shall supply a Free Trade Agreement country end product (other than a Bahraini, Moroccan, Omani, Panamanian, or Peruvian end product), an Israeli end product or, at the Contractor’s option, a domestic end product.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
         <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section "><?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
            <p id="d3401e219" class="- topic/p ">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate I</i> [Reserved]</p>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
            <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e253" outputclass="List1">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate II</i> (<ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">Jan</ph> 2025). As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
                  <xref base="i1090819"
                        href="25.1101.dita#FAR_25_1101"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">25.1101</xref>
               </ph>(b)(1)(ii), substitute the following paragraph (c) for paragraph (c) of the basic clause: </p>
            <p class="- topic/p " id="d3402e317" outputclass="List1"> (c) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Delivery of end products</i>. <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid%3AUSC-prelim-title41-chapter83&amp;saved=%7CZ3JhbnVsZWlkOlVTQy1wcmVsaW0tdGl0bGU0MC1jaGFwdGVyMzctZnJvbnQ%3D%7C%7C%7C0%7Cfalse%7Cprelim&amp;edition=prelim"
                     scope="external"
                     format="html"
                     class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 83</xref> provides a preference for domestic end products for supplies acquired for use in the United States. In accordance with <xref format="html"
                     href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section1907&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                     scope="external"
                     class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. 1907</xref>, the domestic content test of the Buy American statute is waived for an end product that is a COTS item (see 12.505(a)(1)), except that for an end product that consists wholly or predominantly of iron or steel or a combination of both, the domestic content test is applied only to the iron and steel content of the end product, excluding COTS fasteners. In addition, the Contracting Officer has determined that the Israeli Trade Act applies to this acquisition. Unless otherwise specified, this trade agreement applies to all items in the Schedule. The Contractor shall deliver under this contract only domestic end products except to the extent that, in its offer, it specified delivery of foreign end products in the provision entitled “Buy American—Free Trade Agreements—Israeli Trade Act Certificate.” If the Contractor specified in its offer that the Contractor would supply an Israeli end product, then the Contractor shall supply an Israeli end product or, at the Contractor's option, a domestic end product. </p>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
            <p class="- topic/p " id="d3401e298" outputclass="List1">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate III</i>
               <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Feb
               2024)</ph>.
               As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
                  <xref base="i1090819"
                        href="25.1101.dita#FAR_25_1101"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">25.1101</xref>
               </ph>(b)(1)(iii), delete the
               definition of "Bahraini, Moroccan, Omani, Panamanian, or Peruvian
               end product" and add in its place the following definition of "Korean end product" in paragraph (a) of
               the basic clause; and substitute the following paragraph (c) for
               paragraph (c) of the basic clause:</p>
            <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1" id="d3410e273">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Korean
               end product</i> means an article
               that—
            </p>
            <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2" id="d3410e280">
               (1) Is wholly the growth,
               product, or manufacture of Korea (Republic of); or
            </p>
            <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2" id="d3410e284">
               (2) In the case of an article
               that consists in whole or in part of materials from another
               country, has been substantially transformed in Korea (Republic
               of) into a new and different article of commerce with a name,
               character, or use distinct from that of the article or articles
               from which it was transformed. The term refers to a product
               offered for purchase under a supply contract, but for purposes of
               calculating the value of the end product includes services
               (except transportation services) incidental to the article,
               provided that the value of those incidental services does not
               exceed that of the article itself.
            </p>
            <p class="- topic/p " id="d3402e360" outputclass="List1">
               (c) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Delivery of end products</i>. <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid%3AUSC-prelim-title41-chapter83&amp;saved=%7CZ3JhbnVsZWlkOlVTQy1wcmVsaW0tdGl0bGU0MC1jaGFwdGVyMzctZnJvbnQ%3D%7C%7C%7C0%7Cfalse%7Cprelim&amp;edition=prelim"
                     scope="external"
                     format="html"
                     class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 83</xref> provides a
               preference for domestic end products for supplies acquired for
               use in the United States. In accordance with <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section1907&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                     scope="external"
                     format="html"
                     class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C.1907</xref>, the domestic content
               test of the Buy American statute is waived for an end product
               that is a COTS item (see <xref base="i1112949"
                     href="12.505.dita#FAR_12_505"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">12.505</xref>(a)(1)), except that for an
               end product that consists wholly or predominantly of iron or
               steel or a combination of both, the domestic content test is
               applied only to the iron and steel content of the end product,
               excluding COTS fasteners. In addition, the Contracting Officer
               has determined that the Korea (Republic of) FTA and the Israeli
               Trade Act apply to this acquisition. Unless otherwise specified,
               these trade agreements apply to all items in the Schedule. The
               Contractor shall deliver under this contract only domestic end
               products except to the extent that, in its offer, it specified
               delivery of foreign end products in the provision entitled “Buy
               American—Free Trade Agreements—Israeli Trade Act Certificate.” If
               the Contractor specified in its offer that the Contractor would
               supply a Korean end product or an Israeli end product, then the
               Contractor shall supply a Korean end product, an Israeli end
               product, or at the Contractor’s option, a domestic end
               product.
            </p>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
            <p class="- topic/p " id="d3402e339" outputclass="List1">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate IV</i> (<ph outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">Oct</ph> 2022). As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
                  <xref href="25.1101.dita#FAR_25_1101"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">25.1101</xref>
               </ph>(b)(1)(iv)
            substitute the following sentence for the first sentence of
            paragraph (1)(ii)(A) of the definition of <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">domestic end
            product</i> in paragraph (a):</p>
            <p id="d3402e352" outputclass="List4" class="- topic/p ">(A) The cost of its components mined, produced,
            or manufactured in the United States exceeds <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                     xtrc="52.225-3_d1e478"
                     xtrf="GFI"
                     class="- topic/cite ">__</cite> percent of the cost of all its components. [
            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting officer to insert the percentage.</i> ]</p>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
         </section>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
