<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_223_7" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="GFI">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.223-7</ph> 
         Notice of Radioactive Materials.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     href="23.304.dita#FAR_23_304"
                     base="i1094507"
                     class="- topic/xref ">23.304</xref>(b)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3378e14">Notice of Radioactive Materials <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Jan 1997)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3339e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The Contractor shall notify the Contracting Officer or designee, in writing, <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                        xtrc="52.223-7_d3363e33"
                        class="- topic/cite "
                        xtrf="GFI">______________</cite>*days prior to the delivery of, or prior to completion of any servicing required by this contract of, items containing either (1) radioactive material requiring specific licensing under the regulations issued pursuant to the Atomic Energy Act of1954, as amended, as set forth in Title 10 of the <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Code of Federal Regulations</i>, in effect on the date of this contract, or (2) other radioactive material not requiring specific licensing in which the specific activity is greater than 0.002 microcuries per gram or the activity per item equals or exceeds 0.01 microcuries. Such notice shall specify the part or parts of the items which contain radioactive materials, a description of the materials, the name and activity of the isotope, the manufacturer of the materials, and any other information known to the Contractor which will put users of the items on notice as to the hazards involved (OMB No.9000-0107).</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e30">* The Contracting Officer shall insert the number of days required in advance of delivery of the item or completion of the servicing to assure that required licenses are obtained and appropriate personnel are notified to institute any necessary safety and health precautions.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e36">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            If there has been no change affecting the quantity of activity, or the characteristics and composition of the radioactive material from deliveries under this contract or prior contracts, the Contractor may request that the Contracting Officer or designee waive the notice requirement in paragraph (a) of this clause. Any such request shall-</p>
               <ol id="d3339e56" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e42">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Be submitted in writing;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                State that the quantity of activity, characteristics, and composition of the radioactive material have not changed; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e52">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                Cite the contract number on which the prior notification was submitted and the contracting office to which it was submitted.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e57">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            All items, parts, or subassemblies which contain radioactive materials in which the specific activity is greater than 0.002 microcuries per gram or activity per item equals or exceeds 0.01 microcuries, and all containers in which such items, parts or subassemblies are delivered to the Government shall be clearly marked and labeled as required by the latest revision of MIL-STD 129 in effect on the date of the contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3378e62">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            This clause, including this paragraph (d), shall be inserted in all subcontracts for radioactive materials meeting the criteria in paragraph (a) of this clause.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
