<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_215_18" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.215-18</ph> Reversion or Adjustment of Plans for Postretirement Benefits (PRB) Other Than Pensions.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3222e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="15.408.dita#FAR_15_408"
                     base="i1106593"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">15.408</xref>(j)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Reversion or Adjustment of Plans for Postretirement Benefits (PRB) Other Than Pensions (July 2005)</p>
         <ol id="d3187e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3222e19">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The Contractor shall promptly notify the Contracting Officer in writing when the Contractor determines that it will terminate or reduce the benefits of a PRB plan.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3222e24">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            If PRB fund assets revert or inure to the Contractor, or are constructively received by it under a plan termination or otherwise, the Contractor shall make a refund or give a credit to the Government for its equitable share as required by <xref href="31.205-6.dita#FAR_31_205_6"
                        base="i1084735"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">31.205-6</xref>(o)(5) of the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR). When determining or agreeing on the method for recovery of the Government’s equitable share, the contracting parties should consider the following methods: cost reduction, amortizing the credit over a number of years (with appropriate interest), cash refund, or some other agreed upon method. Should the parties be unable to agree on the method for recovery of the Government’s equitable share, through good faith negotiations, the Contracting Officer shall designate the method of recovery.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3222e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The Contractor shall insert the substance of this clause in all subcontracts that meet the applicability requirements of FAR <xref href="15.408.dita#FAR_15_408"
                        base="i1106593"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">15.408</xref>(j).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
