<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_247_16" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.247-16</ph> Contractor Responsibility for Returning Undelivered Freight.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3694e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="47.207-5.dita#FAR_47_207_5"
                     base="i1071062"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">47.207-5</xref>(f)</ph>, insert the following clause in solicitations and contracts for transportation or for transportation-related services when the contractor is responsible for returning undelivered freight:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3694e15">Contractor Responsibility for Returning Undelivered Freight <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3650e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3694e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            When, through no fault of the Contractor, a shipment cannot be delivered, the Contractor shall contact the shipper for disposition instructions. If the shipment is ordered returned to the origin point, the charges assessed for the return trip shall be the same as the charges assessed for the outbound trip. The shipper shall maintain a record of the goods that, through no fault of the Contractor, could not be delivered and are returned to the shipper. If, at a future date, the returned goods are determined to be related to a claim against the Contractor, the claim will be adjusted accordingly.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3694e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            When, through the fault of the Contractor, a shipment cannot be delivered, the Contractor shall return the shipment to the origin point at no charge to the Government. Any charges incurred for redelivery, which are in excess of the charges that would have been incurred under this contract, shall be for the Contractor’s account in accordance with the Default clause of the contract.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
