<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            id="FAR_52_216_16"
            xtrc="GFI">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.216-16</ph> Incentive Price Revision-Firm
Target.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody " outputclass="clause">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e8">As prescribed
in <ph class="- topic/ph " outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF">
               <xref base="i1104557"
                     class="- topic/xref "
                     href="16.406.dita#FAR_16_406"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">16.406</xref>(a)</ph>, insert
the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e15" outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">Incentive Price Revision-Firm Target (Jan
2022)</p>
         <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e25">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e19">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General</i>.
The supplies or services identified in the Schedule as Items <cite class="- topic/cite "
                        outputclass="MultiLine"
                        xtrc="52.216-16_d3232e36"
                        xtrf="GFI">_______
[<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer insert Schedule line item numbers</i>]</cite> are
subject to price revision in accordance with this clause; provided,
that in no event shall the total final price of these items exceed
the ceiling price of <cite class="- topic/cite "
                        outputclass="SingleLine"
                        xtrc="52.216-16_d3232e42"
                        xtrf="GFI">________</cite> dollars ($<cite class="- topic/cite "
                        outputclass="SingleLine"
                        xtrc="52.216-16_d3232e45"
                        xtrf="GFI">_____</cite>).
Any supplies or services that are to be (1) ordered separately under,
or otherwise added to, this</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e37">contract and (2)
subject to price revision in accordance with the terms of this clause
shall be identified as such in a modification to this contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e40">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definition</i>.
"Costs," as used in this clause, means allowable costs in accordance
with <xref base="i1086363"
                        class="- topic/xref "
                        href="Part_31.dita#FAR_Part_31"
                        outputclass="fm:Part">part  31</xref> of the Federal
Acquisition Regulation (FAR) in effect on the date of this contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li " props="Runin">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e50">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(c)</ph> Data
submission.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e71">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e56">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(1)</ph> Within <cite class="- topic/cite "
                              outputclass="SingleLine"
                              xtrc="52.216-16_d3232e84"
                              xtrf="GFI">__________________
[<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer insert number of days</i>]</cite> days after
the end of the month in which the Contractor has delivered the last
unit of supplies and completed the services specified by item number
in paragraph (a) of this clause, the Contractor shall submit in
the format of <xref base="i1106753"
                              class="- topic/xref "
                              href="15.408.dita#FAR_15_408/i1106753"
                              outputclass="fm:Table">Table  15-1</xref>,
FAR <xref base="i1106593"
                              class="- topic/xref "
                              href="15.408.dita#FAR_15_408"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">15.408</xref>, or in any other
form on which the parties agree-</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e90">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e74">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(i)</ph> A detailed
statement of all costs incurred up to the end of that month in performing
all work under the items;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e79">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(ii)</ph> An estimate
of costs of further performance, if any, that may be necessary to
complete performance of all work under the items;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e84">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(iii)</ph> A list
of all residual inventory and an estimate of its value; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e89">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(iv)</ph> Any other
relevant data that the Contracting Officer may reasonably require.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e94">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(2)</ph> If the
Contractor fails to submit the data required by paragraph (c)(1)
of this clause within the time specified and it is later determined
that the Government has overpaid the Contractor, the Contractor
shall repay the excess to the Government immediately. Unless repaid
within 30 days after the end of the data submittal period, the amount
of the excess shall bear interest, computed from the date the data
were due to the date of repayment, at the rate established in accordance
with the Interest clause.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e99">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(d)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Price
revision</i>. Upon the Contracting Officer’s receipt of the data
required by paragraph (c) of this clause, the Contracting Officer
and the Contractor shall promptly establish the total final price
of the items specified in (a) of this clause by applying to final
negotiated cost an adjustment for profit or loss, as follows:</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e152">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e107">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(1)</ph> On
the basis of the information required by paragraph (c) of this clause,
together with any other pertinent information, the parties shall
negotiate the total final cost incurred or to be incurred for supplies
delivered (or services performed) and accepted by the Government
and which are subject to price revision under this clause.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e112">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(2)</ph> The total
final price shall be established by applying to the total final
negotiated cost an adjustment for profit or loss, as follows:</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e171">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e118">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(i)</ph> If
the total final negotiated cost is equal to the total target cost,
the adjustment is the total target profit.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e123">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(ii)</ph> If the
total final negotiated cost is greater than the total target cost,
the adjustment is the total target profit, less <cite class="- topic/cite "
                                    outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.216-16_d3232e194"
                                    xtrf="GFI">______
[<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer insert percent</i>]</cite> percent of the
amount by which the total final negotiated cost exceeds the total
target cost.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e134">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(iii)</ph> If the
final negotiated cost is less than the total target cost, the adjustment
is the total target profit plus <cite class="- topic/cite "
                                    outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.216-16_d3232e209"
                                    xtrf="GFI">_____ [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer insert
percent</i>]</cite> percent of the amount by which the total final
negotiated cost is less than the total target cost.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e145">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(e)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contract
modification</i>. The total final price of the items specified in
paragraph (a) of this clause shall be evidenced by a modification
to this contract, signed by the Contractor and the Contracting Officer.
This price shall not be subject to revision, notwithstanding any
changes in the cost of performing the contract, except to the extent
that-</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e221">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e153">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(1)</ph> The parties may agree in writing,
before the determination of total final price, to exclude specific
elements of cost from this price and to a procedure for subsequent
disposition of those elements; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e158">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(2)</ph> Adjustments
or credits are explicitly permitted or required by this or any other
clause in this contract.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li " props="Runin">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e163">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(f)</ph> Adjusting
billing prices.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e251">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e169">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(1)</ph> Pending execution of the contract
modification (see paragraph (e) of this clause), the Contractor
shall submit invoices or vouchers in accordance with billing prices
as provided in this paragraph. The billing prices shall be the target
prices shown in this contract.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e174">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(2)</ph> If at
any time it appears from information provided by the contractor
under paragraph (g)(2) of this clause that the then-current billing
prices will be substantially greater than the estimated final prices,
the parties shall negotiate a reduction in the billing prices. Similarly,
the parties may negotiate an increase in billing prices by any or
all of the difference between the target prices and the ceiling
price, upon the Contractor’s submission of factual data showing
that final cost under this contract will be substantially greater
than the target cost.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e179">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(3)</ph> Any billing
price adjustment shall be reflected in a contract modification and
shall not affect the determination of the total final price under
paragraph (d) of this clause. After the contract modification establishing
the total final price is executed, the total amount paid or to be
paid on all invoices or vouchers shall be adjusted to reflect the
total final price, and any resulting additional payments, refunds,
or credits shall be made promptly.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e184">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(g)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Quarterly
limitation on payments statement</i>. This paragraph (g) shall apply
until final price revision under this contract has been completed.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e294">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e192">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(1)</ph> Within
45 days after the end of each quarter of the Contractor’s fiscal
year in which a delivery is first made (or services are first performed)
and accepted by the Government under this contract, and for each
quarter thereafter, the Contractor shall submit to the contract
administration office (with a copy to the contracting office and
the cognizant contract auditor) a statement, cumulative from the
beginning of the contract, showing-</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol " id="d3209e304">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e198">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(i)</ph> The total
contract price of all supplies delivered (or services performed)
and accepted by the Government and for which final prices have been
established;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e203">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(ii)</ph> The total
costs (estimated to the extent necessary) reasonably incurred for,
and properly allocable solely to, the supplies delivered (or services
performed) and accepted by the Government and for which final prices
have not been established;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e208">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(iii)</ph> The
portion of the total target profit (used in establishing the initial
contract price or agreed to for the purpose of this paragraph (g))
that is in direct proportion to the supplies delivered (or services
performed) and accepted by the Government and for which final prices
have not been established-increased or decreased in accordance with paragraph
(d)(2) of this clause, when the amount stated under subdivision
(g)(1)(ii) of this clause differs from the aggregate target costs
of the supplies or services; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e213">
                              <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(iv)</ph> The total
amount of all invoices or vouchers for supplies delivered (or services
performed) and accepted by the Government (including amounts applied
or to be applied to liquidate progress payments).</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e218">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(2)</ph> Notwithstanding
any provision of this contract authorizing greater payments, if
on any quarterly statement the amount under subdivision (g)(1)(iv)
of this clause exceeds the sum due the Contractor, as computed in
accordance with subdivisions (g)(1)(i), (ii), and (iii) of this
clause, the Contractor shall immediately refund or credit to the
Government the amount of this excess. The Contractor may, when appropriate,
reduce this refund or credit by the
amount of previous refunds or credits effected under this clause.
If any portion of the excess has been applied to the liquidation
of progress payments, then that portion may, instead of being refunded,
be added to the unliquidated progress payment account consistent
with the Progress Payments clause. The Contractor shall provide
complete details to support any claimed reductions in refunds.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e223">
                        <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(3)</ph> If the
Contractor fails to submit the quarterly statement within 45 days
after the end of each quarter and it is later determined that the
Government has overpaid the Contractor, the Contractor shall repay
the excess to the Government immediately. Unless repaid within 30
days after the end of the statement submittal period, the amount
of the excess shall bear interest, computed from the date the quarterly
statement was due to the date of repayment, at the rate established
in accordance with the Interest clause.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e228">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(h)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Subcontracts</i>.
No subcontract placed under this contract may provide for payment
on a cost-plus-a-percentage-of-cost basis.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e235">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(i)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Disagreements</i>.
If the Contractor and the Contracting Officer fail to agree upon
the total final price within 60 days (or within such other period
as the Contracting Officer may specify) after the date on which
the data required by paragraph (c) of this clause are to be submitted,
the Contracting Officer shall promptly issue a decision in accordance
with the Disputes clause.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e242">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(j)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Termination</i>.
If this contract is terminated before the total final price is established,
prices of supplies or services subject to price revision shall be
established in accordance with this clause for (1) completed supplies
and services accepted by the Government and (2) those supplies and
services not terminated under a partial termination. All other elements
of the termination shall be resolved in accordance with other applicable
clauses of this contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e249">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(k)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Equitable
adjustment under other clauses</i>. If an equitable adjustment in
the contract price is made under any other clause of this contract
before the total final price is established, the adjustment shall
be made in the total target cost and may be made in the maximum
dollar limit on the total final price, the total target profit,
or both. If the adjustment is made after the total final price is
established, only the total final price shall be adjusted.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e257">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(l)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Exclusion
from target price and total final price</i>. If any clause of this
contract provides that the contract price does not or will not include
an amount for a specific purpose, then neither any target price
nor the total final price includes or will include any amount for
that purpose.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e264">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(m)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Separate
reimbursement</i>. If any clause of this contract expressly provides
that the cost of performance of an obligation shall be at Government
expense, that expense shall not be included in any target price
or in the total final price, but shall be reimbursed separately.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3244e271">
                  <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">(n)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Taxes</i>.
As used in the Federal, State, and Local Taxes clause or in any
other clause that provides for certain taxes or duties to be included
in, or excluded from, the contract price, the term "contract price"
includes the total target price or, if it has been established,
the total final price. When any of these clauses requires that the
contract price be increased or decreased as a result of changes
in the obligation of the Contractor to pay or bear the burden of
certain taxes or duties, the increase or decrease shall be made
in the total target price or, if it has been established, in the
total final price, so that it will not affect the Contractor’s profit
or loss on this contract.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
         <section class="- topic/section " outputclass="Alternate"><?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
            <p class="- topic/p " id="d3247e284">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate
I </i>
               <ph outputclass="SmCaps">(Apr 1984)</ph>. As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
                  <xref base="i1104557"
                        class="- topic/xref "
                        href="16.406.dita#FAR_16_406"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">16.406</xref>
               </ph>(a),
add the following paragraph (o) to the basic clause:</p>
            <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(o) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Provisioning and options</i>. Parts,
other supplies, or services that are to be furnished under this
contract on the basis of a provisioning document or Government option
shall be subject to price revision in accordance with this clause.
Any prices established for these parts, other supplies, or services
under a provisioning document or Government option shall be treated as
target prices. Target cost and profit covering these parts, other
supplies, or services may be established separately, in the aggregate,
or in any combination, as the parties may agree.</p>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
         </section>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
