<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_8_701" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">8.701</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart-</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_8.701"
               xtrc="d502e18"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Allocation</i> means an action taken by a central nonprofit agency to designate the AbilityOne participating nonprofit agencies that will furnish definite quantities of supplies or perform specific services upon receipt of orders from ordering offices.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_8.701"
               xtrc="d502e24"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Central nonprofit agency</i> means National Industries for the Blind (NIB), which has been designated to represent people who are blind; or NISH, which has been designated to represent AbilityOne participating nonprofit agencies serving people with severe disabilities other than blindness.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d505e18">"Committee" means the Committee for Purchase From People Who Are Blind or Severely Disabled.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_8.701"
               xtrc="d502e36"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Government</i> or "entity of the Government" means any entity of the legislative or judicial branch, any executive agency, military department, Government corporation, or independent establishment, the U.S. Postal Service, or any nonappropriated-fund instrumentality of the Armed Forces.</p>
         <p id="d505e27" class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_8.701"
               xtrc="d502e43"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Ordering office</i> means any activity in an entity of the Government that places orders for the purchase of supplies or services under the AbilityOne Program.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_8.701"
               xtrc="d502e52"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Procurement List</i> means a list of supplies (including military resale commodities) and services that the Committee has determined are suitable for purchase by the Government under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=(title:41%20chapter:85%20edition:prelim)%20OR%20(granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-chapter85)&amp;f=treesort&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 85.</xref>
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_8.701"
               xtrc="d502e61"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Nonprofit agency serving people who are blind</i> or "nonprofit agency serving people with other severe disabilities" (referred to jointly as AbilityOne participating nonprofit agencies) means a qualified nonprofit agency employing people who are blind or have other severe disabilities approved by the Committee to furnish a commodity or a service to the Government under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid%3AUSC-prelim-title41-chapter85&amp;saved=%7CZ3JhbnVsZWlkOlVTQy1wcmVsaW0tdGl0bGU0MC1jaGFwdGVyMzctZnJvbnQ%3D%7C%7C%7C0%7Cfalse%7Cprelim&amp;edition=prelim"
                  scope="external"
                  format="html">41 U.S.C. chapter 85</xref>.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
