<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_8_706" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">8.706</ph> Purchase exceptions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d499e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            Ordering offices may acquire supplies or services on the Procurement List from commercial sources only if the acquisition is specifically authorized in a purchase exception granted by the designated central nonprofit agency.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            The central nonprofit agency shall promptly grant purchase exceptions when-</p>
               <ol id="d499e32" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                The AbilityOne participating nonprofit agencies cannot provide the supplies or services within the time required, and commercial sources can provide them significantly sooner in the quantities required; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                The quantity required cannot be produced or provided economically by the AbilityOne participating nonprofit agencies.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            The central nonprofit agency granting the exception shall specify the quantity and delivery or performance period covered by the exception.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e36">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            When a purchase exception is granted, the contracting officer shall-</p>
               <ol id="d499e71" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e42">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Initiate purchase action within 15 days following the date of the exception or any extension granted by the central nonprofit agency; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Provide a copy of the solicitation to the central nonprofit agency when it is issued.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d514e52">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
						            The Committee may also grant a purchase exception, under any circumstances it considers appropriate.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
