<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_9_206_3" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">9.206-3</ph> Competition.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d563e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d590e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Presolicitation</i>. If a qualification requirement applies to an acquisition, the contracting officer shall review the applicable QPL, QML, or QBL or other identification of those sources which have met the requirement before issuing a solicitation to ascertain whether the number of sources is adequate for competition. (See <xref href="9.204.dita#FAR_9_204"
                        base="i1115894"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">9.204</xref>(a) for duties of the agency activity responsible for establishment of the qualification requirement.) If the number of sources is inadequate, the contracting officer shall request the agency activity which established the requirement to-</p>
               <ol id="d563e29" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d590e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Indicate the anticipated date on which any sources presently undergoing evaluation will have demonstrated their abilities to meet the qualification requirement so that the solicitation could be rescheduled to allow as many additional sources as possible to qualify; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d590e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Indicate whether a means other than the qualification requirement is feasible for testing or demonstrating quality assurance.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d590e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Post solicitation</i>. The contracting officer shall submit to the agency activity which established the qualification requirement the names and addresses of concerns which expressed interest in the acquisition but are not included on the applicable QPL, QML, or QBL or identified as meeting the qualification requirement. The activity will then assist interested concerns in meeting the standards specified for qualification (see <xref href="9.202.dita#FAR_9_202"
                        base="i1115830"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">9.202</xref>(a)(2) and (4)).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
