<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_9_505" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">9.505</ph> General rules.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p id="d626e8" class="- topic/p ">The general rules in <xref href="9.505-1.dita#FAR_9_505_1"
                  base="i1115013"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">9.505-1</xref> through <xref href="9.505-4.dita#FAR_9_505_4"
                  base="i1115037"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">9.505-4</xref> prescribe limitations on contracting as the means of avoiding, neutralizing, or mitigating organizational conflicts of interest that might otherwise exist in the stated situations. Some illustrative examples are provided in <xref href="9.508.dita#FAR_9_508"
                  base="i1115091"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">9.508</xref>. Conflicts may arise in situations not expressly covered in this section <xref href="#FAR_9_505"
                  base="i1114988"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">9.505</xref> or in the examples in <xref href="9.508.dita#FAR_9_508"
                  base="i1115091"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">9.508</xref>. Each individual contracting situation should be examined on the basis of its particular facts and the nature of the proposed contract. The exercise of common sense, good judgment, and sound discretion is required in both the decision on whether a significant potential conflict exists and, if it does, the development of an appropriate means for resolving it. The two underlying principles are-</p>
         <ol id="d605e46" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d632e27">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            Preventing the existence of conflicting roles that might bias a contractor’s judgment; and</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d632e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            Preventing unfair competitive advantage. In addition to the other situations described in this subpart, an unfair competitive advantage exists where a contractor competing for award of any Federal contract possesses-</p>
               <ol id="d605e65" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d632e38">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Proprietary information that was obtained from a Government official without proper authorization; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d632e43">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Source selection information (as defined in <xref href="2.101.dita#FAR_2_101"
                              base="i1125359"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref>) that is relevant to the contract but is not available to all competitors, and such information would assist that contractor in obtaining the contract.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
