<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_9_502" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">9.502</ph> Applicability.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d602e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            This subpart applies to contracts with either profit or nonprofit organizations, including nonprofit organizations created largely or wholly with Government funds.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            The applicability of this subpart is not limited to any particular kind of acquisition. However, organizational conflicts of interest are more likely to occur in contracts involving-</p>
               <ol id="d602e32" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Management support services;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Consultant or other professional services;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
								                Contractor performance of or assistance in technical evaluations; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
								                Systems engineering and technical direction work performed by a contractor that does not have overall contractual responsibility for development or production.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e41">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            An organizational conflict of interest may result when factors create an actual or potential conflict of interest on an instant contract, or when the nature of the work to be performed on the instant contract creates an actual or potential conflict of interest on a future acquisition. In the latter case, some restrictions on future activities of the contractor may be required.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d629e46">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            Acquisitions subject to unique agency organizational conflict of interest statutes are excluded from the requirements of this subpart.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
