<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="id1617MD00OFT"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">8.701</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart-</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Allocation” means an action taken by a central nonprofit agency
to designate the AbilityOne participating nonprofit agencies that
will furnish definite quantities of supplies or perform specific
services upon receipt of orders from ordering offices.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Central nonprofit agency” means National Industries for the
Blind (NIB), which has been designated to represent people who are
blind; or NISH, which has been designated to represent AbilityOne
participating nonprofit agencies serving people with severe disabilities
other than blindness.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d498e22">“Committee” means the Committee for <ph class="- topic/ph ">Purchase From</ph> People Who
Are Blind or Severely Disabled.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Government” or “entity of the Government” means any entity of
the legislative or judicial branch, any executive agency, military
department, Government corporation, or independent establishment,
the U.S. Postal Service, or any nonappropriated-fund instrumentality
of the Armed Forces.</p>
         <p id="d498e32" class="- topic/p ">“Ordering office” means any activity in an entity
of the Government that places orders for the purchase of supplies
or services <ph class="- topic/ph ">under the AbilityOne Program</ph>.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Procurement List” means a list of supplies (including military
resale commodities) and services that the Committee has determined
are suitable for purchase by the Government under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=(title:41%20chapter:85%20edition:prelim)%20OR%20(granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-chapter85)&amp;f=treesort&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 85.</xref>
         </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Nonprofit agency serving people who are blind” or “nonprofit
agency serving people with other severe disabilities” (referred to
jointly as AbilityOne participating nonprofit agencies) means a
qualified nonprofit agency employing people who are blind or have
other severe disabilities approved by the Committee to furnish a
commodity or a service to the Government under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 85</xref>.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
