<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1083775"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">32.111</ph> Contract clauses for non-commercial purchases.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2027e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2041e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the following clauses, appropriately modified with respect to payment due dates, in accordance with agency regulations-</p>
					          <ol id="d2027e23" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e27" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049385.dita#i1049385"
                              base="i1049385"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-1</xref>, Payments, in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price supply contract, a fixed-price service contract, or a contract for nonregulated communication services is contemplated;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049396.dita#i1049396"
                              base="i1049396"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-2</xref>, Payment under Fixed-Price Research and Development Contracts, in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price research and development contract is contemplated;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049405.dita#i1049405"
                              base="i1049405"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-3</xref>, Payments under Personal Services Contracts, in solicitations and contracts for personal services;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049416.dita#i1049416"
                              base="i1049416"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-4</xref>, Payments under Transportation Contracts and Transportation-Related Services Contracts, in solicitations and contracts for transportation or transportation-related services;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e75" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049425.dita#i1049425"
                              base="i1049425"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-5</xref>, Payments under Fixed-Price Construction Contracts, in solicitations and contracts for construction when a fixed-price contract is contemplated;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e88" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049477.dita#i1049477"
                              base="i1049477"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-6</xref>, Payments under Communication Service Contracts with Common Carriers, in solicitations and contracts for regulated communication services by common carriers; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e100" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049486.dita#i1049486"
                              base="i1049486"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-7</xref>, Payments under Time-and-Materials and Labor-Hour Contracts, in solicitations and contracts when a time-and-materials or labor-hour contract is contemplated. If the contracting officer determines that it is necessary to withhold payment to protect the Government’s interests, paragraph (a)(7) of the clause permits the contracting officer to unilaterally issue a modification requiring the contractor to withhold 5 percent of amounts due, up to a maximum of $50,000 under the contract. The contracting officer shall ensure that the modification specifies the percentage and total amount of the withhold payment. Normally, there should be no need to withhold payment for a contractor with a record of timely submittal of the release discharging the Government from all liabilities, obligations, and claims, as required by paragraph (g) of the clause.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2041e114" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the following clauses, appropriately modified with respect to payment due dates in accordance with agency regulations:</p>
					          <ol id="d2027e120" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e124" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049559.dita#i1049559"
                              base="i1049559"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-8</xref>, Discounts for Prompt Payment, in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price supply contract or fixed-price service contract is contemplated.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e136" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A clause, substantially the same as the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049569.dita#i1049569"
                              base="i1049569"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-9</xref>, Limitation on Withholding of Payments, in solicitations and contracts when a supply contract, research and development contract, service contract, time-and-materials contract, or labor-hour contract is contemplated that includes two or more terms authorizing the temporary withholding of amounts otherwise payable to the contractor for supplies delivered or services performed.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2041e150" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the following clauses, appropriately modified with respect to payments due dates in accordance with agency regulations:</p>
					          <ol id="d2027e156" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e160" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049582.dita#i1049582"
                              base="i1049582"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-10</xref>, Payments under Fixed-Price Architect-Engineer Contracts, in fixed-price architect-engineer contracts.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2041e172" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049598.dita#i1049598"
                              base="i1049598"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-11</xref>, Extras, in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price supply contract, fixed-price service contract, or a transportation contract is contemplated.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
