<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1123190"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">4.203</ph> Taxpayer identification information.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d201e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d203e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the contractor has furnished a Taxpayer Identification Number (TIN) when completing the solicitation provision at <xref href="FAR-i1063736.dita#i1063736"
                        base="i1063736"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.204-3</xref>, Taxpayer Identification, or paragraph (l) of the solicitation provision at <xref href="FAR-i1060550.dita#i1060550"
                        base="i1060550"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.212-3</xref>, Offeror Representations and Certifications-Commercial Items, the contracting officer shall, unless otherwise provided in agency procedures, attach a copy of the completed solicitation provision as the last page of the copy of the contract sent to the payment office.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d203e32" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the TIN or type of organization is derived from a source other than the provision at <xref href="FAR-i1063736.dita#i1063736"
                        base="i1063736"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.204-3</xref> or <xref href="FAR-i1060550.dita#i1060550"
                        base="i1060550"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.212-3</xref>(l), the contracting officer shall annotate the last page of the contract or order forwarded to the payment office to state the contractor’s TIN and type of organization, unless this information is otherwise provided to the payment office in accordance with agency procedures.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d203e47" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the contractor provides its TIN or type of organization to the contracting officer after award, the contracting officer shall forward the information to the payment office within 7 days of its receipt.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d203e56" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Federal Supply Schedule contracts.</i> Each contracting officer that places an order under a Federal Supply Schedule contract (see <xref href="FAR-i1117301.dita#i1117301"
                        base="i1117301"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  8.4</xref>) shall provide the TIN and type of organization information to the payment office in accordance with paragraph (b) of this section.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d203e71" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Basic ordering agreements and indefinite-delivery contracts (other than Federal Supply Schedule contracts).</p>
					          <ol id="d201e77" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d203e81" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Each contracting officer that issues a basic ordering agreement or indefinite-delivery contract (other than a Federal Supply Schedule contract) shall provide to contracting officers placing orders under the agreement or contract (if the contractor is not required to provide this information to the System for Award Management)-</p>
							              <ol id="d201e87" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d203e91" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    A copy of the agreement or contract with a copy of the completed solicitation provision at <xref href="FAR-i1063736.dita#i1063736"
                                    base="i1063736"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">52.204-3</xref> or <xref href="FAR-i1060550.dita#i1060550"
                                    base="i1060550"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">52.212-3</xref>(l) as the last page of the agreement or contract; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d203e106" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The contractor’s TIN and type of organization information.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d203e117" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Each contracting officer that places an order under a basic ordering agreement or indefinite-delivery contract (other than a Federal Supply Schedule contract) shall provide the TIN and type of organization information to the payment office in accordance with paragraph (a) or (b) of this section.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
