<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  ">
	  <concept id="i1057947"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.219-30</ph> Notice of Set-Aside for, or Sole Source Award to, Women-Owned Small Business Concerns Eligible Under the Women-Owned Small Business Program.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3284e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1099324.dita#i1099324"
                     base="i1099324"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">19.1507</xref>
				        </ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Notice of Set-Aside for, or Sole Source Award to, Women-Owned Small Business Concerns Eligible Under the Women-Owned Small Business Program (Dec 2015)</p>
			      <ol id="d3266e27" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3284e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Definitions. “Women-owned small business (WOSB) concern eligible under the WOSB Program” (in accordance with 13 CFR 127), means a small business concern that is at least 51 percent directly and unconditionally owned by, and the management and daily business operations of which are controlled by, one or more women who are citizens of the United States.</p>
					          <p id="d3284e35" class="- topic/p ">“WOSB Program Repository” means a secure, Web-based application that collects, stores, and disseminates documents to the contracting community and SBA, which verify the eligibility of a business concern for a contract to be awarded under the WOSB Program.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3284e41" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Applicability</i>. This clause applies only to-</p>
					          <ol id="d3266e55" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e54" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Contracts that have been set aside or reserved for, or awarded on a sole source basis to, WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Part or parts of a multiple-award contract that have been set aside for WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e72" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Orders set aside for WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program, under multiple-award contracts as described in <xref href="FAR-i1117805.dita#i1117805"
                              base="i1117805"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">8.405-5</xref> and <xref href="FAR-i1104008.dita#i1104008"
                              base="i1104008"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">16.505</xref>(b)(2)(i)(F).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3284e89" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            General.</p>
					          <ol id="d3266e100" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e99" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Offers are solicited only from WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program. Offers received from concerns that are not WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB program shall not be considered.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e108" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Any award resulting from this solicitation will be made to a WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e117" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contracting Officer will ensure that the apparent successful offeror has provided the required documents to the WOSB Program Repository. The contract shall not be awarded until all required documents are received.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3284e128" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Agreement. A WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program agrees that in the performance of the contract for-</p>
					          <ol id="d3266e139" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e138" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Services (except construction), the concern will perform at least 50 percent of the cost of the contract incurred for personnel with its own employees;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e147" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Supplies or products (other than procurement from a non-manufacturer in such supplies or products), the concern will perform at least 50 percent of the cost of manufacturing the supplies or products (not including the costs of materials);</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e156" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                General construction, the concern will perform at least 15 percent of the cost of the contract with its own employees (not including the costs of materials); and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e165" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Construction by special trade contractors, the concern will perform at least 25 percent of the cost of the contract with its own employees (not including cost of materials).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3284e176" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Joint Venture</i>. A joint venture may be considered a WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program if-</p>
					          <ol id="d3266e190" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e189" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                It meets the applicable size standard corresponding to the NAICS code assigned to the contract, unless an exception to affiliation applies pursuant to 13 CFR 121.103(h)(3);</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e198" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The WOSB participant of the joint venture is designated in the System for Award Management as a WOSB concern;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e207" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The parties to the joint venture have entered into a written joint venture agreement that contains provisions<term class="- topic/term "> </term>–</p>
							              <ol id="d3266e221" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3284e220" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Setting forth the purpose of the joint venture;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3284e229" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Designating a WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program as the managing venturer of the joint venture, and an employee of the managing venturer as the project manager responsible for the performance of the contract;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3284e238" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Stating that not less than 51 percent of the net profits earned by the joint venture will be distributed to the WOSB;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3284e247" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Specifying the responsibilities of the parties with regard to contract performance, sources of labor, and negotiation of the WOSB contract; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3284e256" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Requiring the final original records be retained by the managing venturer upon completion of the WOSB contract performed by the joint venture.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e267" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The joint venture must perform the applicable percentage of work required in accordance with paragraph (d) above; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3284e276" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The procuring activity executes the contract in the name of the WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program or joint venture.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3284e288" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Nonmanufacturer. A WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program that is a non-manufacturer, as defined in 13 CFR 121.406(b) or <xref href="FAR-i1101844.dita#i1101844"
                        base="i1101844"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.102</xref>(f), may submit an offer on a WOSB requirement with a NAICS code for supplies, if it meets the requirements under the non-manufacturer rule set forth in those regulations.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
