<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i1115091"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">9.508</ph> Examples.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p id="d628e13" class="- topic/p ">The examples in paragraphs (a) through
(i) <ph class="- topic/ph ">of this section</ph> illustrate
situations in which questions concerning organizational conflicts
of interest may arise. They are not all inclusive, but are intended
to help the contracting officer apply the general rules in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="FAR-i1114988.dita#i1114988"
                     base="i1114988"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">9.505</xref>
            </ph> to individual
contract situations.</p>
         <ol id="d614e22" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                   Company
A agrees to provide systems engineering and technical direction
for the Navy on the powerplant for a group of submarines (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">i.e.,</i>turbines,
drive shafts, propellers, etc.). Company A should not be allowed
to supply any powerplant components. Company A can, however, supply
components of the submarine unrelated to the powerplant (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>fire
control, navigation, etc.). In this example, the system is the powerplant,
not the submarine, and the ban on supplying components is limited
to those for the system only.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e44" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                   Company
A is the systems engineering and technical direction contractor
for system X. After some progress, but before completion, the system
is canceled. Later, system Y is developed to achieve the same purposes
as system X, but in a fundamentally different fashion. Company B
is the systems engineering and technical direction contractor for
system Y. Company A may supply system Y or its components.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e53" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                   Company
A develops new electronic equipment and, as a result of this development,
prepares specifications. Company A may supply the equipment.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e62" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                   XYZ Tool
Company and PQR Machinery Company, representing the American Tool
Institute, work under Government supervision and control to refine
specifications or to clarify the requirements of a specific acquisition.
These companies may supply the item.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e71" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                   Before an
acquisition for information technology is conducted, Company A is
awarded a contract to prepare data system specifications and equipment
performance criteria to be used as the basis for the equipment competition.
Since the specifications are the basis for selection of commercial
hardware, a potential conflict of interest exists. Company A should
be excluded from the initial follow-on information technology hardware
acquisition.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e81" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                   Company
A receives a contract to define the detailed performance characteristics
an agency will require for purchasing rocket fuels. Company A has
not developed the particular fuels. When the definition contract
is awarded, it is clear to both parties that the agency will use
the performance characteristics arrived at to choose competitively
a contractor to develop or produce the fuels. Company A may not
be awarded this follow-on contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e90" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                   Company
A receives a contract to prepare a detailed plan for scientific
and technical training of an agency’s personnel. It suggests a curriculum
that the agency endorses and incorporates in its request for proposals
to institutions to establish and conduct the training. Company A
may not be awarded a contract to conduct the training.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e99" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(h)</ph>
                   Company A is selected to study
the use of lasers in communications. The agency intends to ask that
firms doing research in the field make proprietary information available
to Company A. The contract must require Company A to-</p>
               <ol id="d614e102" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d628e109" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                         Enter into
agreements with these firms to protect any proprietary information
they provide; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d628e118" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                         Refrain from using the information
in supplying lasers to the Government or for any purpose other than
that for which it was intended.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d628e129" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                   An agency
that regulates an industry wishes to develop a system for evaluating
and processing license applications. Contractor X helps develop
the system and process the applications. Contractor X should be
prohibited from acting as a consultant to any of the applicants
during its period of performance and for a reasonable period thereafter.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
