<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept id="i1126703"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">1.301</ph> Policy.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d31e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d33e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
					          </p>
					          <ol id="d31e23" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d33e27" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Subject to the authorities in paragraph (c) of this section and other statutory authority, an agency head may issue or authorize the issuance of agency acquisition regulations that implement or supplement the FAR and incorporate, together with the FAR, agency policies, procedures, contract clauses, solicitation provisions, and forms that govern the contracting process or otherwise control the relationship between the agency, including any of its suborganizations, and contractors or prospective contractors.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d33e36" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Subject to the authorities in paragraph (c) of this section and other statutory authority, an agency head may issue or authorize the issuance of internal agency guidance at any organizational level (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>designations and delegations of authority, assignments of responsibilities, work-flow procedures, and internal reporting requirements).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d33e50" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Agency heads shall establish procedures to ensure that agency acquisition regulations are published for comment in the Federal Register</i> in conformance with the procedures in <xref href="FAR-i1126551.dita#i1126551"
                        base="i1126551"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  1.5</xref> and as required by <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. 1707</xref>, and other applicable statutes, when they have a significant effect beyond the internal operating procedures of the agency or have a significant cost or administrative impact on contractors or offerors. However, publication is not required for issuances that merely implement or supplement higher level issuances that have previously undergone the public comment process, unless such implementation or supplementation results in an additional significant cost or administrative impact on contractors or offerors or effect beyond the internal operating procedures of the issuing organization. Issuances under <xref href="#i1126703"
                        base="i1126703"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">1.301</xref>(a)(2) need not be publicized for public comment.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d33e71" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            When adopting acquisition regulations, agencies shall ensure that they comply with the Paperwork Reduction Act (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">44 U.S.C.3501</xref>, <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">et seq.</i>) as implemented in 5 CFR1320 (see <xref href="FAR-i1126974.dita#i1126974"
                        base="i1126974"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">1.106</xref>) and the Regulatory Flexibility Act (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">5 U.S.C.601</xref>, <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">et seq.</i>). Normally, when a law requires publication of a proposed regulation, the Regulatory Flexibility Act applies and agencies must prepare written analyses, or certifications as provided in the law.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d33e96" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Agency acquisition regulations implementing or supplementing the FAR are, for-</p>
					          <ol id="d31e102" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d33e106" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The military departments and defense agencies, issued subject to the authority of the Secretary of Defense;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d33e115" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                NASA activities, issued subject to the authorities of the Administrator of NASA; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d33e124" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The civilian agencies other than NASA, issued by the heads of those agencies subject to the overall authority of the Administrator of General Services or independent authority the agency may have.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
