<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1096966"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">22.1012-2</ph> Wage determinations based on collective bargaining agreements.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1397e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1411e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In sealed bidding, a new or changed collective bargaining agreement shall not be effective under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> if the contracting agency has received notice of the terms of the new or changed collective bargaining agreement less than 10 days before bid opening and the contracting officer determines that there is not reasonable time to incorporate the new or changed terms of the collective bargaining agreement in the solicitation.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1411e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            For contractual actions other than sealed bidding, a new or changed collective bargaining agreement shall not be effective under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> if notice of the terms of the new or changed collective bargaining agreement is received by the contracting agency after award of a successor contract or a modification as specified in <xref href="FAR-i1096782.dita#i1096782"
                        base="i1096782"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1007</xref>(b), provided that the contract start of performance is within 30 days of the award of the contract or of the specified modification. If the contract does not specify a start of performance date which is within 30 days of the award of the contract or of the specified modification, or if contract performance does not commence within 30 days of the award of the contract or of the specified modification, any notice of the terms of a new or changed collective bargaining agreement received by the agency not less than 10 days before commencement of the work shall be effective for purposes of the successor contract under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref>.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1411e47" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The limitations in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection shall apply only if timely notification required in <xref href="FAR-i1096936.dita#i1096936"
                        base="i1096936"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1010</xref> has been given.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1411e59" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the contracting officer has submitted an e98 to Department of Labor requesting a wage determination based on a collective bargaining agreement and has not received a response from the Department of Labor within 10 days, the contracting officer shall contact the Wage and Hour Division by telephone to determine when the wage determination can be expected. (The telephone number is provided on the e98 website.) If the Department of Labor is unable to provide the wage determination by the latest date needed to maintain the acquisition schedule, the contracting officer shall incorporate the collective bargaining agreement itself in a solicitation or other contract action (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> exercise of option) and include a wage determination referencing that collective bargaining agreement created by use of the WDOL website (see <xref href="FAR-i1096794.dita#i1096794"
                        base="i1096794"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1008-1</xref>(d)(2)).</p>
					          <p id="d1411e71" class="- topic/p "/>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
