<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1083117"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">32.202-1</ph> Policy.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2037e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2051e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Use of financing in contracts.</i> It is the responsibility of the contractor to provide all resources needed for performance of the contract. Thus, for purchases of commercial items, financing of the contract is normally the contractor’s responsibility. However, in some markets the provision of financing by the buyer is a commercial practice. In these circumstances, the contracting officer may include appropriate financing terms in contracts for commercial purchases when doing so will be in the best interest of the Government.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2051e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Authorization.</i> Commercial interim payments and commercial advance payments may be made under the following circumstances-</p>
					          <ol id="d2037e38" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e42" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contract item financed is a commercial supply or service;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contract price exceeds the simplified acquisition threshold;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e60" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contracting officer determines that it is appropriate or customary in the commercial marketplace to make financing payments for the item;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e69" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Authorizing this form of contract financing is in the best interest of the Government (see paragraph (e) of this sub-section);</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e78" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Adequate security is obtained (see <xref href="FAR-i1083181.dita#i1083181"
                              base="i1083181"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">32.202-4</xref>);</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e91" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Prior to any performance of work under the contract, the aggregate of commercial advance payments shall not exceed 15 percent of the contract price;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e100" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contract is awarded on the basis of competitive procedures or, if only one offer is solicited, adequate consideration is obtained (based on the time value of the additional financing to be provided) if the financing is expected to be substantially more advantageous to the offeror than the offeror’s normal method of customer financing; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2051e109" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contracting officer obtains concurrence from the payment office concerning liquidation provisions when required by <xref href="FAR-i1083258.dita#i1083258"
                              base="i1083258"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">32.206</xref>(e).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2051e123" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Difference from non-commercial financing.</i> Government financing of commercial purchases under this subpart is expected to be different from that used for non-commercial purchases under <xref href="FAR-i1083622.dita#i1083622"
                        base="i1083622"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  32.1</xref> and its related subparts. While the contracting officer may adapt techniques and procedures from the non-commercial subparts for use in implementing commercial contract financing arrangements, the contracting officer must have a full understanding of effects of the differing contract environments and of what is needed to protect the interests of the Government in commercial contract financing.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2051e138" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Unusual contract financing.</i> Any contract financing arrangement not in accord with the requirements of agency regulations or this part is unusual contract financing and requires advance approval in accordance with agency procedures. If not otherwise specified, such unusual contract financing shall be approved by the head of the contracting activity.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2051e150" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Best interest of the Government.</i> The statutes cited in <xref href="FAR-i1083111.dita#i1083111"
                        base="i1083111"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.201</xref> do not allow contract financing by the Government unless it is in the best interest of the United States. Agencies may establish standards to determine whether contract financing is in the best interest of the Government. These standards may be for certain types of procurements, certain types of items, or certain dollar levels of procurements.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
