<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1099561"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">19.1303</ph> Status as a HUBZone small business concern.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1232e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1246e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Status as a HUBZone small business concern is determined by the Small Business Administration (SBA) in accordance with 13 CFR Part126.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1246e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the SBA determines that a concern is a HUBZone small business concern, it will issue a certification to that effect and will add the concern to the List of Qualified HUBZone Small Business Concerns at <xref href="http://dsbs.sba.gov/dsbs/search/dsp_searchhubzone.cfm"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">http://dsbs.sba.gov/dsbs/search/dsp_searchhubzone.cfm</xref>. Only firms on the list are HUBZone small business concerns, eligible for HUBZone preferences. HUBZone preferences apply without regard to the place of performance. Information on HUBZone small business concerns can also be obtained at <xref href="http://www.sba.gov/hubzone"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">www.sba.gov/hubzone</xref> or by writing to the Director for the HUBZone Program (Director/HUB) at U.S. Small Business Administration, 409 3 rd Street, SW., Washington, DC 20416 or at hubzone@sba.gov.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1246e41" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            A joint venture may be considered a HUBZone small business concern if it meets the criteria in the explanation of affiliates (see <xref href="FAR-i1101807.dita#i1101807"
                        base="i1101807"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.101</xref>).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1246e53" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            To be eligible for a HUBZone contract under this section, a HUBZone small business concern must be a HUBZone small business concern both at the time of its initial offer and at the time of contract award.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1246e62" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            A HUBZone small business concern may submit an offer for supplies as a nonmanufacturer if it meets the requirements of the nonmanufacturer rule set forth at 13 CFR 121.406(b)(1) and if the small business manufacturer providing the end item is also a HUBZone small business concern.</p>
					          <ol id="d1232e68" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1246e72" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                There are no waivers to the nonmanufacturer rule for HUBZone contracts.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1246e81" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                For HUBZone contracts at or below $25,000 in total value, a HUBZone small business concern may supply the end item of any manufacturer, including a large business, so long as the product acquired is manufactured or produced in the United States.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
