<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  ">
	  <concept id="id1669B0308QM"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">4.1901</ph> Definitions.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ul class="- topic/ul ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d312e17" class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart–</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d312e23" class="- topic/p ">“Covered contractor information system” means an information system that is owned or operated by a contractor that processes, stores, or transmits Federal contract information.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d312e29" class="- topic/p ">“Federal contract information” means information, not intended for public release, that is provided by or generated for the Government under a contract to develop or deliver a product or service to the Government, but not including information provided by the Government to the public (such as that on public Web sites) or simple transactional information, such as that necessary to process payments.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d312e35" class="- topic/p ">“Information” means any communication or representation of knowledge such as facts, data, or opinions in any medium or form, including textual, numerical, graphic, cartographic, narrative, or audiovisual (Committee on National Security Systems Instruction (CNSSI) 4009).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d312e41" class="- topic/p ">“Information system” means a discrete set of information resources organized for the collection, processing, maintenance, use, sharing, dissemination, or disposition of information (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">44 U.S.C. 3502</xref>).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d312e51" class="- topic/p ">“Safeguarding” means measures or controls that are prescribed to protect information systems.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ul>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
