<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept id="i1056818"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.222-55</ph> Minimum Wages Under Executive Order 13658.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3342e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1095377.dita#i1095377"
                     base="i1095377"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">22.1906</xref>
				        </ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Minimum Wages Under Executive Order 13658 (Dec 2015)</p>
			      <ol id="d3324e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Definitions. As used in this clause–</p>
					          <p id="d3342e35" class="- topic/p ">“United States” means the 50 states and the District of Columbia.</p>
					          <p id="d3342e38" class="- topic/p ">“Worker” –</p>
					          <ol id="d3324e47" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Means any person engaged in performing work on, or in connection with, a contract covered by Executive Order 13658, and-</p>
							              <ol id="d3324e57" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e55" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Whose wages under such contract are governed by the Fair Labor Standards Act (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">29 U.S.C. chapter 8</xref>), the Service Contract Labor Standards statute (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 67</xref>), or the Wage Rate Requirements (Construction) statute (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">40 U.S.C. chapter 31</xref>, subchapter IV);</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e73" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Other than individuals employed in a bona fide executive, administrative, or professional capacity, as those terms are defined in 29 CFR part 541; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e82" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Regardless of the contractual relationship alleged to exist between the individual and the employer.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e93" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Includes workers performing on, or in connection with, the contract whose wages are calculated pursuant to special certificates issued under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">29 U.S.C. 214(c)</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e105" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Also includes any person working on, or in connection with, the contract and individually registered in a bona fide apprenticeship or training program registered with the Department of Labor’s Employment and Training Administration, Office of Apprenticeship, or with a State Apprenticeship Agency recognized by the Office of Apprenticeship.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e116" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Executive Order Minimum wage rate.</p>
					          <ol id="d3324e131" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e126" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall pay to workers, while performing in the United States, and performing on, or in connection with, this contract, a minimum hourly wage rate of $10.10 per hour beginning January 1, 2015.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e135" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall adjust the minimum wage paid, if necessary, beginning January 1, 2016, and annually thereafter, to meet the applicable annual E.O. minimum wage. The Administrator of the Department of Labor’s Wage and Hour Division (the Administrator) will publish annual determinations in the Federal Register no later than 90 days before the effective date of the new E.O. minimum wage rate. The Administrator will also publish the applicable E.O. minimum wage on <xref href="http://www.wdol.gov" scope="external" class="- topic/xref ">http://www.wdol.gov</xref> (or any successor website), and a general notice on all wage determinations issued under the Service Contract Labor Standards statute or the Wage Rate Requirements (Construction) statute, that will provide information on the E.O. minimum wage and how to obtain annual updates. The applicable published E.O. minimum wage is incorporated by reference into this contract.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e147" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                
							              </p>
							              <ol id="d3324e162" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e157" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The Contractor may request a price adjustment only after the effective date of the new annual E.O. minimum wage determination. Prices will be adjusted only for increased labor costs (including subcontractor labor costs) as a result of an increase in the annual E.O. minimum wage, and for associated labor costs (including those for subcontractors). Associated labor costs shall include increases or decreases that result from changes in social security and unemployment taxes and workers’ compensation insurance, but will not otherwise include any amount for general and administrative costs, overhead, or profit.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e166" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Subcontractors may be entitled to adjustments due to the new minimum wage, pursuant to paragraph (b)(2). Contractors shall consider any subcontractor requests for such price adjustment.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e175" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The Contracting Officer will not adjust the contract price under this clause for any costs other than those identified in paragraph (b)(3)(i) of this clause, and will not provide duplicate price adjustments with any price adjustment under clauses implementing the Service Contract Labor Standards statute or the Wage Rate Requirements (Construction) statute.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e186" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor warrants that the prices in this contract do not include allowance for any contingency to cover increased costs for which adjustment is provided under this clause.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e195" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A pay period under this clause may not be longer than semi-monthly, but may be shorter to comply with any applicable law or other requirement under this contract establishing a shorter pay period. Workers shall be paid no later than one pay period following the end of the regular pay period in which such wages were earned or accrued.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e205" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall pay, unconditionally to each worker, all wages due free and clear without subsequent rebate or kickback. The Contractor may make deductions that reduce a worker’s wages below the E.O. minimum wage rate only if done in accordance with 29 CFR 10.23, Deductions.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e214" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall not discharge any part of its minimum wage obligation under this clause by furnishing fringe benefits or, with respect to workers whose wages are governed by the Service Contract Labor Standards statute, the cash equivalent thereof.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e223" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Nothing in this clause shall excuse the Contractor from compliance with any applicable Federal or State prevailing wage law or any applicable law or municipal ordinance establishing a minimum wage higher than the E.O. minimum wage. However, wage increases under such other laws or municipal ordinances are not subject to price adjustment under this subpart.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e232" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(9)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall pay the E.O. minimum wage rate whenever it is higher than any applicable collective bargaining agreement(s) wage rate.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e241" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(10)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall follow the policies and procedures in 29 CFR 10.24(b) and 10.28 for treatment of workers engaged in an occupation in which they customarily and regularly receive more than $30 a month in tips.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e252" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
					          </p>
					          <ol id="d3324e267" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e262" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                This clause applies to workers as defined in paragraph (a). As provided in that definition–</p>
							              <ol id="d3324e277" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e272" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Workers are covered regardless of the contractual relationship alleged to exist between the contractor or subcontractor and the worker;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e281" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Workers with disabilities whose wages are calculated pursuant to special certificates issued under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">29 U.S.C. 214(c)</xref> are covered; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e293" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Workers who are registered in a bona fide apprenticeship program or training program registered with the Department of Labor’s Employment and Training Administration, Office of Apprenticeship, or with a State Apprenticeship Agency recognized by the Office of Apprenticeship, are covered.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e304" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                This clause does not apply to–</p>
							              <ol id="d3324e329" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e314" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Fair Labor Standards Act (FLSA)-covered individuals performing in connection with contracts covered by the E.O., <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">i.e.</i> those individuals who perform duties necessary to the performance of the contract, but who are not directly engaged in performing the specific work called for by the contract, and who spend less than 20 percent of their hours worked in a particular workweek performing in connection with such contracts;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e326" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Individuals exempted from the minimum wage requirements of the FLSA under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">29 U.S.C. 213(a)</xref> and 214(a) and (b), unless otherwise covered by the Service Contract Labor Standards statute, or the Wage Rate Requirements (Construction) statute. These individuals include but are not limited to-</p>
									                  <ol id="d3324e354" class="- topic/ol ">
										                    <li class="- topic/li ">
											                      <p id="d3342e339" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph>
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
												                        Learners, apprentices, or messengers whose wages are calculated pursuant to special certificates issued under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                                          scope="external"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">29 U.S.C. 214(a)</xref>.</p>
										                    </li>
										                    <li class="- topic/li ">
											                      <p id="d3342e351" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph>
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
												                        Students whose wages are calculated pursuant to special certificates issued under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                                          scope="external"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">29 U.S.C. 214(b)</xref>.</p>
										                    </li>
										                    <li class="- topic/li ">
											                      <p id="d3342e363" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(C)</ph>
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
												                        Those employed in a bona fide executive, administrative, or professional capacity <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/"
                                          scope="external"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">(29 U.S.C. 213(a)(1)</xref> and 29 CFR part 541).</p>
										                    </li>
									                  </ol>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e381" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Notice. The Contractor shall notify all workers performing work on, or in connection with, this contract of the applicable E.O. minimum wage rate under this clause. With respect to workers covered by the Service Contract Labor Standards statute or the Wage Rate Requirements (Construction) statute, the Contractor may meet this requirement by posting, in a prominent and accessible place at the worksite, the applicable wage determination under those statutes. With respect to workers whose wages are governed by the FLSA, the Contractor shall post notice, utilizing the poster provided by the Administrator, which can be obtained at <xref href="http://www.dol.gov/whd/govcontracts"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">http://www.dol.gov/whd/govcontracts</xref>, in a prominent and accessible place at the worksite. Contractors that customarily post notices to workers electronically may post the notice electronically provided the electronic posting is displayed prominently on any Web site that is maintained by the contractor, whether external or internal, and customarily used for notices to workers about terms and conditions of employment.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e393" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Payroll Records.</p>
					          <ol id="d3324e421" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e403" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall make and maintain records, for three years after completion of the work, containing the following information for each worker:</p>
							              <ol id="d3324e431" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e413" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Name, address, and social security number;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e422" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The worker’s occupation(s) or classification(s);</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e431" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The rate or rates of wages paid;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e440" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The number of daily and weekly hours worked by each worker;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e449" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Any deductions made; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3342e459" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Total wages paid.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e470" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall make records pursuant to paragraph (e)(1) of this clause available for inspection and transcription by authorized representatives of the Administrator. The Contractor shall also make such records available upon request of the Contracting Officer.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e479" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall make a copy of the contract available, as applicable, for inspection or transcription by authorized representatives of the Administrator.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e488" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Failure to comply with this paragraph (e) shall be a violation of 29 CFR 10.26 and this contract. Upon direction of the Administrator or upon the Contracting Officer's own action, payment shall be withheld until such time as the noncompliance is corrected.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3342e497" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Nothing in this clause limits or otherwise modifies the Contractor’s payroll and recordkeeping obligations, if any, under the Service Contract Labor Standards statute, the Wage Rate Requirements (Construction) statute, the Fair Labor Standards Act, or any other applicable law.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e509" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Access. The Contractor shall permit authorized representatives of the Administrator to conduct investigations, including interviewing workers at the worksite during normal working hours.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e518" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Withholding. The Contracting Officer, upon his or her own action or upon written request of the Administrator, will withhold funds or cause funds to be withheld, from the Contractor under this or any other Federal contract with the same Contractor, sufficient to pay workers the full amount of wages required by this clause.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e527" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(h)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Disputes. Department of Labor has set forth in 29 CFR 10.51, Disputes concerning contractor compliance, the procedures for resolving disputes concerning a contractor’s compliance with Department of Labor regulations at 29 CFR part 10. Such disputes shall be resolved in accordance with those procedures and not the Disputes clause of this contract. These disputes include disputes between the Contractor (or any of its subcontractors) and the contracting agency, the Department of Labor, or the workers or their representatives.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e536" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Antiretaliation. The Contractor shall not discharge or in any other manner discriminate against any worker because such worker has filed any complaint or instituted or caused to be instituted any proceeding under or related to compliance with the E.O. or this clause, or has testified or is about to testify in any such proceeding.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e545" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(j)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Subcontractor compliance. The Contractor is responsible for subcontractor compliance with the requirements of this clause and may be held liable for unpaid wages due subcontractor workers.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3342e554" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(k)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Subcontracts. The Contractor shall include the substance of this clause, including this paragraph (k) in all subcontracts, regardless of dollar value, that are subject to the Service Contract Labor Standards statute or the Wage Rate Requirements (Construction) statute, and are to be performed in whole or in part in the United States.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
