<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1063408"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.203-11</ph> Certification and Disclosure Regarding Payments to Influence Certain Federal Transactions.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="provision" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3053e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1124124.dita#i1124124"
                     base="i1124124"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">3.808</xref>(a)</ph>, insert the following provision:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Certification and Disclosure Regarding Payments to Influence Certain Federal Transactions (Sept 2007)</p>
			      <ol id="d3036e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3053e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions.</i> As used in this provision-“Lobbying contact” has the meaning provided at <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">2 U.S.C. 1602(8)</xref>. The terms “agency,” “influencing or attempting to influence,” “officer or employee of an agency,” “person,” “reasonable compensation,” and “regularly employed” are defined in the FAR clause of this solicitation entitled “Limitation on Payments to Influence Certain Federal Transactions” (<xref href="FAR-i1063429.dita#i1063429"
                        base="i1063429"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.203-12</xref>).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3053e47" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Prohibition</i>. The prohibition and exceptions contained in the FAR clause of this solicitation entitled “Limitation on Payments to Influence Certain Federal Transactions” (<xref href="FAR-i1063429.dita#i1063429"
                        base="i1063429"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.203-12</xref>) are hereby incorporated by reference in this provision.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3053e62" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Certification</i>. The offeror, by signing its offer, hereby certifies to the best of its knowledge and belief that no Federal appropriated funds have been paid or will be paid to any person for influencing or attempting to influence an officer or employee of any agency, a Member of Congress, an officer or employee of Congress, or an employee of a Member of Congress on its behalf in connection with the awarding of this contract.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3053e74" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Disclosure</i>. If any registrants under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 have made a lobbying contact on behalf of the offeror with respect to this contract, the offeror shall complete and submit, with its offer, OMB Standard Form LLL, Disclosure of Lobbying Activities, to provide the name of the registrants. The offeror need not report regularly employed officers or employees of the offeror to whom payments of reasonable compensation were made.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3053e86" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Penalty</i>. Submission of this certification and disclosure is a prerequisite for making or entering into this contract imposed by <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">31 U.S.C. 1352</xref>.Any person who makes an expenditure prohibited under this provision or who fails to file or amend the disclosure required to be filed or amended by this provision, shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than $10,000, and not more than $100,000, for each such failure.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofprovision">(End of provision)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
