<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1099249"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">19.1505</ph> Set-aside procedures.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1253e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1267e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer-</p>
					          <ol id="d1253e23" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e27" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall comply with <xref href="FAR-i1101696.dita#i1101696"
                              base="i1101696"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.203</xref> before deciding to set aside an acquisition under the WOSB Program;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                May set aside acquisitions exceeding the micro-purchase threshold for competition restricted to EDWOSB concerns or WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program when the acquisition-</p>
							              <ol id="d1253e45" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1267e49" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Is assigned a NAICS code in which SBA has determined that WOSB concerns are underrepresented in Federal procurement; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1267e58" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Is assigned a NAICS code in which SBA has determined that WOSB concerns are substantially underrepresented in Federal procurement, as specified on SBA’s Web site at <xref href="http://www.sba.gov/WOSB"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">http://www.sba.gov/WOSB</xref>.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1267e74" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            For requirements in NAICS codes designated by SBA as underrepresented, a contracting officer may restrict competition to EDWOSB concerns if the contracting officer has a reasonable expectation based on market research that-</p>
					          <ol id="d1253e80" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e84" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Two or more EDWOSB concerns will submit offers for the contract and;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e93" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Contract award will be made at a fair and reasonable price.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1267e104" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            A contracting officer may restrict competition to WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program (including EDWOSB concerns), for requirements in NAICS codes designated by SBA as substantially underrepresented if there is a reasonable expectation based on market research that-</p>
					          <ol id="d1253e110" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e114" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Two or more WOSB concerns eligible under the WOSB Program (including EDWOSB concerns), will submit offers and;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e123" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Contract award may be made at a fair and reasonable price.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1267e134" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer may make an award, if only one acceptable offer is received from a qualified EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1267e143" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer must check whether the apparently successful offeror filed all the required eligibility documents, and file a status protest if any documents are missing. See <xref href="FAR-i1099188.dita#i1099188"
                        base="i1099188"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.1503</xref>(d)(2).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1267e156" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If no acceptable offers are received from an EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program, the set-aside shall be withdrawn and the requirement, if still valid, must be considered for set aside in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1101696.dita#i1101696"
                        base="i1101696"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.203</xref> and subpart <xref href="FAR-i1100723.dita#i1100723"
                        base="i1100723"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.5</xref>.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1267e171" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the contracting officer rejects a recommendation by SBA’s Procurement Center Representative-</p>
					          <ol id="d1253e177" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e181" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contracting officer shall notify the procurement center representative as soon as practicable;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e190" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                SBA shall notify the contracting officer of its intent to appeal the contracting officer’s decision no later than five business days after receiving notice of the contracting officer’s decision;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e199" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contracting officer shall suspend further action regarding the procurement until the head of the agency issues a written decision on the appeal, unless the head of the agency makes a written determination that urgent and compelling circumstances which significantly affect the interests of the United States compel award of the contract;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e208" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Within 15 business days of SBA’s notification to the head of the contracting activity, SBA shall file a formal appeal to the head of the agency, or the appeal will be determined withdrawn; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1267e217" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The head of the agency, or designee, shall specify in writing the reasons for a denial of an appeal brought under this section.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
