<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i1100796"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">19.502-3</ph>
          Partial set-asides of contracts other than multiple-award contracts.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1161e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1184e12" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  The contracting officer shall set aside a portion or portions of an acquisition, except for construction, for exclusive small business participation when—</p>
               <ol id="d1161e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1184e18" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        Market research indicates that a total set-aside is not appropriate (see <xref href="FAR-i1100762.dita#i1100762"
                              base="i1100762"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.502-2</xref>);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1184e26" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        The requirement can be divided into distinct portions;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1184e31" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        The acquisition is not subject to simplified acquisition procedures;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1184e36" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        Two or more responsible small business concerns are reasonably expected to submit offers on the set-aside portion or portions of the acquisition that are competitive in terms of fair market prices, quality, and delivery;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1184e41" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        The specific program eligibility requirements identified in this part apply; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1184e46" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        The solicitation will result in a contract other than a multiple-award contract (see <xref href="FAR-i1125359.dita#i1125359"
                              base="i1125359"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref> for definition of multiple-award contract).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1184e54" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  When the contracting officer determines that a requirement is to be partially set aside, the solicitation shall identify which portion or portions are set aside and not set aside.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1184e59" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  The contracting officer shall specify in the solicitation how offers shall be submitted with regard to the set-aside and non-set-aside portions.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1184e64" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  Offers received from concerns that do not qualify as small business concerns shall be considered nonresponsive and shall be rejected on the set-aside portion of partial set-asides. However, before rejecting an offer otherwise eligible for award because of questions concerning the size representation, an SBA determination must be obtained (see <xref href="FAR-i1101116.dita#i1101116"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  19.3</xref>).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
