<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1081292"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">32.906</ph> Making payments.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2156e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2170e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General</i>. The Government will not make invoice payments earlier than 7 days prior to the due dates specified in the contract unless the agency head determines-</p>
					          <ol id="d2156e26" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e30" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                To make earlier payment on a case-by-case basis; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                That the use of accelerated payment methods are necessary (see <xref href="FAR-i1081128.dita#i1081128"
                              base="i1081128"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">32.903</xref>(a)(5)).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2170e53" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Payment office</i>. The designated payment office-</p>
					          <ol id="d2156e62" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e66" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Will mail checks on the same day they are dated;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e75" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                For payments made by EFT, will specify a date on or before the established due date for settlement of the payment at a Federal Reserve Bank;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e84" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                When the due date falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday when Government offices are closed, may make payment on the following working day without incurring a late payment interest penalty.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e93" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                When it is determined that the designated billing office erroneously rejected a proper invoice and upon resubmission of the invoice, will enter in the payment system the original date the invoice was received by the designated billing office for the purpose of calculating the correct payment due date and any interest penalties that may be due.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2170e104" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Partial deliveries.</p>
					          <ol id="d2156e110" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e114" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Contracting officers must, where the nature of the work permits, write contract statements of work and pricing arrangements that allow contractors to deliver and receive invoice payments for discrete portions of the work as soon as completed and found acceptable by the Government (see <xref href="FAR-i1083635.dita#i1083635"
                              base="i1083635"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">32.102</xref>(d)).</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2170e126" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Unless specifically prohibited by the contract, the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049385.dita#i1049385"
                              base="i1049385"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.232-1</xref>, Payments, provides that the contractor is entitled to payment for accepted partial deliveries of supplies or partial performance of services that comply with all applicable contract requirements and for which prices can be calculated from the contract terms.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2170e140" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contractor identifier</i>. Each payment or remittance advice will use the contractor invoice number in addition to any Government or contract information in describing any payment made.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2170e152" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Discounts</i>. When a discount for prompt payment is taken, the designated payment office will make payment to the contractor as close as possible to, but not later than, the end of the discount period. The discount period is specified by the contractor and is calculated from the date of the contractor’s proper invoice. If the contractor has not placed a date on the invoice, the due date is calculated from the date the designated billing office receives a proper invoice, provided the agency annotates such invoice with the date of receipt at the time of receipt. When the discount date falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday when Government offices are closed, the designated payment office may make payment on the following working day and take a discount. Payment terms are specified in the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049559.dita#i1049559"
                        base="i1049559"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.232-8</xref>, Discounts for Prompt Payment.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
