<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept id="i1124830"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">3.104-4</ph> Disclosure, protection, and marking of contractor bid or proposal information and source selection information.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d92e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d94e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Except as specifically provided for in this subsection, no person or other entity may disclose contractor bid or proposal information or source selection information to any person other than a person authorized, in accordance with applicable agency regulations or procedures, by the agency head or the contracting officer to receive such information.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d94e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Contractor bid or proposal information and source selection information must be protected from unauthorized disclosure in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1109704.dita#i1109704"
                        base="i1109704"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">14.401</xref>, <xref href="FAR-i1109077.dita#i1109077"
                        base="i1109077"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">15.207</xref>, applicable law, and agency regulations.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d94e41" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Individuals unsure if particular information is source selection information, as defined in <xref href="FAR-i1125359.dita#i1125359"
                        base="i1125359"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref>, should consult with agency officials as necessary. Individuals responsible for preparing material that may be source selection information as described at paragraph (10) of the “source selection information” definition in <xref href="FAR-i1125359.dita#i1125359"
                        base="i1125359"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref> must mark the cover page and each page that the individual believes contains source selection information with the legend <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">“Source Selection Information-See FAR</i>
						            <xref href="FAR-i1125359.dita#i1125359"
                        base="i1125359"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref>
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">and <xref href="FAR-i1124683.dita#i1124683"
                           base="i1124683"
                           outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                           class="- topic/xref ">3.104</xref>.”</i> Although the information in paragraphs (1) through (9) of the definition in <xref href="FAR-i1125359.dita#i1125359"
                        base="i1125359"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref> is considered to be source selection information whether or not marked, all reasonable efforts must be made to mark such material with the same legend.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d94e72" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Except as provided in paragraph (d)(3) of this subsection, the contracting officer must notify the contractor in writing if the contracting officer believes that proprietary information, contractor bid or proposal information, or information marked in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1059069.dita#i1059069"
                        base="i1059069"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.215-1</xref>(e) has been inappropriately marked. The contractor that has affixed the marking must be given an opportunity to justify the marking.</p>
					          <ol id="d92e81" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e85" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the contractor agrees that the marking is not justified, or does not respond within the time specified in the notice, the contracting officer may remove the marking and release the information.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e94" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If, after reviewing the contractor’s justification, the contracting officer determines that the marking is not justified, the contracting officer must notify the contractor in writing before releasing the information.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e103" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                For technical data marked as proprietary by a contractor, the contracting officer must follow the procedures in <xref href="FAR-i1089292.dita#i1089292"
                              base="i1089292"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">27.404-5</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d94e117" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            This section does not restrict or prohibit-</p>
					          <ol id="d92e123" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e127" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A contractor from disclosing its own bid or proposal information or the recipient from receiving that information;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e136" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The disclosure or receipt of information, not otherwise protected, relating to a Federal agency procurement after it has been canceled by the Federal agency, before contract award, unless the Federal agency plans to resume the procurement;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e145" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Individual meetings between a Federal agency official and an offeror or potential offeror for, or a recipient of, a contract or subcontract under a Federal agency procurement, provided that unauthorized disclosure or receipt of contractor bid or proposal information or source selection information does not occur; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e154" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Government’s use of technical data in a manner consistent with the Government’s rights in the data.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d94e166" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            This section does not authorize-</p>
					          <ol id="d92e172" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e176" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The withholding of any information pursuant to a proper request from the Congress, any committee or subcommittee thereof, a Federal agency, the Comptroller General, or an Inspector General of a Federal agency, except as otherwise authorized by law or regulation. Any release containing contractor bid or proposal information or source selection information must clearly identify the information as contractor bid or proposal information or source selection information related to the conduct of a Federal agency procurement and notify the recipient that the disclosure of the information is restricted by <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 21</xref>;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e188" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The withholding of information from, or restricting its receipt by, the Comptroller General in the course of a protest against the award or proposed award of a Federal agency procurement contract;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e197" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The release of information after award of a contract or cancellation of a procurement if such information is contractor bid or proposal information or source selection information that pertains to another procurement; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d94e206" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The disclosure, solicitation, or receipt of bid or proposal information or source selection information after award if disclosure, solicitation, or receipt is prohibited by law. (See <xref href="FAR-i1124740.dita#i1124740"
                              base="i1124740"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">3.104-2</xref>(b)(5) and <xref href="FAR-i1093980.dita#i1093980"
                              base="i1093980"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  24.2</xref>.)</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
