<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1045849"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.247-29</ph> F.o.b. Origin.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3680e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1070179.dita#i1070179"
                     base="i1070179"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">47.303-1</xref>(c)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">F.o.b. Origin (Feb 2006)</p>
			      <ol id="d3663e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3680e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The term “f.o.b. origin,” as used in this clause, means free of expense to the Government delivered-</p>
					          <ol id="d3663e35" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                On board the indicated type of conveyance of the carrier (or of the Government, if specified) at a designated point in the city, county, and State from which the shipment will be made and from which line-haul transportation service (as distinguished from switching, local drayage, or other terminal service) will begin;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                To, and placed on, the carrier’s wharf (at shipside, within reach of the ship’s loading tackle, when the shipping point is within a port area having water transportation service) or the carrier’s freight station;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e57" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                To a U.S. Postal Service facility; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e66" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If stated in the solicitation, to any Government designated point located within the same city or commercial zone as the f.o.b. origin point specified in the contract (the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration prescribes commercial zones at Subpart B of 49 CFR part 372).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3680e77" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contractor shall-</p>
					          <ol id="d3663e83" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e87" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                
							              </p>
							              <ol id="d3663e93" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e97" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Pack and mark the shipment to comply with contract specifications; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e106" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    In the absence of specifications, prepare the shipment in conformance with carrier requirements to protect the goods and to ensure assessment of the lowest applicable transportation charge;</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e117" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                
							              </p>
							              <ol id="d3663e123" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e127" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Order specified carrier equipment when requested by the Government; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e136" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    If not specified, order appropriate carrier equipment not in excess of capacity to accommodate shipment;</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e147" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Deliver the shipment in good order and condition to the carrier, and load, stow, trim, block, and/or brace carload or truckload shipment (when loaded by the Contractor) on or in the carrier’s conveyance as required by carrier rules and regulations;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e156" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Be responsible for any loss of and/or damage to the goods-</p>
							              <ol id="d3663e162" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e166" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Occurring before delivery to the carrier;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e175" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Resulting from improper packing and marking; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e184" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Resulting from improper loading, stowing, trimming, blocking, and/or bracing of the shipment, if loaded by the Contractor on or in the carrier’s conveyance;</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e195" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Complete the Government bill of lading supplied by the ordering agency or, when a Government bill of lading is not supplied, prepare a commercial bill of lading or other transportation receipt. The bill of lading shall show-</p>
							              <ol id="d3663e201" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e205" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    A description of the shipment in terms of the governing freight classification or tariff (or Government rate tender) under which lowest freight rates are applicable;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e214" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The seals affixed to the conveyance with their serial numbers or other identification;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e223" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Lengths and capacities of cars or trucks ordered and furnished;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e232" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Other pertinent information required to effect prompt delivery to the consignee, including name, delivery address, postal address and ZIP code of consignee, routing, etc.;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e241" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Special instructions or annotations requested by the ordering agency for commercial bills of lading; <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g., “This shipment is the property of, and the freight charges paid to the carrier(s) will be reimbursed by, the Government”;</i>and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3680e254" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The signature of the carrier’s agent and the date the shipment is received by the carrier; and</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e266" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Distribute the copies of the bill of lading, or other transportation receipts, as directed by the ordering agency.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3680e277" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            These Contractor responsibilities are specified for performance at the plant or plants at which the supplies are to be finally inspected and accepted, unless the facilities for shipment by carrier’s equipment are not available at the Contractor’s plant, in which case the responsibilities shall be performed f.o.b. the point or points in the same or nearest city where the specified carrier’s facilities are available; subject, however, to the following qualifications:</p>
					          <ol id="d3663e283" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e287" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the Contractor’s shipping plant is located in the State of Alaska or Hawaii, the Contractor shall deliver the supplies listed for shipment outside Alaska or Hawaii to the port of loading in Alaska or Hawaii, respectively, as specified in the contract, at Contractor’s expense, and to that extent the contract shall be “f.o.b. destination.”</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3680e296" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Notwithstanding paragraph (c)(1) of this clause, if the Contractor’s shipping plant is located in the State of Hawaii, and the contract requires delivery to be made by container service, the Contractor shall deliver the supplies, at the Contractor’s expense, to the container yard in the same or nearest city where seavan container service is available.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
