<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="id1617MD0000A"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">17.703</ph> Policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1083e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1097e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   A DoD acquisition official may
request a nondefense agency to conduct an acquisition on behalf
of DoD in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold only if
the head of the nondefense agency conducting the acquisition on
DoD's behalf has certified that the agency will comply with applicable
procurement requirements for that fiscal year except when waived
in accordance with paragraph (e) of this section.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1097e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   A nondefense
agency is compliant with applicable procurement requirements if
the procurement policies, procedures, and internal controls of the
nondefense agency applicable to the procurement of supplies and
services on behalf of DoD, and the manner in which they are administered,
are adequate to ensure the compliance of the nondefense department
or agency with-</p>
               <ol id="d1083e32" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1097e36" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         The Federal Acquisition Regulation
and other laws and regulations that apply to procurements of supplies
and services by Federal agencies; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1097e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Laws and
regulations that apply to procurements of supplies and services
made by DoD through other Federal agencies, including DoD financial
management regulations, the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation
Supplement (DFARS), DoD class deviations, and the DFARS Procedures,
Guidance, and Information (PGI). (The DFARS, DoD class deviations,
and PGI are accessible at: <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/dars</xref>).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1097e59" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Within 30 days of the beginning
of each fiscal year, submit nondefense agency certifications of
compliance to Principal Director, Defense Pricing and Contracting
at:</p>
               <p id="d1097e65" class="- topic/p ">Department
of Defense</p>
               <p id="d1097e68" class="- topic/p ">Office
of the Under Secretary of Defense (Acquisition and Sustainment)</p>
               <p id="d1097e71" class="- topic/p ">Defense Pricing
and Contracting</p>
               <p id="d1097e74" class="- topic/p ">Contract
Policy</p>
               <p id="d1097e78" class="- topic/p ">Room
3B938</p>
               <p id="d1097e81" class="- topic/p ">3060
Defense Pentagon,</p>
               <p id="d1097e84" class="- topic/p ">Washington D.C. 20301-3060.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1097e90" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   The DoD
acquisition official, as defined at 17.701, shall provide to the
servicing nondefense agency contracting officer any DoD-unique terms,
conditions, other related statutes, regulations, directives, and
other applicable requirements for incorporation into the order or
contract. In the event there are no DoD-unique requirements beyond
the FAR, the DoD acquisition official shall so inform the servicing
nondefense agency contracting officer in writing. Nondefense agency
contracting officers are responsible for ensuring support provided
in response to DoD’s request complies with paragraph (b) of this
section.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1097e99" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  <ph class="- topic/ph ">
                     <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Waiver</i>
                  </ph>. The limitation
in paragraph (a) of this section shall not apply to the acquisition
of supplies and services on behalf of DoD by a nondefense agency
during any fiscal year for which the Under Secretary of Defense
for <ph class="- topic/ph ">Acquisition and Sustainment</ph> has
determined in writing that it is necessary in the interest of DoD
to acquire supplies and services through the nondefense agency during
the fiscal year. The written determination shall identify the acquisition
categories to which the waiver applies.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1097e118" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Nondefense
agency certifications, waivers, and additional information are available
at <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">http://www.acq.osd.mil/dpap/cpic/cp/interagency_acquisition.html</xref>.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
