<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept id="i1097948"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">22.406-3</ph> Additional classifications.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1314e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1328e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If any laborer or mechanic is to be employed in a classification that is not listed in the wage determination applicable to the contract, the contracting officer, pursuant to the clause at <xref href="FAR-i52_222_6.dita#i52_222_6"
                        base="i1055387"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.222-6</xref>, Construction Wage Rate Requirements, shall require that the contractor submit to the contracting officer, <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/request-authorization-additional-classification-and-rate"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">Standard Form (SF) 1444</xref>, Request for Authorization of Additional Classification and Rate, which, along with other pertinent data, contains the proposed additional classification and minimum wage rate including any fringe benefits payments.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1328e32" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Upon receipt of <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/request-authorization-additional-classification-and-rate"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">SF 1444</xref> from the contractor, the contracting officer shall review the request to determine whether it meets the following criteria:</p>
					          <ol id="d1314e41" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1328e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The classification is appropriate and the work to be performed by the classification is not performed by any classification contained in the applicable wage determination.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1328e54" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The classification is utilized in the area by the construction industry.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1328e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The proposed wage rate, including any fringe benefits, bears a reasonable relationship to the wage rates in the wage determination in the contract.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1328e74" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
					          </p>
					          <ol id="d1314e80" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1328e84" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the criteria in paragraph (b) of this subsection are met and the contractor and the laborers or mechanics to be employed in the additional classification (if known) or their representatives agree to the proposed additional classification, and the contracting officer approves, the contracting officer shall submit a report (including a copy of <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/request-authorization-additional-classification-and-rate"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">SF 1444</xref>) of that action to the Administrator, Wage and Hour Division, for approval, modification, or disapproval of the additional classification and wage rate (including any amount designated for fringe benefits); or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1328e96" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the contractor, the laborers or mechanics to be employed in the classification or their representatives, and the contracting officer do not agree on the proposed additional classification, or if the criteria are not met, the contracting officer shall submit a report (including a copy of <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/request-authorization-additional-classification-and-rate"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">SF 1444</xref>) giving the views of all interested parties and the contracting officer’s recommendation to the Administrator, Wage and Hour Division, for determination of appropriate classification and wage rate.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1328e110" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
					          </p>
					          <ol id="d1314e116" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1328e120" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Within 30 days of receipt of the report, the Administrator, Wage and Hour Division, will complete action and so advise the contracting officer, or will notify the contracting officer that additional time is necessary.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1328e129" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Upon receipt of the Department of Labor’s action, the contracting officer shall forward a copy of the action to the contractor, directing that the classification and wage rate be posted in accordance with paragraph (a) of the clause at <xref href="FAR-i52_222_6.dita#i52_222_6"
                              base="i1055387"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.222-6</xref> and that workers in the affected classification receive no less than the minimum rate indicated from the first day on which work under the contract was performed in the classification.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1328e143" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In each option to extend the term of the contract, if any laborer or mechanic is to be employed during the option in a classification that is not listed (or no longer listed) on the wage determination incorporated in that option, the contracting officer must require that the contractor submit a request for conformance using the procedures noted in paragraphs (a) through (d) of this section.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
