<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1052174"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.227-1</ph> Authorization and Consent.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3412e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1090060.dita#i1090060"
                     base="i1090060"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">27.201-2</xref>(a)(1)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Authorization and Consent (Dec 2007)</p>
			      <ol id="d3394e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3412e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Government authorizes and consents to all use and manufacture, in performing this contract or any subcontract at any tier, of any invention described in and covered by a United States patent-</p>
					          <ol id="d3394e35" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3412e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Embodied in the structure or composition of any article the delivery of which is accepted by the Government under this contract; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3412e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Used in machinery, tools, or methods whose use necessarily results from compliance by the Contractor or a subcontractor with (i) specifications or written provisions forming a part of this contract or (ii) specific written instructions given by the Contracting Officer directing the manner of performance. the entire liability to the Government for infringement of a United States patent shall be determined solely by the provisions of the indemnity clause, if any, included in this contract or any subcontract hereunder (including any lower-tier subcontract), and the Government assumes liability for all other infringement to the extent of the authorization and consent hereinabove granted.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3412e59" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contractor shall include the substance of this clause, including this paragraph (b), in all subcontracts that are expected to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold. However, omission of this clause from any subcontract, including those at or below the simplified acquisition threshold, does not affect this authorization and consent.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
			      <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section ">
				<?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
				        <p id="d3412e74" class="- topic/p ">
					          <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate I (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Apr</i>1984)</i>. As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
						            <xref href="FAR-i1090060.dita#i1090060"
                        base="i1090060"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">27.201-2</xref>(a)(2)</ph>, substitute the following paragraph (a) for paragraph (a) of the basic clause:</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(a) The Government authorizes and consents to all use and manufacture of any invention described in and covered by a United States patent in the performance of this contract or any subcontract at any tier.</p>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
				        <p class="- topic/p ">
					          <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate II (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Apr</i>1984)</i>. As prescribed in <xref href="FAR-i1090060.dita#i1090060"
                     base="i1090060"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">27.201-2</xref>(a)(3), substitute the following paragraph (a) for paragraph (a) of the basic clause:</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(a) The Government authorizes and consents to all use and manufacture in the performance of any order at any tier or subcontract at any tier placed under this contract for communication services and facilities for which rates, charges, and tariffs are <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">not</i> established by a government regulatory body, of any invention described in and covered by a United States patent-</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(1) Embodied in the structure or composition of any article the delivery of which is accepted by the Government under this contract; or</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) Used in machinery, tools, or methods whose use necessarily results from compliance by the Contractor or a subcontractor with specifications or written provisions forming a part of this contract or with specific written instructions given by the Contracting Officer directing the manner of performance.</p>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
			      </section>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
