<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i42_1503"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">42.1503</ph> Procedures.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2549e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
               </p>
               <ol id="d2549e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e27" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Agencies shall
assign responsibility and management accountability for the completeness
of past performance submissions. Agency procedures for the past
performance evaluation system shall-</p>
                     <ol id="d2549e33" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e37" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Generally
provide for input to the evaluations from the technical office,
contracting office, program management office, and where appropriate,
quality assurance and end users of the product or service.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e46" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Identify
and assign past performance evaluation roles and responsibilities
to those individuals responsible for preparing and reviewing interim
evaluations, if prepared, and final evaluations (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, contracting
officers, contracting officer representatives, project managers,
and program managers). Those individuals identified may obtain information
for the evaluation of performance from the program office, administrative
contracting office, audit office, end users of the product or service,
and any other technical or business advisor, as appropriate.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e58" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Address
management controls and appropriate management reviews of past performance
evaluations, to include accountability for documenting past performance
on PPIRS.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e67" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               If agency
procedures do not specify the individuals responsible for past performance
evaluation duties, the contracting officer is responsible for this
function.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e76" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Interim
evaluations may be prepared as required, in accordance with agency
procedures.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e89" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
               </p>
               <ol id="d2549e101" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e99" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         The
evaluation should include a clear, non-technical description of
the principal purpose of the contract or order. The evaluation should
reflect how the contractor performed. The evaluation should include
clear relevant information that accurately depicts the contractor’s
performance, and be based on objective facts supported by program
and contract or order performance data. The evaluations should be
tailored to the contract type, size, content, and complexity of
the contractual requirements.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e108" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Evaluation
factors for each assessment shall include, at a minimum, the following:</p>
                     <ol id="d2549e120" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e118" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Technical
(quality of product or service).</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e127" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Cost
control (not applicable for firm-fixed-price or fixed-price with
economic price adjustment arrangements).</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e136" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Schedule/timeliness.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e145" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Management
or business relations.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e154" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Small
business subcontracting, including reduced or untimely payments
to small business subcontractors when <xref href="FAR-i1100224.dita#i1100224"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">19.702</xref>(a)
requires a subcontracting plan (as applicable, see <xref href="#i42_1503/iTable_42-2"
                                    outputclass="fm:Table"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">Table  42-3</xref>).</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e170" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Other
(as applicable) (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, trafficking violations, tax delinquency,
failure to report in accordance with contract terms and conditions,
defective cost or pricing data, terminations, suspension and debarments).</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e184" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Evaluation
factors may include subfactors.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e193" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Each factor
and subfactor used shall be evaluated and a supporting narrative
provided. Each evaluation factor, as listed in paragraph (b)(2)
of this section, shall be rated in accordance with a five scale
rating system (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">i.e.</i>, exceptional, very good, satisfactory,
marginal, and unsatisfactory). The ratings and narratives must reflect
the definitions in the tables 42-1 or 42-2 of this section.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e207" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
               </p>
               <ol id="d2549e225" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e217" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         When
the contract provides for incentive fees, the incentive-fee contract
performance evaluation shall be entered into CPARS.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e226" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         When the
contract provides for award fee, the award fee-contract performance
adjectival rating as described in <xref href="FAR-i1104345.dita#i1104345"
                              base="i1104345"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">16.401</xref>(e)(3) shall be
entered into CPARS.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e240" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Agency
evaluations of contractor performance, including both negative and
positive evaluations, prepared under this subpart shall be provided
to the contractor as soon as practicable after completion of the
evaluation. The contractor will receive a CPARS-system generated
notification when an evaluation is ready for comment. Contractors
shall be afforded up to 14 calendar days from the date of notification
of availability of the past performance evaluation to submit comments, rebutting
statements, or additional information. Agencies shall provide for
review at a level above the contracting officer to consider disagreements
between the parties regarding the evaluation. The ultimate conclusion
on the performance evaluation is a decision of the contracting agency.
Copies of the evaluation, contractor response, and review comments,
if any, shall be retained as part of the evaluation. These evaluations
may be used to support future award decisions, and should therefore
be marked “Source Selection Information”. Evaluation of Federal
Prison Industries (FPI) performance may be used to support a waiver
request (see <xref href="FAR-i1117175.dita#i1117175"
                        base="i1117175"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">8.604</xref>) when FPI is a mandatory
source in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1117091.dita#i1117091"
                        base="i1117091"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  8.6</xref>.
The completed evaluation shall not be released to other than Government
personnel and the contractor whose performance is being evaluated
during the period the information may be used to provide source
selection information. Disclosure of such information could cause
harm both to the commercial interest of the Government and to the
competitive position of the contractor being evaluated as well as
impede the efficiency of Government operations. Evaluations used
in determining award or incentive fee payments may also be used
to satisfy the requirements of this subpart. A copy of the annual
or final past performance evaluation shall be provided to the contractor
as soon as it is finalized.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e255" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Agencies
shall require frequent evaluation (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, monthly, quarterly)
of agency compliance with the reporting requirements in <xref href="FAR-i42_1502.dita#i42_1502"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">42.1502</xref>,
so agencies can readily identify delinquent past performance reports
and monitor their reports for quality control.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e271" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Agencies
shall prepare and submit all past performance evaluations electronically
in the CPARS at <xref href="http://www.cpars.gov"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">http://www.cpars.gov/</xref>. These evaluations,
including any contractor-submitted information (with indication
whether agency review is pending), are automatically transmitted
to PPIRS at <xref href="http://www.ppirs.gov"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">http://www.ppirs.gov</xref>. not later than
14 days after the date on which the contractor is notified of the
evaluation’s availability for comment. The Government shall update
PPIRS with any contractor comments provided after 14 days, as well
as any subsequent agency review of comments received. Past performance
evaluations for classified contracts and special access programs
shall not be reported in CPARS, but will be reported as stated in
this subpart and in accordance with agency procedures. Agencies
shall ensure that appropriate management and technical controls
are in place to ensure that only authorized personnel have access
to the data and the information safeguarded in accordance with <xref href="#i42_1503"
                        base="i1074269"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">42.1503</xref>(d).</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e289" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Agencies
shall use the past performance information in PPIRS that is within
three years (six for construction and architect-engineer contracts)
of the completion of performance of the evaluated contract or order,
and information contained in the Federal Awardee Performance and
Integrity Information System (FAPIIS), <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, terminations
for default or cause.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2563e301" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(h)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Other
contractor performance information.</p>
               <ol id="d2549e319" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e311" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Agencies
shall ensure information is accurately reported in the FAPIIS module
of CPARS within 3 calendar days after a contracting officer-</p>
                     <ol id="d2549e329" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e321" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Issues
a final determination that a contractor has submitted defective
cost or pricing data;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e330" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Makes
a subsequent change to the final determination concerning defective
cost or pricing data pursuant to <xref href="FAR-i1106430.dita#i1106430"
                                    base="i1106430"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">15.407-1</xref>(d);</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e342" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Issues
a final termination for cause or default notice;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e351" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Makes
a subsequent withdrawal or a conversion of a termination for default
to a termination for convenience;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e360" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Receives
a final determination after an administrative proceeding, in accordance
with <xref href="FAR-i1095633.dita#i1095633"
                                    base="i1095633"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">22.1704</xref>(d)(1), that substantiates
an allegation of a violation of the trafficking in persons prohibitions
in <xref href="FAR-i1095563.dita#i1095563"
                                    base="i1095563"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">22.1703</xref>(a) and <xref href="FAR-i1056535.dita#i1056535"
                                    base="i1056535"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">52.222-50</xref>(b); or</p>  
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2563e379" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Determines
that a contractor has a history of three or more unjustified reduced
or untimely payments to small business subcontractors under a single
contract within a 12-month period (see <xref href="FAR-i42_1502.dita#i42_1502"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">42.1502</xref>(g)(2)).</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e393" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         The information
to be posted in accordance with this paragraph (h) is information
relating to contractor performance, but does not constitute a “past
performance review,” which would be exempted from public availability
in accordance with section 3010 of the Supplemental Appropriations
Act, 2010 (Pub. L. 111-212). Therefore, all such information posted
in FAPIIS will be publicly available, unless covered by a disclosure
exemption under the Freedom of Information Act (see <xref href="FAR-i1116277.dita#i1116277"
                              base="i1116277"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">9.105-2</xref>(b)(2)).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e405" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Agencies
shall establish CPARS focal points who will register users to report
data into the FAPIIS module of CPARS (available at <xref href="http://www.cpars.gov/"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">http://www.cpars.gov/</xref>,
then select FAPIIS).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2563e417" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         With regard
to information that may be covered by a disclosure exemption under
the Freedom of Information Act, the contracting officer shall follow
the procedures at <xref href="FAR-i1116277.dita#i1116277"
                              base="i1116277"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">9.105-2</xref>(b)(2)(iv).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
               <table frame="none"
                      colsep="0"
                      rowsep="0"
                      id="iTable_42-1"
                      class="- topic/table ">
                  <title class="- topic/title ">
                     <ph class="- topic/ph ">Table
42-1 -</ph>Evaluation Rating Definitions</title>
                  <tgroup cols="3"
                          colsep="0"
                          rowsep="0"
                          outputclass="Title_norule"
                          class="- topic/tgroup ">
                     <colspec colnum="1"
                              colname="1"
                              colwidth="19*"
                              colsep="0"
                              class="- topic/colspec "/>
                     <colspec colnum="2"
                              colname="2"
                              colwidth="41*"
                              colsep="0"
                              class="- topic/colspec "/>
                     <colspec colnum="3"
                              colname="3"
                              colwidth="40*"
                              colsep="0"
                              class="- topic/colspec "/>
                     <thead class="- topic/thead ">
                        <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1"
                                  colsep="1"
                                  align="center"
                                  outputclass="CellHeading_Ctr"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">Rating</entry>
                           <entry colname="2"
                                  colsep="1"
                                  align="center"
                                  outputclass="CellHeading_Ctr"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">Definition</entry>
                           <entry colname="3"
                                  align="center"
                                  outputclass="CellHeading_Ctr"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">Note</entry>
                        </row>
                     </thead>
                     <tbody class="- topic/tbody ">
                        <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="d2563e470" class="- topic/p ">(a)
Exceptional</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Performance meets
contractual requirements and exceeds many to the Government’s benefit.
The contractual performance of the element or sub-element being
evaluated was accomplished with few minor problems for which corrective
actions taken by the contractor were highly effective.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify an Exceptional rating,
identify multiple significant events and state how they were of benefit
to the Government. A singular benefit, however, could be of such
magnitude that it alone constitutes an Exceptional rating. Also, there
should have been NO significant weaknesses identified.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="d2563e497" class="- topic/p ">(b)
Very Good</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Performance meets
contractual requirements and exceeds some to the Government’s benefit.
The contractual performance of the element or sub-element being
evaluated was accomplished with some minor problems for which corrective
actions taken by the contractor were effective.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify a Very Good rating,
identify a significant event and state how it was a benefit to the Government.
There should have been no significant weaknesses identified.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="d2563e524" class="- topic/p ">(c)
Satisfactory</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Performance meets
contractual requirements. The contractual performance of the element
or sub-element contains some minor problems for which corrective
actions taken by the contractor appear or were satisfactory.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify a Satisfactory rating,
there should have been only minor problems, or major problems the
contractor recovered from without impact to the contract/order.
There should have been NO significant weaknesses identified. A fundamental
principle of assigning ratings is that contractors will not be evaluated
with a rating lower than Satisfactory solely for not performing
beyond the requirements of the contract/order.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="d2563e551" class="- topic/p ">(d)
Marginal</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Performance does
not meet some contractual requirements. The contractual performance
of the element or sub-element being evaluated reflects a serious
problem for which the contractor has not yet identified corrective
actions. The contractor’s proposed actions appear only marginally
effective or were not fully implemented.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify Marginal performance,
identify a significant event in each category that the contractor
had trouble overcoming and state how it impacted the Government.
A Marginal rating should be supported by referencing the management
tool that notified the contractor of the contractual deficiency
(e.g., management, quality, safety, or environmental deficiency
report or letter).</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1" colsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="d2563e578" class="- topic/p ">(e) Unsatisfactory</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2" colsep="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Performance does not meet most
contractual requirements and recovery is not likely in a timely manner.
The contractual performance of the element or sub-element contains
a serious problem(s) for which the contractor’s corrective actions
appear or were ineffective.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify an Unsatisfactory rating, identify
multiple significant events in each category that the contractor
had trouble overcoming and state how it impacted the Government.
A singular problem, however, could be of such serious magnitude
that it alone constitutes an unsatisfactory rating. An Unsatisfactory
rating should be supported by referencing the management tools used
to notify the contractor of the contractual deficiencies (e.g.,
management, quality, safety, or environmental deficiency reports,
or letters).</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                     </tbody>
                  </tgroup>
               </table>
               <p id="d2563e569" class="- topic/p ">NOTE 1: Plus or minus signs
may be used to indicate an improving (+) or worsening (-) trend
insufficient to change the evaluation status.</p>
               <p id="d2563e572" class="- topic/p ">NOTE
2: N/A (not applicable) should be used if the ratings are not going
to be applied to a particular area for evaluation.</p>
               <table frame="all"
                      colsep="1"
                      rowsep="1"
                      id="iTable_42-2"
                      class="- topic/table ">
                  <title class="- topic/title ">
                     <ph class="- topic/ph ">Table
42-2 -</ph>Evaluation Rating Definitions</title>
                  <tgroup cols="3"
                          colsep="1"
                          rowsep="1"
                          outputclass="Format A"
                          class="- topic/tgroup ">
                     <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="22*" class="- topic/colspec "/>
                     <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="42*" class="- topic/colspec "/>
                     <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="36*" class="- topic/colspec "/>
                     <tbody class="- topic/tbody ">
                        <row rowsep="1" valign="top" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="id192BF0F0VG2" class="- topic/p ">(a) Exceptional</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Exceeded
all statutory goals or goals as negotiated. Had exceptional success
with initiatives to assist, promote, and utilize small business
(SB), small disadvantaged business (SDB), women-owned small business
(WOSB), HUBZone small business, veteran-owned small business (VOSB) and
service disabled veteran owned small business (SDVOSB). Complied
with FAR <xref href="FAR-i52_219-8.dita#i52_219-8"
                                       base="i1057444"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-8</xref>, Utilization
of Small Business Concerns. Exceeded any other small business participation requirements
incorporated in the contract/order, including the use of small businesses
in mission critical aspects of the program. Went above and beyond
the required elements of the subcontracting plan and other small
business requirements of the contract/order. Completed and submitted Individual
Subcontract Reports and/or Summary Subcontract Reports in an accurate
and timely manner. Did not have a history of three or more unjustified
reduced or untimely payments to small business subcontractors within
a 12-month period.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="0" align="center" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify
an Exceptional rating, identify multiple significant events and
state how they were a benefit to small business utilization. A singular
benefit, however, could be of such magnitude that it constitutes
an Exceptional rating. Small businesses should be given meaningful
and innovative work directly related to the contract, and opportunities
should not be limited to indirect work such as cleaning offices,
supplies, landscaping, etc. Also, there should have been no significant weaknesses
identified.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1" valign="top" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="id192BF0F40MG" class="- topic/p ">(b) Very Good</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Met
all of the statutory goals or goals as negotiated. Had significant
success with initiatives to assist, promote and utilize SB, SDB,
WOSB, HUBZone, VOSB, and SDVOSB. Complied with FAR <xref href="FAR-i52_219-8.dita#i52_219-8"
                                       base="i1057444"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-8</xref>, Utilization
of Small Business Concerns. Met or exceeded any other small business participation
requirements incorporated in the contract/order, including the use
of small businesses in mission critical aspects of the program.
Endeavored to go above and beyond the required elements of the subcontracting
plan. Completed and submitted Individual Subcontract Reports and/or
Summary Subcontract Reports in an accurate and timely manner. Did
not have a history of three or more unjustified reduced or untimely
payments to small business subcontractors within a 12-month period.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="0" align="center" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify
a Very Good rating, identify a significant event and state how it
was a benefit to small business utilization. Small businesses should
be given meaningful and innovative opportunities to participate
as subcontractors for work directly related to the contract, and
opportunities should not be limited to indirect work such as cleaning offices,
supplies, landscaping, etc. There should be no significant weaknesses identified.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1" valign="top" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="id192BF0FI08C" class="- topic/p ">(c) Satisfactory</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Demonstrated
a good faith effort to meet all of the negotiated subcontracting
goals in the various socio-economic categories for the current period. Complied
with FAR <xref href="FAR-i52_219-8.dita#i52_219-8"
                                       base="i1057444"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-8</xref>, Utilization
of Small Business Concerns. Met any other small business participation
requirements included in the contract/order. Fulfilled the requirements
of the subcontracting plan included in the contract/order. Completed
and submitted Individual Subcontract Reports and/or Summary Subcontract
Reports in an accurate and timely manner. Did not have a history
of three or more unjustified reduced or untimely payments to small
business subcontractors within a 12-month period.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="0" align="center" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify
a Satisfactory rating, there should have been only minor problems,
or major problems the contractor has addressed or taken corrective
action. There should have been no significant weaknesses identified.
A fundamental principle of assigning ratings is that contractors
will not be assessed a rating lower than Satisfactory solely for
not performing beyond the requirements of the contract/order.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1" valign="top" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="id192BF0G0HBL" class="- topic/p ">(d) Marginal</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2"
                                  colsep="0"
                                  rowsep="0"
                                  align="center"
                                  class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Deficient
in meeting key subcontracting plan elements. Deficient in complying
with FAR <xref href="FAR-i52_219-8.dita#i52_219-8"
                                       base="i1057444"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-8</xref>, Utilization
of Small Business Concerns, and any other small business participation requirements
in the contract/order. Did not submit Individual Subcontract Reports
and/or Summary Subcontract Reports in an accurate or timely manner.
Failed to satisfy one or more requirements of a corrective action
plan currently in place; however, does show an interest in bringing performance
to a satisfactory level and has demonstrated a commitment to apply
the necessary resources to do so. Required a corrective action plan.
Did not have a history of three or more unjustified reduced or untimely
payments to small business subcontractors within a 12-month period.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" rowsep="0" align="center" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify
a Marginal rating, identify a significant event that the contractor
had trouble overcoming and how it impacted small business utilization.
A Marginal rating should be supported by referencing the actions
taken by the Government that notified the contractor of the contractual deficiency.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0" valign="top" class="- topic/row ">
                           <entry colname="1" colsep="0" align="center" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p id="id192BF0G0LCM" class="- topic/p ">(e) Unsatisfactory</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="2" colsep="0" align="center" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">Noncompliant
with FAR <xref href="FAR-i52_219-8.dita#i52_219-8"
                                       base="i1057444"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-8</xref> and <xref href="FAR-i52_219-9.dita#i52_219-9"
                                       base="i1057444"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-9</xref>, and any other
small business participation requirements in the contract/order.
Did not submit Individual Subcontract Reports and/or Summary Subcontract
Reports in an accurate or timely manner. Showed little interest
in bringing performance to a satisfactory level or is generally uncooperative.
Required a corrective action plan. Had a history of three or more
unjustified reduced or untimely payments to small business subcontractors
within a 12-month period.</p>
                           </entry>
                           <entry colname="3" align="center" class="- topic/entry ">
                              <p class="- topic/p ">To justify an Unsatisfactory
rating, identify multiple significant events that the contractor
had trouble overcoming and state how it impacted small business utilization.
A singular problem, however, could be of such serious magnitude
that it alone constitutes an Unsatisfactory rating. An Unsatisfactory
rating should be supported by referencing the actions taken by the
Government to notify the contractor of the deficiencies. When an Unsatisfactory
rating is justified, the contracting officer must consider whether the
contractor made a good faith effort to comply with the requirements
of the subcontracting plan required by FAR <xref href="FAR-i52_219-9.dita#i52_219-9"
                                       base="i1057444"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-9</xref> and follow the
procedures outlined in <xref href="FAR-i1057758.dita#i1057758"
                                       base="i1057758"
                                       outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                       class="- topic/xref ">52.219-16</xref>,
Liquidated Damages-Subcontracting Plan.</p>
                           </entry>
                        </row>
                     </tbody>
                  </tgroup>
               </table>
               <p id="d2563e726" class="- topic/p ">NOTE 1: Plus or minus signs
may be used to indicate an improving (+) or worsening (-) trend
insufficient to change evaluation status.</p>
               <p id="d2563e729" class="- topic/p ">NOTE
2: Generally, zero percent is not a goal unless the contracting
officer determined when negotiating the subcontracting plan that
no subcontracting opportunities exist in a particular socio-economic
category. In such cases, the contractor shall be considered to have
met the goal for any socio-economic category where the goal negotiated
in the plan was zero.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
