<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  ">
	  <concept id="i1101517"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">19.201</ph> General policy.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1130e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1144e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            It is the policy of the Government to provide maximum practicable opportunities in its acquisitions to small business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled veteran-owned small business, HUBZone small business, small disadvantaged business, and women-owned small business concerns. Such concerns must also have the maximum practicable opportunity to participate as subcontractors in the contracts awarded by any executive agency, consistent with efficient contract performance. The Small Business Administration (SBA) counsels and assists small business concerns and assists contracting personnel to ensure that a fair proportion of contracts for supplies and services is placed with small business.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1144e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Heads of contracting activities are responsible for effectively implementing the small business programs within their activities, including achieving program goals. They are to ensure that contracting and technical personnel maintain knowledge of small business program requirements and take all reasonable action to increase participation in their activities’ contracting processes by these businesses.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1144e35" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Small Business Act requires each agency with contracting authority to establish an Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization (see section 15(k) of the Small Business Act). For the Department of Defense, in accordance with section 904 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 (Public Law 109-163) (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C. 144 note</xref>), the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization has been redesignated as the Office of Small Business Programs. Management of the office is the responsibility of an officer or employee of the agency who, in carrying out the purposes of the Act—</p>
					          <ol id="d1130e44" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Is known as the Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization, or for the Department of Defense, the Director of Small Business Programs;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e57" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Be appointed by the agency head;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e66" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Is responsible to and reports directly to the agency head or the deputy to the agency head;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e75" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Is responsible for the agency carrying out the functions and duties in sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small Business Act;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e84" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Works with the SBA procurement center representative (or, if a procurement center representative is not assigned, see <xref href="FAR-i1101041.dita#i1101041"
                              base="i1101041"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.402</xref>(a)(2)) to identify proposed solicitations that involve bundling and work with the agency acquisition officials and SBA to revise the acquisition strategies for such proposed solicitations to increase the probability of participation by small businesses;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e97" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Assists small business concerns in obtaining payments under their contracts, late payment interest penalties, or information on contractual payment provisions;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e106" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Has supervisory authority over agency personnel to the extent that their functions and duties relate to sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small Business Act;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e115" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Assigns a small business technical advisor to each contracting activity within the agency to which the SBA has assigned a representative (see <xref href="FAR-i1101041.dita#i1101041"
                              base="i1101041"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.402</xref>)—</p>
							              <ol id="d1130e154" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1144e128" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Who is a full-time employee of the contracting activity, well qualified, technically trained, and familiar with the supplies or services contracted for by the activity; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1144e137" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Whose principal duty is to assist the SBA’s assigned representative in performing functions and duties relating to sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small Business Act;</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e148" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(9)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Cooperates and consults on a regular basis with the SBA in carrying out the agency's functions and duties in sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small Business Act;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e157" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(10)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Makes recommendations in accordance with agency procedures as to whether a particular acquisition should be awarded under subpart <xref href="FAR-i1100723.dita#i1100723"
                              base="i1100723"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.5</xref> as a small business set-aside, under subpart <xref href="FAR-i1099848.dita#i1099848"
                              base="i1099848"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.8</xref> as a section 8(a) award, under subpart <xref href="FAR-i1099552.dita#i1099552"
                              base="i1099552"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.13</xref> as a HUBZone set-aside, under subpart <xref href="FAR-i1099391.dita#i1099391"
                              base="i1099391"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.14</xref> as a service-disabled veteran-owned small business set-aside, or under subpart <xref href="FAR-i1099174.dita#i1099174"
                              base="i1099174"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.15</xref> as a set-aside for economically disadvantaged women-owned small business (EDWOSB) concerns or women-owned small business (WOSB) concerns eligible under the WOSB Program;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e182" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(11)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Conducts annual reviews to assess the—</p>
							              <ol id="d1130e218" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1144e192" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Extent to which small businesses are receiving a fair share of Federal procurements, including contract opportunities under the programs administered under the Small Business Act;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1144e201" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Adequacy of consolidated or bundled contract documentation and justifications; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1144e210" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Actions taken to mitigate the effects of necessary and justified consolidation or bundling on small businesses.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e222" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(12)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Provides a copy of the assessment made under paragraph (c)(11) of this section to the Agency Head and SBA Administrator;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e231" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(13)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Provides to the chief acquisition officer and senior procurement executive advice and comments on acquisition strategies, market research, and justifications related to consolidation of contract requirements;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e240" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(14)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                When notified by a small business concern prior to the award of a contract that the small business concern believes that a solicitation, request for proposal, or request for quotation unduly restricts the ability of the small business concern to compete for the award–</p>
							              <ol class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1144e250" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Submits the notification by the small business concern to the contracting officer and, if necessary, recommends ways in which the solicitation, request for proposal, or request for quotation may be altered to increase the opportunity for competition; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1144e259" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Informs the advocate for competition of such agency (as established under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C 1705</xref> or <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C. 2318</xref>) of such notification;</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e276" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(15)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Ensures agency purchases using the Governmentwide purchase card that are greater than the micro-purchase threshold and less than the simplified acquisition threshold were made in compliance with the Small Business Act and were properly recorded in accordance with subpart 4.6 in the Federal Procurement Data System;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e285" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(16)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Assists small business contractors and subcontractors in finding resources for education and training on compliance with contracting regulations;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e294" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(17)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Reviews all subcontracting plans required by <xref href="FAR-i1100224.dita#i1100224"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.702</xref>(a) to ensure the plan provides maximum practicable opportunity for small business concerns to participate in the performance of the contract; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1144e307" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(18)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Performs other duties listed at <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1144e321" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Small Business Specialists must be appointed and act in accordance with agency regulations.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
