<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1068532"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">49.001</ph> Definitions.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p class="- topic/p ">As used in this part-</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Other work” means any current or scheduled work of the contractor, whether Government or commercial, other than work related to the terminated contract.</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Plant clearance period,” as used in this subpart, means the period beginning on the effective date of contract completion or termination and ending 90 days (or such longer period as may be agreed to) after receipt by the contracting officer of acceptable inventory schedules for each property classification. The final phase of the plant clearance period means that period after receipt of acceptable inventory schedules.</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Settlement agreement” means a written agreement in the form of a contract modification settling all or a severable portion of a settlement proposal.</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Settlement proposal” means a proposal for effecting settlement of a contract terminated in whole or in part, submitted by a contractor or subcontractor in the form, and supported by the data, required by this part. A settlement proposal is included within the generic meaning of the word “claim” under false claims acts (see <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                  scope="external"
                  format="html"
                  class="- topic/xref ">18 U.S.C.287</xref> and <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                  scope="external"
                  format="html"
                  class="- topic/xref ">31 U.S.C.3729</xref>).</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Unsettled contract change” means any contract change or contract term for which a definitive modification is required but has not been executed.</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
