<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1056197"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.222-34</ph> Project Labor Agreement.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3321e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1097603.dita#i1097603"
                     base="i1097603"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">22.505</xref>(b)(1)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Project Labor Agreement (May 2010)</p>
			      <ol id="d3303e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3321e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>. As used in this clause-</p>
					          <p id="d3321e38" class="- topic/p ">“Labor organization” means a labor organization as defined in <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">29 U. S.C. 152(5)</xref>.</p>
					          <p id="d3321e44" class="- topic/p ">“Project labor agreement” means a pre-hire collective bargaining agreement with one or more labor organizations that establishes the terms and conditions of employment for a specific construction project and is an agreement described in <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">29U. S.C.158(f)</xref>.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3321e53" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contractor shall maintain in a current status throughout the life of the contract the project labor agreement entered into prior to the award of this contract in accordance with solicitation provision <xref href="FAR-i1056167.dita#i1056167"
                        base="i1056167"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.222-33</xref>, Notice of Requirement for Project Labor Agreement.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3321e65" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Subcontracts</i>. The Contractor shall include the substance of this clause, including this paragraph (c), in all subcontracts with subcontractors engaged in construction on the construction project.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
			      <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section ">
				<?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
				        <p id="d3321e83" class="- topic/p ">
					          <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate I (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">May</i> 2010)</i>. As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
						            <xref href="FAR-i1097603.dita#i1097603"
                        base="i1097603"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.505</xref>(b)(2)</ph>, substitute the following paragraphs (b) through (f) for paragraphs (b) and (c) of the basic clause:</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(b) Consistent with applicable law, the Contractor shall negotiate a project labor agreement with one or more labor organizations for the term of this construction contract. The Contractor shall submit an executed copy of the project labor agreement to the Contracting Officer.</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(c) Consistent with applicable law, the project labor agreement reached pursuant to this clause shall-</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(1) Bind the Contractor and all subcontractors engaged in construction on the construction project to comply with the project labor agreement;</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) Allow the Contractor and all subcontractors to compete for contracts and subcontracts without regard to whether they are otherwise parties to collective bargaining agreements;</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(3) Contain guarantees against strikes, lockouts, and similar job disruptions;</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(4) Set forth effective, prompt, and mutually binding procedures for resolving labor disputes arising during the project labor agreement;</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(5) Provide other mechanisms for labor-management cooperation on matters of mutual interest and concern, including productivity, quality of work, safety, and health; and</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(6) Fully conform to all statutes, regulations, Executive orders, and agency requirements.</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(d) Any project labor agreement reached pursuant to this clause does not change the terms of this contract or provide for any price adjustment by the Government.</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(e) The Contractor shall maintain in a current status throughout the life of the contract the project labor agreement entered into pursuant to this clause.</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(f) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Subcontracts</i>. The Contractor shall require subcontractors engaged in construction on the construction project to agree to any project labor agreement negotiated by the prime contractor pursuant to this clause, and shall include the substance of paragraphs (d) through (f) of this clause in all subcontracts with subcontractors engaged in construction on the construction project.</p>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
			      </section>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
