<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
	<concept id="i1101807" ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2" class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		<title class="- topic/title ">
			<ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">19.101</ph> Definitions.</title>
		<conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
			<p class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart—</p>
			<p id="id199RD9002QT" class="- topic/p ">“Affiliates.” means business concerns, one of whom directly or indirectly controls or has the power to control the others, or a third party or parties control or have the power to control the others. In determining whether affiliation exists, consideration is given to all appropriate factors including common ownership, common management, and contractual relationships. SBA determines affiliation based on the factors set forth at 13 CFR 121.103.</p>
			<p id="d1148e327" class="- topic/p ">“Annual receipts.”</p>
			<ol id="d1127e19" class="- topic/ol ">
				<li class="- topic/li ">
					<ol id="d1127e334" class="- topic/ol ">
						<li class="- topic/li ">
							<p id="d1148e30" class="- topic/p ">
								<ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Annual receipts of a concern which has been in business for 3 or more complete fiscal years means the annual average gross revenue of the concern taken for the last 3 fiscal years. For the purpose of this definition, gross revenue of the concern includes revenues from sales of products and services, interest, rents, fees, commissions and/or whatever other sources derived, but less returns and allowances, sales of fixed assets, interaffiliate transactions between a concern and its domestic and foreign affiliates, and taxes collected for remittance (and if due, remitted) to a third party. Such revenues shall be measured as entered on the regular books of account of the concern whether on a cash, accrual, or other basis of accounting acceptable to the U.S. Treasury Department for the purpose of supporting Federal income tax returns, except when a change in accounting method from cash to accrual or accrual to cash has taken place during such 3-year period, or when the completed contract method has been used.</p>
							<ol id="d1127e344" class="- topic/ol ">
								<li class="- topic/li ">
									<p id="d1148e40" class="- topic/p ">
										<ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>In any case of change in accounting method from cash to accrual or accrual to cash, revenues for such 3-year period shall, prior to the calculation of the annual average, be restated to the accrual method. In any case, where the completed contract method has been used to account for revenues in such 3-year period, revenues must be restated on an accrual basis using the percentage of completion method.</p>
								</li>
								<li class="- topic/li ">
									<p id="d1148e49" class="- topic/p ">
										<ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>In the case of a concern which does not keep regular books of accounts, but which is subject to U.S. Federal income taxation, “annual receipts” shall be measured as reported, or to be reported to the U.S. Treasury Department, Internal Revenue Service, for Federal income tax purposes, except that any return based on a change in accounting method or on the completed contract method of accounting must be restated as provided for in the preceding paragraphs.</p>
								</li>
							</ol>
						</li>
						<li class="- topic/li ">
							<p id="d1148e60" class="- topic/p ">
								<ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Annual receipts of a concern that has been in business for less than 3 complete fiscal years means its total receipts for the period it has been in business, divided by the number of weeks including fractions of a week that it has been in business, and multiplied by 52. In calculating total receipts, the definitions and adjustments related to a change of accounting method and the completed contract method of paragraph (1) of this definition, are applicable.</p>
						</li>
					</ol>
				</li>
			</ol>
			<p id="d1148e374" class="- topic/p ">“Number of employees” is a measure of the average employment of a business concern and means its average employment, including the employees of its domestic and foreign affiliates, based on the number of persons employed on a full-time, part-time, temporary, or other basis during each of the pay periods of the preceding 12 months. If a business has not been in existence for 12 months, “number of employees” means the average employment of such concern and its affiliates during the period that such concern has been in existence based on the number of persons employed during each of the pay periods of the period that such concern has been in business. If a business has acquired an affiliate during the applicable 12-month period, it is necessary, in computing the applicant’s number of employees, to include the affiliate’s number of employees during the entire period, rather than only its employees during the period in which it has been an affiliate. The employees of a former affiliate are not included, even if such concern had been an affiliate during a portion of the period.</p>
			<msgblock props="Citation" xml:space="preserve" class="+ topic/pre sw-d/msgblock ">[51 FR 2650, Jan. 17, 1986, as amended at 64 FR 32743, June 17, 1999; 64 FR 72444, Dec. 27, 1999; 65 FR 46055, July 26, 2000; 66 FR 2129, Jan. 10, 2001; 68 FR 28081, May 22, 2003; 75 FR 77729, Dec. 13, 2010]</msgblock>
		</conbody>
	</concept>
</dita>