<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1088534"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">28.101-4</ph> Noncompliance with bid guarantee requirements.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1783e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1797e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In sealed bidding, noncompliance with a solicitation requirement for a bid guarantee requires rejection of the bid, except in the situations described in paragraph (c) of this subsection when the noncompliance shall be waived.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1797e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In negotiation, noncompliance with a solicitation requirement for a bid guarantee requires rejection of an initial proposal as unacceptable, if a determination is made to award the contract based on initial proposals without discussion, except in the situations described in paragraph (c) of this subsection when noncompliance shall be waived. (See <xref href="FAR-i1108639.dita#i1108639"
                        base="i1108639"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">15.306</xref>(a)(2) for conditions regarding making awards based on initial proposals.) If the conditions for awarding based on initial proposals are not met, deficiencies in bid guarantees submitted by offerors determined to be in the competitive range shall be addressed during discussions and the offeror shall be given an opportunity to correct the deficiency.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1797e38" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Noncompliance with a solicitation requirement for a bid guarantee shall be waived in the following circumstances unless the contracting officer determines in writing that acceptance of the bid would be detrimental to the Government’s interest when-</p>
					          <ol id="d1783e44" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Only one offer is received. In this case, the contracting officer may require the furnishing of the bid guarantee before award;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e57" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The amount of the bid guarantee submitted is less than required, but is equal to or greater than the difference between the offer price and the next higher acceptable offer;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e66" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The amount of the bid guarantee submitted, although less than that required by the solicitation for the maximum quantity offered, is sufficient for a quantity for which the offeror is otherwise eligible for award. Any award to the offeror shall not exceed the quantity covered by the bid guarantee;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e75" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The bid guarantee is received late, and late receipt is waived under <xref href="FAR-i1110200.dita#i1110200"
                              base="i1110200"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">14.304</xref>;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e87" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A bid guarantee becomes inadequate as a result of the correction of a mistake under <xref href="FAR-i1109856.dita#i1109856"
                              base="i1109856"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">14.407</xref>(but only if the bidder will increase the bid guarantee to the level required for the corrected bid);</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e100" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                An otherwise acceptable bid bond was submitted with a signed offer, but the bid bond was not signed by the offeror;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e109" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                An otherwise acceptable bid bond is erroneously dated or bears no date at all; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1797e118" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A bid bond does not list the United States as obligee, but correctly identifies the offeror, the solicitation number, and the name and location of the project involved, so long as it is acceptable in all other respects.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
