<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1057352"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.219-4</ph> Notice of Price Evaluation Preference for HUBZone Small Business Concerns.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3258e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1099698.dita#i1099698"
                     base="i1099698"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">19.1309</xref>(b)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Notice of Price Evaluation preference for HUBZone Small Business Concerns (Oct 2014)</p>
			      <ol id="d3240e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3258e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>. See 13 CFR 125.6(e) for definitions of terms used in paragraph (d).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3258e41" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Evaluation preference.</p>
					          <ol id="d3240e47" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Offers will be evaluated by adding a factor of 10 percent to the price of all offers, except-</p>
							              <ol id="d3240e57" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e61" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Offers from HUBZone small business concerns that have not waived the evaluation preference; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e70" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Otherwise successful offers from small business concerns.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e81" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The factor of 10 percent shall be applied on a line item basis or to any group of items on which award may be made. Other evaluation factors described in the solicitation shall be applied before application of the factor.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e90" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                When the two highest rated offerors are a HUBZone small business concern and a large business, and the evaluated offer of the HUBZone small business concern is equal to the evaluated offer of the large business after considering the price evaluation preference, award will be made to the HUBZone small business concern.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3258e101" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Waiver of evaluation preference</i>. A HUBZone small business concern may elect to waive the evaluation preference, in which case the factor will be added to its offer for evaluation purposes. The agreements in paragraphs(d) and (e) of this clause do not apply if the offeror has waived the evaluation preference.</p>
					          <p id="d3258e110" class="- topic/p ">
						            <term outputclass="ZapfDingbats" class="- topic/term "></term> Offeror elects to waive the evaluation preference.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3258e119" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Agreement</i>. A HUBZone small business concern agrees that in the performance of the contract, in the case of a contract for-</p>
					          <ol id="d3240e144" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e132" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Services (except construction), at least 50 percent of the cost of personnel for contract performance will be spent for employees of the concern or employees of other HUBZone small business concerns;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e141" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Supplies (other than procurement from a nonmanufacturer of such supplies), at least 50 percent of the cost of manufacturing, excluding the cost of materials, will be performed by the concern or other HUBZone small business concerns;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e150" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                General construction.</p>
							              <ol id="d3240e172" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e160" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    At least 15 percent of the cost of contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be spent on the prime contractor’s employees;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e169" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    At least 50 percent of the cost of the contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be spent on the prime contractor’s employees or on a combination of the prime contractor’s employees and employees of HUBZone small business concern subcontractors;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e178" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    No more than 50 percent of the cost of contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be subcontracted to concerns that are not HUBZone small business concerns; or</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e189" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Construction by special trade contractors.</p>
							              <ol id="d3240e211" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e199" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    At least 25 percent of the cost of contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be spent on the prime contractor’s employees;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e208" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    At least 50 percent of the cost of the contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be spent on the prime contractor’s employees or on a combination of the prime contractor’s employees and employees of HUBZone small business concern subcontractors;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3258e217" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    No more than 50 percent of the cost of contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be subcontracted to concerns that are not HUBZone small business concerns.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3258e230" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            A HUBZone joint venture agrees that the aggregate of the HUBZone small business concerns to the joint venture, not each concern separately, will perform the applicable percentage of work requirements.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3258e240" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
					          </p>
					          <ol id="d3240e261" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e250" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                When the total value of the contract exceeds $25,000, a HUBZone small business concern nonmanufacturer agrees to furnish in performing this contract only end items manufactured or produced by HUBZone small business concern manufacturers.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e259" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                When the total value of the contract is equal to or less than $25,000, a HUBZone small business concern nonmanufacturer may provide end items manufactured by other than a HUBZone small business concern manufacturer provided the end items are produced or manufactured in the United States.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3258e268" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Paragraphs (f)(1) and (f)(2) of this section do not apply in connection with construction or service contracts.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3258e279" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Notice</i>. The HUBZone small business offeror acknowledges that a prospective HUBZone awardee must be a HUBZone small business concern at the time of award of this contract. The HUBZone offeror shall provide the Contracting Officer a copy of the notice required by 13 CFR 126.501 if material changes occur before contract award that could affect its HUBZone eligibility. If the apparently successful HUBZone offeror is not a HUBZone small business concern at the time of award of this contract, the Contracting Officer will proceed to award to the next otherwise successful HUBZone small business concern or other offeror.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
			      <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section ">
				<?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
				        <p id="d3258e297" class="- topic/p ">
					          <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate I (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Jan</i>2011)</i>. As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
						            <xref href="FAR-i1099698.dita#i1099698"
                        base="i1099698"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.1309</xref>(b)(1)</ph>, substitute the following paragraphs (d)(3) and (d)(4) for paragraphs (d)(3) and (d)(4) of the basic clause:</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p ">(3) General construction, at least 15 percent of the cost of the contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be spent on the concern’s employees; or</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p ">(4) Construction by special trade contractors, at least 25 percent of the cost of the contract performance to be incurred for personnel will be spent on the concern’s employees.</p>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
			      </section>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
