<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1126427"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">1.602-2</ph> Responsibilities.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p class="- topic/p ">Contracting officers are responsible for ensuring performance of all necessary actions for effective contracting, ensuring compliance with the terms of the contract, and safeguarding the interests of the United States in its contractual relationships. In order to perform these responsibilities, contracting officers should be allowed wide latitude to exercise business judgment. Contracting officers shall-</p>
			      <ol id="d53e16" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d55e20" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Ensure that the requirements of <xref href="FAR-i1126420.dita#i1126420"
                        base="i1126420"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">1.602-1</xref>(b) have been met, and that sufficient funds are available for obligation;</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d55e32" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Ensure that contractors receive impartial, fair, and equitable treatment;</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d55e41" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Request and consider the advice of specialists in audit, law, engineering, information security, transportation, and other fields, as appropriate; and</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d55e50" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Designate and authorize, in writing and in accordance with agency procedures, a contracting officer’s representative (COR) on all contracts and orders other than those that are firm-fixed price, and for firm-fixed-price contracts and orders as appropriate, unless the contracting officer retains and executes the COR duties. See <xref href="FAR-i1118917.dita#i1118917"
                        base="i1118917"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">7.104</xref>(e). <term class="- topic/term "></term>COR-</p>
					          <ol id="d53e62" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d55e66" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall be a Government employee, unless otherwise authorized in agency regulations;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d55e75" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall be certified and maintain certification in accordance with the current Office of Management and Budget memorandum on the Federal Acquisition Certification for Contracting Officer Representatives (FAC-COR) guidance, or for DoD, in accordance with the current applicable DoD policy guidance;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d55e84" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall be qualified by training and experience commensurate with the responsibilities to be delegated in accordance with agency procedures;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d55e93" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                May not be delegated responsibility to perform functions that have been delegated under <xref href="FAR-i1075965.dita#i1075965"
                              base="i1075965"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">42.202</xref> to a contract administration office, but may be assigned some duties at <xref href="FAR-i1075705.dita#i1075705"
                              base="i1075705"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">42.302</xref> by the contracting officer;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d55e108" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Has no authority to make any commitments or changes that affect price, quality, quantity, delivery, or other terms and conditions of the contract nor in any way direct the contractor or its subcontractors to operate in conflict with the contract terms and conditions;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d55e118" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall be nominated either by the requiring activity or in accordance with agency procedures; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d55e127" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall be designated in writing, with copies furnished to the contractor and the contract administration office-</p>
							              <ol id="d53e133" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d55e137" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Specifying the extent of the COR’s authority to act on behalf of the contracting officer;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d55e146" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Identifying the limitations on the COR’s authority;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d55e155" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Specifying the period covered by the designation;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d55e164" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Stating the authority is not redelegable; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d55e173" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Stating that the COR may be personally liable for unauthorized acts.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
