<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1059741"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.215-23</ph> Limitations on Pass-Through Charges.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3210e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1106593.dita#i1106593"
                     base="i1106593"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">15.408</xref>(n)(2)</ph>, use the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Limitations on Pass-Through Charges (Oct 2009)</p>
			      <ol id="d3192e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3210e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>. As used in this clause-</p>
					          <p id="d3210e38" class="- topic/p ">“Added value” means that the Contractor performs subcontract management functions that the Contracting Officer determines are a benefit to the Government (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, processing orders of parts or services, maintaining inventory, reducing delivery lead times, managing multiple sources for contract requirements, coordinating deliveries, performing quality assurance functions).</p>
					          <p id="d3210e44" class="- topic/p ">“Excessive pass-through charge”, with respect to a Contractor or subcontractor that adds no or negligible value to a contract or subcontract, means a charge to the Government by the Contractor or subcontractor that is for indirect costs or profit/fee on work performed by a subcontractor (other than charges for the costs of managing subcontracts and any applicable indirect costs and associated profit/fee based on such costs).</p>
					          <p id="d3210e47" class="- topic/p ">“No or negligible value” means the Contractor or subcontractor cannot demonstrate to the Contracting Officer that its effort added value to the contract or subcontract in accomplishing the work performed under the contract (including task or delivery orders).</p>
					          <p id="d3210e50" class="- topic/p ">“Subcontract” means any contract, as defined in FAR <xref href="FAR-i1125359.dita#i1125359"
                        base="i1125359"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">2.101</xref>, entered into by a subcontractor to furnish supplies or services for performance of the contract or a subcontract. It includes but is not limited to purchase orders, and changes and modifications to purchase orders.</p>
					          <p id="d3210e57" class="- topic/p ">“Subcontractor”, as defined in FAR <xref href="FAR-i1073689.dita#i1073689"
                        base="i1073689"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">44.101</xref>, means any supplier, distributor, vendor, or firm that furnishes supplies or services to or for a prime Contractor or another subcontractor.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3210e66" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General</i>. The Government will not pay excessive pass-through charges. The Contracting Officer shall determine if excessive pass-through charges exist.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3210e78" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Reporting</i>. Required reporting of performance of work by the Contractor or a subcontractor. The Contractor shall notify the Contracting Officer in writing if-</p>
					          <ol id="d3192e90" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3210e91" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor changes the amount of subcontract effort after award such that it exceeds 70 percent of the total cost of work to be performed under the contract, task order, or delivery order. The notification shall identify the revised cost of the subcontract effort and shall include verification that the Contractor will provide added value; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3210e100" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Any subcontractor changes the amount of lower-tier subcontractor effort after award such that it exceeds 70 percent of the total cost of the work to be performed under its subcontract. The notification shall identify the revised cost of the subcontract effort and shall include verification that the subcontractor will provide added value as related to the work to be performed by the lower-tier subcontractor(s).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3210e111" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Recovery of excessive pass-through charges</i>. If the Contracting Officer determines that excessive pass-through charges exist;</p>
					          <ol id="d3192e123" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3210e124" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                For other than fixed-price contracts, the excessive pass-through charges are unallowable in accordance with the provisions in FAR subpart <xref href="FAR-i1084539.dita#i1084539"
                              base="i1084539"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">31.2</xref>; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3210e136" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                For applicable DoD fixed-price contracts, as identified in <xref href="FAR-i1106593.dita#i1106593"
                              base="i1106593"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.408</xref>(n)(2)(i)(B), the Government shall be entitled to a price reduction for the amount of excessive pass-through charges included in the contract price.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3210e150" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Access to records</i>.</p>
					          <ol id="d3192e162" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3210e163" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contracting Officer, or authorized representative, shall have the right to examine and audit all the Contractor’s records (as defined at FAR <xref href="FAR-i1059150.dita#i1059150"
                              base="i1059150"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.215-2</xref>(a)) necessary to determine whether the Contractor proposed, billed, or claimed excessive pass-through charges.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3210e175" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                For those subcontracts to which paragraph (f) of this clause applies, the Contracting Officer, or authorized representative, shall have the right to examine and audit all the subcontractor’s records (as defined at FAR <xref href="FAR-i1059150.dita#i1059150"
                              base="i1059150"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.215-2</xref>(a)) necessary to determine whether the subcontractor proposed, billed, or claimed excessive pass-through charges.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3210e190" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Flowdown</i>. The Contractor shall insert the substance of this clause, including this paragraph (f), in all cost-reimbursement subcontracts under this contract that exceed the simplified acquisition threshold, except if the contract is with DoD, then insert in all cost-reimbursement subcontracts and fixed-price subcontracts, except those identified in <xref href="FAR-i1106593.dita#i1106593"
                        base="i1106593"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">15.408</xref>(n)(2)(i)(B)(<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">2</i>), that exceed the threshold for obtaining cost or pricing data in accordance with FAR <xref href="FAR-i1106066.dita#i1106066"
                        base="i1106066"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">15.403-4</xref>.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
			      <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section ">
				<?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
				        <p id="d3210e217" class="- topic/p ">
					          <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate I (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Oct</i>2009)</i>. As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
						            <xref href="FAR-i1106593.dita#i1106593"
                        base="i1106593"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">15.408</xref>
					          </ph>(n)(2)(iii), substitute the following paragraph (b) for paragraph (b) of the basic clause:</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(b) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General</i>. The Government will not pay excessive pass-through charges. The Contracting Officer has determined that there will be no excessive pass-through charges, provided the Contractor performs the disclosed value-added functions.</p>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
			      </section>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
