<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="id1617MD0H03Y"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">34.005-2</ph> Mission-oriented solicitation.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2220e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2234e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Before issuing the solicitation, whenever practicable and consistent with agency procedures, the contracting officer should take the actions outlined in paragraphs(a)(1) and (2):</p>
					          <ol id="d2220e23" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e27" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Advance notification of the acquisition should be given the widest practicable dissemination, including publicizing through the Governmentwide point of entry (see <xref href="FAR-i1120661.dita#i1120661"
                              base="i1120661"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  5.2</xref>) and should be sent to as wide a selection of potential sources as practicable, including smaller and newer firms, Government laboratories, federally funded research and development centers, educational institutions and other not-for-profit organizations, and, if it would be beneficial and is not prohibited, foreign sources.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If appropriate, hold a presolicitation conference (see <xref href="FAR-i1108766.dita#i1108766"
                              base="i1108766"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.201</xref>) and/or send copies of the proposed solicitation to all prospective offerors for their comments. After evaluation of these comments, the solicitation should be revised, if appropriate.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2234e53" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall send the final solicitation to all prospective offerors. It shall-</p>
					          <ol id="d2220e59" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Describe the nature of the need in terms of mission capabilities required, without reference to any specific systems to satisfy the need;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e72" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Indicate, and explain when appropriate, the schedule, capability, and cost objectives and any known constraints in the acquisition;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e81" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Provide, or indicate how access can be obtained to, all Government data related to the acquisition;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e90" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Include selection requirements consistent with the acquisition strategy; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e99" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Clearly state that each offeror is free to propose its own technical approach, main design features, subsystems, and alternatives to schedule, cost, and capability goals.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2234e109" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Require the use of an Earned Value Management System that complies with the guidelines of Electronic Industries Alliance Standard 748 (EIA-748) (current version at time of solicitation). See <xref href="FAR-i1079908.dita#i1079908"
                              base="i1079908"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">34.201</xref> for earned value management systems and reporting requirements.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2234e123" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            To the extent practicable, the solicitation shall not reference or mandate Government specifications or standards, unless the agency is mandating a subsystem or other component as approved under agency procedure.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
