<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="id1617MD00ME2"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">7.106</ph> Additional requirements
for major systems.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d405e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d412e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   In planning for the solicitation
of a major system (see <xref href="FAR-i1080083.dita#i1080083"
                        base="i1080083"
                        outputclass="fm:Part"
                        class="- topic/xref ">part  34</xref>)
development contract, planners shall consider requiring offerors
to include, in their offers, proposals to incorporate in the design
of a major system-</p>
               <ol id="d405e26" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d412e30" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Items which are currently available
within the supply system of the agency responsible for the major
system, available elsewhere in the national supply system, or commercially
available from more than one source; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d412e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Items which
the Government will be able to acquire competitively in the future
if they are likely to be needed in substantial quantities during
the system’s service life.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d412e50" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   In planning
for the solicitation of a major system (see <xref href="FAR-i1080083.dita#i1080083"
                        base="i1080083"
                        outputclass="fm:Part"
                        class="- topic/xref ">part  34</xref>) production
contract, planners shall consider requiring offerors to include,
in their offers, proposals identifying opportunities to assure that
the Government will be able to obtain, on a competitive basis, items
acquired in connection with the system that are likely to be acquired
in substantial quantities during the service life of the system.
Proposals submitted in response to such requirements may include
the following:</p>
               <ol id="d405e59" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d412e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Proposals to provide the Government
the right to use technical data to be provided under the contract
for competitive future acquisitions, together with the cost to the
Government, if any, of acquiring such technical data and the right to
use such data.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d412e72" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Proposals
for the qualification or development of multiple sources of supply
for competitive future acquisitions.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d412e83" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   In determining
whether to apply <ph class="- topic/ph ">paragraphs (a) and
(b) of this section</ph>, planners shall consider the purposes for
which the system is being acquired and the technology necessary
to meet the system’s required capabilities. If such proposals are
required, the contracting officer shall consider them in evaluating
competing offers. In noncompetitive awards, the factors in <ph class="- topic/ph ">paragraphs (a) and (b) of this
section</ph>, may be considered by the contracting officer as objectives
in negotiating the contract.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
