<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="id1617MD0I05K"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">35.017-4</ph> Reviewing FFRDC’s.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2257e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2271e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The sponsor, prior to extending the contract or agreement with an FFRDC, shall conduct a comprehensive review of the use and need for the FFRDC. The review will be coordinated with any co-sponsors and may be performed in conjunction with the budget process. If the sponsor determines that its sponsorship is no longer appropriate, it shall apprise other agencies which use the FFRDC of the determination and afford them an opportunity to assume sponsorship.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2271e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Approval to continue or terminate the sponsorship shall rest with the head of the sponsoring agency. This determination shall be based upon the results of the review conducted in accordance with paragraph (c) of this subsection.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2271e35" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            An FFRDC review should include the following:</p>
					          <ol id="d2257e41" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2271e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                An examination of the sponsor’s special technical needs and mission requirements that are performed by the FFRDC to determine if and at what level they continue to exist.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2271e54" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Consideration of alternative sources to meet the sponsor’s needs.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2271e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                An assessment of the efficiency and effectiveness of the FFRDC in meeting the sponsor’s needs, including the FFRDC’s ability to maintain its objectivity, independence, quick response capability, currency in its field(s) of expertise, and familiarity with the needs of its sponsor.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2271e72" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                An assessment of the adequacy of the FFRDC management in ensuring a cost-effective operation.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2271e81" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A determination that the criteria for establishing the FFRDC continue to be satisfied and that the sponsoring agreement is in compliance with <xref href="FAR-i1079704.dita#i1079704"
                              base="i1079704"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">35.017-1</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
