<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?Fm Validation Off?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i1055793"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.222-26</ph> Equal Opportunity.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p id="d3313e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="FAR-i1097344.dita#i1097344"
                     base="i1097344"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">22.810</xref>(e)</ph>, insert
the following clause:</p>
         <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Equal Opportunity (Sept 2016)</p>
         <ol id="d3295e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d3313e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definition</i>.
As used in this clause.</p>
               <p id="d3313e38" class="- topic/p ">“Compensation” means
any payments made to, or on behalf of, an employee or offered to
an applicant as remuneration for employment, including but not limited
to salary, wages, overtime pay, shift differentials, bonuses, commissions,
vacation and holiday pay, allowances, insurance and other benefits,
stock options and awards, profit sharing, and retirement.</p>
               <p id="d3313e41" class="- topic/p ">“Compensation information” means the amount
and type of compensation provided to employees or offered to applicants, including,
but not limited to, the desire of the Contractor to attract and
retain a particular employee for the value the employee is perceived
to add to the Contractor's profit or productivity; the availability
of employees with like skills in the marketplace; market research
about the worth of similar jobs in the relevant marketplace; job
analysis, descriptions, and evaluations; salary and pay structures;
salary surveys; labor union agreements; and Contractor decisions,
statements and policies related to setting or altering employee
compensation.</p>
               <p id="d3313e44" class="- topic/p ">“Essential job functions” means
the fundamental job duties of the employment position an individual
holds. A job function may be considered essential if-</p>
               <ol id="d3295e53" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> The
access to compensation information is necessary in order to perform
that function or another routinely assigned business task; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e60" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The function
or duties of the position include protecting and maintaining the
privacy of employee personnel records, including compensation information.</p>
                     <p id="d3313e66" class="- topic/p ">“Gender identity” has the meaning given by the
Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs,
and is found at <xref href="https://www.dol.gov/ofccp/LGBT/LGBT_FAQs.html"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">http://www.dol.gov/ofccp/LGBT/LGBT_FAQs.html</xref>.</p>
                     <p id="d3313e72" class="- topic/p ">“Sexual orientation” has the meaning given by
the Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contract Compliance
Programs, and is found at <xref href="https://www.dol.gov/ofccp/LGBT/LGBT_FAQs.html"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">http://www.dol.gov/ofccp/LGBT/LGBT_FAQs.html</xref>.</p>
                     <p id="d3313e78" class="- topic/p ">“United States,” means the 50 States, the District
of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa,
Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and Wake Island.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d3313e86" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d3295e98" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e96" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> If,
during any 12-month period (including the 12 months preceding the
award of this contract), the Contractor has been or is awarded nonexempt
Federal contracts and/or subcontracts that have an aggregate value
in excess of $10,000, the Contractor shall comply with this clause,
except for work performed outside the United States by employees
who were not recruited within the United States. Upon request, the
Contractor shall provide information necessary to determine the
applicability of this clause.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e105" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>  If the
Contractor is a religious corporation, association, educational
institution, or society, the requirements of this clause do not
apply with respect to the employment of individuals of a particular
religion to perform work connected with the carrying on of the Contractor’s
activities (41 CFR 60-1.5).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d3313e116" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d3295e128" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e126" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> The
Contractor shall not discriminate against any employee or applicant
for employment because of race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation,
gender identity, or national origin. However, it shall not be a
violation of this clause for the Contractor to extend a publicly
announced preference in employment to Indians living on or near
an Indian reservation, in connection with employment opportunities
on or near an Indian reservation, as permitted by 41 CFR 60-1.5.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e135" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The Contractor
shall take affirmative action to ensure that applicants are employed,
and that employees are treated during employment, without regard
to their race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender
identity, or national origin. This shall include, but not be limited
to-</p>
                     <ol id="d3295e147" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e145" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Employment;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e154" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Upgrading;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e163" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph> Demotion;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e172" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph> Transfer;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e181" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph> Recruitment
or recruitment advertising;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e191" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph> Layoff
or termination;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e200" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vii)</ph> Rates
of pay or other forms of compensation; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e209" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(viii)</ph> Selection
for training, including apprenticeship.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e220" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> The Contractor
shall post in conspicuous places available to employees and applicants
for employment the notices to be provided by the Contracting Officer
that explain this clause.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e229" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> The Contractor
shall, in all solicitations or advertisements for employees placed
by or on behalf of the Contractor, state that all qualified applicants
will receive consideration for employment without regard to race,
color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, or national
origin.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e238" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                     </p>
                     <ol id="d3295e250" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e248" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> The
Contractor shall not discharge or in any other manner discriminate
against any employee or applicant for employment because such employee
or applicant has inquired about, discussed, or disclosed the compensation of
the employee or applicant or another employee or applicant. This
prohibition against discrimination does not apply to instances in
which an employee who has access to the compensation information
of other employees or applicants as a part of such employee's essential
job functions discloses the compensation of such other employees or
applicants to individuals who do not otherwise have access to such
information, unless such disclosure is in response to a formal complaint
or charge, in furtherance of an investigation, proceeding, hearing,
or action, including an investigation conducted by the employer,
or is consistent with the Contractor's legal duty to furnish information.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d3313e257" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> The Contractor
shall disseminate the prohibition on discrimination in paragraph
(c)(5)(i) of this clause, using language prescribed by the Director
of the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs (OFCCP), to
employees and applicants by-</p>
                           <ol id="d3295e269" class="- topic/ol ">
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p id="d3313e267" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph> Incorporation
into existing employee manuals or handbooks; and</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p id="d3313e276" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph> Electronic
posting or by posting a copy of the provision in conspicuous places
available to employees and applicants for employment.</p>
                              </li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e290" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph> The Contractor
shall send, to each labor union or representative of workers with
which it has a collective bargaining agreement or other contract
or understanding, the notice to be provided by the Contracting Officer
advising the labor union or workers’ representative of the Contractor’s
commitments under this clause, and post copies of the notice in conspicuous
places available to employees and applicants for employment.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e299" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph> The Contractor
shall comply with Executive Order11246, as amended, and the rules,
regulations, and orders of the Secretary of Labor.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e308" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph> The Contractor
shall furnish to the contracting agency all information required
by Executive Order11246, as amended, and by the rules, regulations,
and orders of the Secretary of Labor. The Contractor shall also
file Standard Form100 (EEO-1), or any successor form, as prescribed
in 41 CFR Part60-1. Unless the Contractor has filed within the 12
months preceding the date of contract award, the Contractor shall,
within 30 days after contract award, apply to either the regional
Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs (OFCCP) or the local
office of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission for the necessary
forms.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e317" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(9)</ph> The Contractor
shall permit access to its premises, during normal business hours,
by the contracting agency or the OFCCP for the purpose of conducting
on-site compliance evaluations and complaint investigations. The
Contractor shall permit the Government to inspect and copy any books,
accounts, records (including computerized records), and other material
that may be relevant to the matter under investigation and pertinent
to compliance with Executive Order11246, as amended, and rules and
regulations that implement the Executive Order.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e326" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(10)</ph> If the
OFCCP determines that the Contractor is not in compliance with this
clause or any rule, regulation, or order of the Secretary of Labor,
this contract may be canceled, terminated, or suspended in whole
or in part and the Contractor may be declared ineligible for further
Government contracts, under the procedures authorized in Executive Order11246,
as amended. In addition, sanctions may be imposed and remedies invoked
against the Contractor as provided in Executive Order11246, as amended;
in the rules, regulations, and orders of the Secretary of Labor;
or as otherwise provided by law.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e335" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(11)</ph> The Contractor
shall include the terms and conditions of this clause in every subcontract
or purchase order that is not exempted by the rules, regulations,
or orders of the Secretary of Labor issued under Executive Order11246,
as amended, so that these terms and conditions will be binding upon
each subcontractor or vendor.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d3313e345" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(12)</ph> The Contractor
shall take such action with respect to any subcontract or purchase
order as the Director of OFCCP may direct as a means of enforcing
these terms and conditions, including sanctions for noncompliance,
provided, that if the Contractor becomes involved in, or is threatened
with, litigation with a subcontractor or vendor as a result of any direction,
the Contractor may request the United States to enter into the litigation
to protect the interests of the United States.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d3313e356" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> Notwithstanding
any other clause in this contract, disputes relative to this clause
will be governed by the procedures in 41 CFR 60-1.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
         <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section "><?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?> 
            <p id="d3313e371" class="- topic/p ">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate
I (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Feb</i>1999)</i>. As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
                  <xref href="FAR-i1097344.dita#i1097344"
                        base="i1097344"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.810</xref>
               </ph>(e), add the
following as a preamble to the clause:</p>
            <p id="d3313e385" class="- topic/p ">
               <term class="- topic/term ">Notice</term>:
The following terms of this clause are waived for this contract:
__________ [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer shall list terms</i>].</p> 
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
         </section>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>