<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1054813"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.225-24</ph> Notice of Required Use of American Iron, Steel, and Manufactured Goods-Buy American Statute-Construction Materials Under Trade Agreements.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3401e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1090904.dita#i1090904"
                     base="i1090904"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">25.1102</xref>(e)</ph>, insert the following provision:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Notice of Required Use of American Iron, Steel, and Manufactured Goods-Buy American Statute-Construction Materials Under Trade Agreements (May 2014)</p>
			      <ol id="d3383e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3401e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>. “Construction material,” “domestic construction material,” “foreign construction material,” “manufactured construction material,” “Recovery Act designated country construction material,” “steel,” and “unmanufactured construction material,” as used in this provision, are defined in the clause of this solicitation entitled “Required Use of Iron, Steel, and Manufactured Goods-Buy American statute-Construction Materials Under Trade Agreements” (Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                        base="i1054633"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref>).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3401e44" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Requests for determination of inapplicability</i>. An offeror requesting a determination regarding the inapplicability of section 1605 of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (Pub. L. 111-5) (Recovery Act) or the Buy American statute should submit the request to the Contracting Officer in time to allow a determination before submission of offers. The offeror shall include the information and applicable supporting data required by paragraphs (c) and (d) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                        base="i1054633"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref> in the request. If an offeror has not requested a determination regarding the inapplicability of section 1605 of the Recovery Act or the Buy American statute before submitting its offer, or has not received a response to a previous request, the offeror shall include the information and supporting data in the offer.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3401e59" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Evaluation of offers.</p>
					          <ol id="d3383e65" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3401e69" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the Government determines that an exception based on unreasonable cost of domestic construction material applies in accordance with FAR 25.604, the Government will evaluate an offer requesting exception to the requirements of section 1605 of the Recovery Act or the Buy American statute by adding to the offered price of the contract-</p>
							              <ol id="d3383e75" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3401e79" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    25 percent of the offered price of the contract, if foreign manufactured construction material is included in the offer based on an exception for the unreasonable cost of comparable manufactured domestic construction material; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3401e88" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    6 percent of the cost of foreign unmanufactured construction material included in the offer based on an exception for the unreasonable cost of comparable domestic unmanufactured construction material.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3401e99" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the solicitation specifies award on the basis of factors in addition to cost or price, the Contracting Officer will apply the evaluation factors as specified in paragraph (c)(1) of this provision and use the evaluated cost or price in determining the offer that represents the best value to the Government.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3401e108" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Unless paragraph (c)(2) of this provision applies, if two or more offers are equal in price, the Contracting Officer will give preference to an offer that does not include foreign construction material excepted at the request of the offeror on the basis of unreasonable cost.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3401e119" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Alternate offers.</p>
					          <ol id="d3383e125" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3401e129" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                When an offer includes foreign construction material, other than Recovery Act designated country construction material, that is not listed by the Government in this solicitation in paragraph (b)(3) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                              base="i1054633"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref>, the offeror also may submit an alternate offer based on use of equivalent domestic or Recovery Act designated country construction material.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3401e141" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If an alternate offer is submitted, the offeror shall submit a separate Standard Form 1442 for the alternate offer and a separate cost comparison table prepared in accordance with paragraphs (c) and (d) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                              base="i1054633"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref> for the offer that is based on the use of any foreign construction material for which the Government has not yet determined an exception applies.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3401e153" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the Government determines that a particular exception requested in accordance with paragraph (c) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                              base="i1054633"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref> does not apply, the Government will evaluate only those offers based on use of the equivalent domestic or Recovery Act designated country construction material, and the offeror shall be required to furnish such domestic or Recovery Act designated country construction material. An offer based on use of the foreign construction material for which an exception was requested-</p>
							              <ol id="d3383e162" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3401e166" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Will be rejected as nonresponsive if this acquisition is conducted by sealed bidding; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3401e175" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    May be accepted if revised during negotiations.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofprovision">(End of Provision)</p>
			      <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section ">
				<?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
				        <p id="d3401e194" class="- topic/p ">
					          <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate I (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">May</i>2014)</i>. As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
						            <xref href="FAR-i1090904.dita#i1090904"
                        base="i1090904"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">25.1102</xref>
					          </ph>(e), substitute the following paragraph (b) for paragraph (b) of the basic provision:</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p ">(b) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Requests for determination of inapplicability</i>. An offeror requesting a determination regarding the inapplicability of section 1605 of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (Pub. L. 111-5) (Recovery Act) or the Buy American statute shall submit the request with its offer, including the information and applicable supporting data required by paragraphs (c) and (d) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                     base="i1054633"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref>.</p>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
				        <p class="- topic/p ">
					          <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate II (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Mar</i>2009)</i>. As prescribed in <xref href="FAR-i1090904.dita#i1090904"
                     base="i1090904"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">25.1102</xref>(e), add the definition of “Bahrainian, Mexican, or Omani construction material” to paragraph (a) and substitute the following paragraph (d) for paragraph (d) of the basic provision:</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List1">(d) <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate offers</i>. (1) When an offer includes foreign construction material, except foreign construction material from a Recovery Act designated country other than Bahrain, Mexico, or Oman that is not listed by the Government in this solicitation in paragraph (b)(3) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                     base="i1054633"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref>, the offeror also may submit an alternate offer based on use of equivalent domestic or Recovery Act designated country construction material other than Bahrainian, Mexican, or Omani construction material.</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(2) If an alternate offer is submitted, the offeror shall submit a separate Standard Form 1442 for the alternate offer and a separate cost comparison table prepared in accordance with paragraphs (c) and (d) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                     base="i1054633"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref> for the offer that is based on the use of any foreign construction material for which the Government has not yet determined an exception applies.</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List2">(3) If the Government determines that a particular exception requested in accordance with paragraph (c) of FAR clause <xref href="FAR-i1054633.dita#i1054633"
                     base="i1054633"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">52.225-23</xref> does not apply, the Government will evaluate only those offers based on use of the equivalent domestic or Recovery Act designated country construction material other than Bahrainian, Mexican, or Omani construction material. An offer based on use of the foreign construction material for which an exception was requested-</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3">(i) Will be rejected as nonresponsive if this acquisition is conducted by sealed bidding; or</p>
				        <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="List3">(ii) May be accepted if revised during negotiations.</p>
				        <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
			      </section>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
