<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i1101517"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">19.201</ph> General policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1130e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1153e10" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  It is the policy of the Government to provide maximum practicable opportunities in its acquisitions to small business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled veteran-owned small business, HUBZone small business, small disadvantaged business, and women-owned small business concerns. Such concerns must also have the maximum practicable opportunity to participate as subcontractors in the contracts awarded by any executive agency, consistent with efficient contract performance. The Small Business Administration (SBA) counsels and assists small business concerns and assists contracting personnel to ensure that a fair proportion of contracts for supplies and services is placed with small business.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1153e15" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  Heads of contracting activities are responsible for effectively implementing the small business programs within their activities, including achieving program goals. They are to ensure that contracting and technical personnel maintain knowledge of small business program requirements and take all reasonable action to increase participation in their activities’ contracting processes by these businesses.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1153e20" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  The Small Business Act requires each agency with contracting authority to establish an Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization (see section 15(k) of the Small Business Act). For the Department of Defense, in accordance with section 904 of <xref href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/PLAW-109publ163/html/PLAW-109publ163.htm"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">Public Law 109-163</xref> (<xref href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/USCODE-2018-title10/html/USCODE-2018-title10-subtitleA-partI-chap4-sec144.htm"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C. 144</xref> note), the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization has been redesignated as the Office of Small Business Programs. Management of the office is the responsibility of an officer or employee of the agency who, in carrying out the purposes of the Act—</p>
               <ol id="d1130e44" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e37" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        Is known as the Director of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization, or for the Department of Defense, the Director of the Office of Small Business Programs;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e50" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        Has supervisory authority over agency personnel to the extent that their functions and duties relate to sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small Business Act;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e55" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        Is responsible to and reports directly to the agency head or the deputy to the agency head (except that for the Department of Defense, the Director of the Office of Small Business Programs reports to the Secretary or the Secretary’s designee);
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        Cooperates and consults on a regular basis with the SBA in carrying out the agency's functions and duties in sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small Business Act;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e68" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        Works with the SBA procurement center representative (PCR) (or, if a PCR is not assigned, see <xref href="FAR-i1101041.dita#i1101041"
                              base="i1101041"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.402</xref>(a)) to identify proposed solicitations that involve bundling and work with the agency acquisition officials and SBA to revise the acquisition strategies for such proposed solicitations to increase the probability of participation by small businesses;
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e79" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        Conducts annual reviews to assess the—</p>
                     <ol id="d1130e218" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1153e85" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              Extent to which small businesses are receiving a fair share of Federal procurements, including contract opportunities under the programs administered under the Small Business Act;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1153e90" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              Adequacy of consolidated or bundled contract documentation and justifications; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1153e95" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              Actions taken to mitigate the effects of necessary and justified consolidation or bundling on small businesses.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e100" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        Provides a copy of the assessment made under paragraph (c)(11) of this section to the Agency Head and SBA Administrator;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e105" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        Provides to the chief acquisition officer and senior procurement executive advice and comments on acquisition strategies, market research, and justifications related to consolidation of contract requirements;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e110" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(9)</ph>
                        When notified by a small business concern prior to the award of a contract that the small business concern believes that a solicitation, request for proposal, or request for quotation unduly restricts the ability of the small business concern to compete for the award–</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1153e116" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              Submits the notification by the small business concern to the contracting officer and, if necessary, recommends ways in which the solicitation, request for proposal, or request for quotation may be altered to increase the opportunity for competition; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1153e121" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              Informs the advocate for competition of such agency (as established under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C 1705</xref> or <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C. 2318</xref>) of such notification;</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e132" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(10)</ph>
                        Ensures agency purchases using the Governmentwide purchase card that are greater than the micro-purchase threshold and less than the simplified acquisition threshold were made in compliance with the Small Business Act and were properly recorded in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1122770.dita#i1122770"
                              base="i1122770"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  4.6</xref> in the Federal Procurement Data System;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e140" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(11)</ph>
                        Assists small business contractors and subcontractors in finding resources for education and training on compliance with contracting regulations;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e146" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(12)</ph>
                        Reviews all subcontracting plans required by <xref href="FAR-i1100224.dita#i1100224"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.702</xref>(a) to ensure the plan provides maximum practicable opportunity for small business concerns to participate in the performance of the contract; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e154" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(13)</ph>
                        Performs other duties listed at <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1153e162" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  Small business specialists shall be appointed and act in accordance with agency regulations.
               </p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e171" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        The contracting activity shall coordinate with the small business specialist as early in the acquisition planning process as practicable, but no later than 30 days before the issuance of a solicitation, or prior to placing an order without a solicitation when the acquisition meets the dollar thresholds set forth at <xref href="FAR-CEHJGJDGD2.dita#CEHJGJDGD2"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.107-4</xref>(a)(1). See also <xref href="FAR-i1118917.dita#i1118917"
                              base="i1118917"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.104</xref>(d).
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e183" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        The small business specialist shall notify the agency's Director of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization, and for the Department of Defense, the Director of the Office of Small Business Programs, when the criteria relating to substantial bundling at <xref href="FAR-CEHJGJDGD2.dita#CEHJGJDGD2"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.107-4</xref>(a)(1) are met.
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1153e192" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        The small business specialist shall coordinate with the contracting activity and the SBA PCR on all determinations and findings required by <xref href="FAR-i1119141.dita#i1119141"
                              base="i1119141"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.107</xref> for consolidation or bundling of contract requirements.
                     </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
