<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1072143"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">46.404</ph> Government contract quality assurance for acquisitions at or below the simplified acquisition threshold.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2679e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2693e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In determining the type and extent of Government contract quality assurance to be required for contracts at or below the simplified acquisition threshold, the contracting officer shall consider the criticality of application of the supplies or services, the amount of possible losses, and the likelihood of uncontested replacement of defective work (see <xref href="FAR-i1072409.dita#i1072409"
                        base="i1072409"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">46.202-2</xref>).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2693e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            When the conditions in <xref href="FAR-i1072409.dita#i1072409"
                        base="i1072409"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">46.202-2</xref>(b) apply, the following policies shall govern:</p>
					          <ol id="d2679e38" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2693e42" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Unless a special situation exists, the Government shall inspect contracts at or below the simplified acquisition threshold at destination and only for type and kind; quantity; damage; operability (if readily determinable); and preservation, packaging, packing, and marking, if applicable.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2693e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Special situations may require more detailed quality assurance and the use of a standard inspection or higher-level contract quality requirement. These situations include those listed in <xref href="FAR-i1072124.dita#i1072124"
                              base="i1072124"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">46.402</xref> and contracts for items having critical applications.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2693e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Detailed Government inspection may be limited to those characteristics that are special or likely to cause harm to personnel or property. When repetitive purchases of the same item are made from the same manufacturer with a history of defect-free work, Government inspection may be reduced to a periodic check of occasional purchases.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
