<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1098102"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">22.406-10</ph> Disposition of disputes concerning construction contract labor standards enforcement.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1321e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1335e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The areas of possible differences of opinion between contracting officers and contractors in construction contract labor standards enforcement include-</p>
					          <ol id="d1321e23" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e27" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Misclassification of workers;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e36" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Hours of work;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Wage rates and payment;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e54" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Payment of overtime;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Withholding practices; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e73" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The applicability of the labor standards requirements under varying circumstances.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1335e84" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Generally, these differences are settled administratively at the project level by the contracting agency. If necessary, these differences may be settled with assistance from the Department of Labor.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1335e93" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            When requesting the contractor to take corrective action in labor violation cases, the contracting officer shall inform the contractor of the following:</p>
					          <ol id="d1321e99" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e103" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Disputes concerning the labor standards requirements of the contract are handled under the contract clause at <xref href="FAR-i1055549.dita#i1055549"
                              base="i1055549"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.222-14</xref>, Disputes Concerning Labor Standards, and not under the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1048610.dita#i1048610"
                              base="i1048610"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.233-1</xref>, Disputes.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1335e118" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contractor may appeal the contracting officer’s findings or part thereof by furnishing the contracting officer a complete statement of the reasons for the disagreement with the findings.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1335e129" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall promptly transmit the contracting officer’s findings and the contractor’s statement to the Administrator, Wage and Hour Division.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1335e138" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Administrator, Wage and Hour Division, will respond directly to the contractor or subcontractor, with a copy to the contracting agency. The contractor or subcontractor may appeal the Administrator’s findings in accordance with the procedures outlined in Labor Department Regulations (29 CFR5.11). Hearings before administrative law judges are conducted in accordance with 29 CFR Part6, and hearings before the Labor Department Administrative Review Board are conducted in accordance with 29 CFR Part7.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1335e148" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Administrator, Wage and Hour Division, may institute debarment proceedings against the contractor or subcontractor if the Administrator finds reasonable cause to believe that the contractor or subcontractor has committed willful or aggravated violations of the Contract Work Hours and Safety Standards statute or the Copeland (Anti-Kickback) Act, or any of the applicable statutes listed in 29 CFR 5.1 other than the Construction Wage Rate Requirements statute, or has committed violations of the Construction Wage Rate Requirements statute that constitute a disregard of its obligations to employees or subcontractors under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">40 U.S.C. 3144</xref>.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
