<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="id1617MD0I0AC"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">35.005</ph> Work statement.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2241e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2255e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            A clear and complete work statement concerning the area of exploration (for basic research) or the end objectives (for development and applied research) is essential. The work statement should allow contractors freedom to exercise innovation and creativity. Work statements must be individually tailored by technical and contracting personnel to attain the desired degree of flexibility for contractor creativity and the objectives of the R&amp;D.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2255e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In basic research the emphasis is on achieving specified objectives and knowledge rather than on achieving predetermined end results prescribed in a statement of specific performance characteristics. This emphasis applies particularly during the early or conceptual phases of the R&amp;D effort.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2255e35" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In reviewing work statements, contracting officers should ensure that language suitable for a level-of-effort approach, which requires the furnishing of technical effort and a report on the results, is not intermingled with language suitable for a task-completion approach, which often requires the development of a tangible end item designed to achieve specific performance characteristics. The wording of the work statement should also be consistent with the type and form of contract to be negotiated (see <xref href="FAR-i1105063.dita#i1105063"
                        base="i1105063"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">16.207</xref> and <xref href="FAR-i1104719.dita#i1104719"
                        base="i1104719"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">16.306</xref>(d)). For example, the work statement for a cost-reimbursement contract promising the contractor’s best efforts for a fixed term would be phrased differently than a work statement for a cost-reimbursement completion contract promising the contractor’s best efforts for a defined task. Differences between work statements for fixed-price contracts and cost-reimbursement contracts should be even clearer.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2255e50" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In preparing work statements, technical and contracting personnel shall consider and, as appropriate, provide in the solicitation-</p>
					          <ol id="d2241e56" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2255e60" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A statement of the area of exploration, tasks to be performed, and objectives of the research or development effort;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2255e69" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Background information helpful to a clear understanding of the objective or requirement (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>any known phenomena, techniques, methodology, or results of related work);</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2255e81" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Information on factors such as personnel, environment, and interfaces that may constrain the results of the effort;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2255e90" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Reporting requirements and information on any additional items that the contractor is required to furnish (at specified intervals) as the work progresses;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2255e99" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The type and form of contract contemplated by the Government and, for level-of-effort work statements, an estimate of applicable professional and technical effort involved; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2255e109" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Any other considerations peculiar to the work to be performed; for example, any design-to-cost requirements.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
