<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1091310"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">25.703-4</ph> Waiver.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1662e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1676e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            An agency or contractor seeking a waiver of the requirements of 25.703-2 or 25.703-3, consistent with section 6(b)(5) of the Iran Sanctions Act or 22 U.S.C. 8551(b), respectively, and the Presidential Memorandum of September 23, 2010 (75 FR 67025), shall submit the request to the Office of Federal Procurement Policy, allowing sufficient time for review and approval.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1676e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Agencies may request a waiver on an individual or class basis; however, waivers are not indefinite and can be cancelled, if warranted.</p>
					          <ol id="d1662e32" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e36" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A class waiver may be requested only when the class of supplies or equipment is not available from any other source and it is in the national interest.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Prior to submitting the waiver request, the request must be reviewed and cleared by the agency head.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1676e56" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            In general, all waiver requests should include the following information:</p>
					          <ol id="d1662e62" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e66" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Agency name, complete mailing address, and point of contact name, telephone number, and e-mail address.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e75" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Offeror’s name, complete mailing address, and point of contact name, telephone number, and e-mail address.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e84" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Description/nature of product or service.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e93" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The total cost and length of the contract.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e102" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Justification, with market research demonstrating that no other offeror can provide the product or service and stating why the product or service must be procured from this offeror.</p>
							              <ol id="d1662e108" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e112" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    If the offeror exports sensitive technology to the government of Iran or any entities or individuals owned or controlled by, or acting on behalf or at the direction of, the government of Iran, provide rationale why it is in the national interest for the President to waive the prohibition on contracting with this offeror, as required by 22 U.S.C. 8551(b).</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e121" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    If the offeror conducts activities for which sanctions may be imposed under section 5 of the Iran Sanctions Act or engages in any transaction that exceeds $3,500 with Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any of its officials, agents, or affiliates, the property and interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act, provide rationale why it is essential to the national security interests of the United States for the President to waive the prohibition on contracting with this offeror, as required by section 6(b)(5) of the Iran Sanctions Act.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e133" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Documentation regarding the offeror’s past performance and integrity (see the Past Performance Information Retrieval System and the Federal Awardee Performance Information and Integrity System at www.ppirs.gov, and any other relevant information).</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e142" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Information regarding the offeror’s relationship or connection with other firms that-</p>
							              <ol id="d1662e148" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e152" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Export sensitive technology to the government of Iran or any entities or individuals owned or controlled by, or acting on behalf or at the direction of, the government of Iran;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e161" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Conduct activities for which sanctions may be imposed under section 5 of the Iran Sanctions Act; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e170" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Conduct any transaction that exceeds $3,500 with Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any of its officials, agents, or affiliates, the property and interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1676e181" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Describe-</p>
							              <ol id="d1662e187" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e191" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The sensitive technology and the entity or individual to which it was exported (i.e., the government of Iran or an entity or individual owned or controlled by, or acting on behalf or at the direction of, the government of Iran);</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e200" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The activities in which the offeror is engaged for which sanctions may be imposed under section 5 of the Iran Sanctions Act; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1676e209" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The transactions that exceed $3,500 with Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps or any of its officials, agents, or affiliates, the property and interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
