<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1048970"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.236-17</ph> Layout of Work.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3541e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1078735.dita#i1078735"
                     base="i1078735"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">36.517</xref>
				        </ph>, insert the following clause in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price construction contract is contemplated and use of this clause is appropriate due to a need for accurate work layout and for siting verification during work performance:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Layout of Work (Apr 1984)</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">The Contractor shall lay out its work from Government established base lines and bench marks indicated on the drawings, and shall be responsible for all measurements in connection with the layout. The Contractor shall furnish, at its own expense, all stakes, templates, platforms, equipment, tools, materials, and labor required to lay out any part of the work. The Contractor shall be responsible for executing the work to the lines and grades that may be established or indicated by the Contracting Officer. The Contractor shall also be responsible for maintaining and preserving all stakes and other marks established by the Contracting Officer until authorized to remove them. If such marks are destroyed by the Contractor or through its negligence before their removal is authorized, the Contracting Officer may replace them and deduct the expense of the replacement from any amounts due or to become due to the Contractor.</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
