<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="id1617ME002BE"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">49.305-1</ph> General.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2905e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2919e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The TCO shall determine the adjusted fee to be paid, if any, in the manner provided by the contract. The determination is generally based on a percentage of completion of the contract or of the terminated portion. When this basis is used, factors such as the extent and difficulty of the work performed by the contractor (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>planning, scheduling, technical study, engineering work, production and supervision, placing and supervising subcontracts, and work performed by the contractor in (1)stopping performance, (2)settling terminated subcontracts, and (3)disposing of termination inventory) shall be compared with the total work required by the contract or by the terminated portion. The contractor’s adjusted fee shall not include an allowance for fee for subcontract effort included in subcontractors’ settlement proposals.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2919e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The ratio of costs incurred to the total estimated cost of performing the contract or the terminated portion is only one factor in computing the percentage of completion. This percentage may be either greater or less than that indicated by the ratio of costs incurred, depending upon the evaluation by the TCO of other pertinent factors.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
