<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  ">
	  <concept id="i1115270"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">9.405-2</ph> Restrictions on subcontracting.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d584e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d598e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            When a contractor debarred, suspended, or proposed for debarment is proposed as a subcontractor for any subcontract subject to Government consent (see <xref href="FAR-i1073536.dita#i1073536"
                        base="i1073536"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  44.2</xref>), contracting officers shall not consent to subcontracts with such contractors unless the agency head states in writing the compelling reasons for this approval action. (See <xref href="FAR-i1115236.dita#i1115236"
                        base="i1115236"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">9.405</xref>(b) concerning declarations of ineligibility affecting sub-contracting.)</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d598e32" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Government suspends or debars contractors to protect the Government’s interests. By operation of the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1062590.dita#i1062590"
                        base="i1062590"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.209-6</xref>, Protecting the Government’s Interests When Subcontracting with Contractors Debarred, Suspended or Proposed for Debarment, contractors shall not enter into any subcontract in excess of $35,000, other than a subcontract for a commercially available off-the-shelf item, with a contractor that has been debarred, suspended, or proposed for debarment unless there is a compelling reason to do so. If a contractor intends to enter into a subcontract in excess of $35,000, other than a subcontract for a commercially available off-the-shelf item, with a party that is debarred, suspended, or proposed for debarment as evidenced by the party's having an active exclusion record in SAM (see <xref href="FAR-i1115204.dita#i1115204"
                        base="i1115204"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">9.404</xref>), a corporate officer or designee of the contractor is required by operation of the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1062590.dita#i1062590"
                        base="i1062590"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.209-6</xref>, Protecting the Government’s Interests when Subcontracting with Contractors Debarred, Suspended, or Proposed for Debarment, to notify the contracting officer, in writing, before entering into such subcontract. For contracts for the acquisition of commercial items, the notification requirement applies only for first-tier subcontracts. For all other contracts, the notification requirement applies to subcontracts at any tier. The notice must provide the following:</p>
					          <ol id="d584e47" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d598e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The name of the subcontractor;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d598e60" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The contractor’s knowledge of the reasons for the subcontractor having an active exclusion record in SAM;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d598e69" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The compelling reason(s) for doing business with the subcontractor notwithstanding its having an active exclusion record in SAM; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d598e78" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The systems and procedures the contractor has established to ensure that it is fully protecting the Government’s interests when dealing with such subcontractor in view of the specific basis for the party’s debarment, suspension, or proposed debarment.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d598e89" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contractor’s compliance with the requirements of <xref href="FAR-i1062590.dita#i1062590"
                        base="i1062590"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.209-6</xref> will be reviewed during Contractor Purchasing System Reviews (see <xref href="FAR-i1073426.dita#i1073426"
                        base="i1073426"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  44.3</xref>).</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
