<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  ">
	  <concept id="i1114728"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">10.002</ph> Procedures.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d627e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d641e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Acquisitions begin with a description of the Government’s needs stated in terms sufficient to allow conduct of market research.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d641e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Market research is then conducted to determine if commercial items or nondevelopmental items are available to meet the Government’s needs or could be modified to meet the Government’s needs.</p>
					          <ol id="d627e32" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d641e36" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The extent of market research will vary, depending on such factors as urgency, estimated dollar value, complexity, and past experience. The contracting officer may use market research conducted within 18 months before the award of any task or delivery order if the information is still current, accurate, and relevant. Market research involves obtaining information specific to the item being acquired and should include-</p>
							              <ol id="d627e42" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e46" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Whether the Government’s needs can be met by-</p>
									                  <ol id="d627e52" class="- topic/ol ">
										                    <li class="- topic/li ">
											                      <p id="d641e56" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph>
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
												                        Items of a type customarily available in the commercial marketplace;</p>
										                    </li>
										                    <li class="- topic/li ">
											                      <p id="d641e65" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph>
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
												                        Items of a type customarily available in the commercial marketplace with modifications; or</p>
										                    </li>
										                    <li class="- topic/li ">
											                      <p id="d641e74" class="- topic/p ">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(C)</ph>
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
                                    
												                        Items used exclusively for governmental purposes;</p>
										                    </li>
									                  </ol>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e85" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Customary practices regarding customizing, modifying or tailoring of items to meet customer needs and associated costs;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e94" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Customary practices, including warranty, buyer financing, discounts, contract type considering the nature and risk associated with the requirement, etc., under which commercial sales of the products or services are made;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e103" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The requirements of any laws and regulations unique to the item being acquired;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e112" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The availability of items that contain recovered materials and items that are energy efficient;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e122" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The distribution and support capabilities of potential suppliers, including alternative arrangements and cost estimates; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e131" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Size and status of potential sources (see <xref href="FAR-i1101928.dita#i1101928"
                                    base="i1101928"
                                    outputclass="fm:Part"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">part  19</xref>).</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d641e145" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Techniques for conducting market research may include any or all of the following:</p>
							              <ol id="d627e151" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e155" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Contacting knowledgeable individuals in Government and industry regarding market capabilities to meet requirements.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e164" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Reviewing the results of recent market research undertaken to meet similar or identical requirements.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e173" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Publishing formal requests for information in appropriate technical or scientific journals or business publications.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e182" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Querying the Governmentwide database of contracts and other procurement instruments intended for use by multiple agencies available at <xref href="https://www.contractdirectory.gov/contractdirectory/"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">https://www.contractdirectory. gov/contractdirectory/</xref> and other Government and commercial databases that provide information relevant to agency acquisitions.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e194" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Participating in interactive, on-line communication among industry, acquisition personnel, and customers.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e204" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Obtaining source lists of similar items from other contracting activities or agencies, trade associations or other sources.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e213" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Reviewing catalogs and other generally available product literature published by manufacturers, distributors, and dealers or available on-line.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d641e222" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(viii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Conducting interchange meetings or holding presolicitation conferences to involve potential offerors early in the acquisition process.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d641e235" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If market research indicates commercial or nondevelopmental items might not be available to satisfy agency needs, agencies shall reevaluate the need in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1114676.dita#i1114676"
                        base="i1114676"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">10.001</xref>(a)(3)(ii) and determine whether the need can be restated to permit commercial or nondevelopmental items to satisfy the agency’s needs.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d641e247" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
					          </p>
					          <ol id="d627e253" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d641e257" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If market research establishes that the Government’s need may be met by a type of item or service customarily available in the commercial marketplace that would meet the definition of a commercial item at <xref href="FAR-i1125357.dita#i1125357"
                              base="i1125357"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  2.1</xref>, the contracting officer shall solicit and award any resultant contract using the policies and procedures in <xref href="FAR-i1113784.dita#i1113784"
                              base="i1113784"
                              outputclass="fm:Part"
                              class="- topic/xref ">part  12</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d641e272" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If market research establishes that the Government’s need cannot be met by a type of item or service customarily available in the marketplace, <xref href="FAR-i1113784.dita#i1113784"
                              base="i1113784"
                              outputclass="fm:Part"
                              class="- topic/xref ">part  12</xref> shall not be used. When publication of the notice at <xref href="FAR-i1120663.dita#i1120663"
                              base="i1120663"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">5.201</xref> is required, the contracting officer shall include a notice to prospective offerors that the Government does not intend to use <xref href="FAR-i1113784.dita#i1113784"
                              base="i1113784"
                              outputclass="fm:Part"
                              class="- topic/xref ">part  12</xref> for the acquisition.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d641e292" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Agencies should document the results of market research in a manner appropriate to the size and complexity of the acquisition.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
