<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1088162"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">28.203-1</ph> Security interests by an individual surety.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d1811e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1825e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            An individual surety may be accepted only if a security interest in assets acceptable under <xref href="FAR-i1088189.dita#i1088189"
                        base="i1088189"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">28.203-2</xref> is provided to the Government by the individual surety. The security interest shall be furnished with the bond.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d1825e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The value at which the contracting officer accepts the assets pledged must be equal to or greater than the aggregate penal amounts of the bonds required by the solicitation and may be provided by one or a combination of the following methods:</p>
					          <ol id="d1811e35" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1825e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                An escrow account with a federally insured financial institution in the name of the contracting agency. (See <xref href="FAR-i1088189.dita#i1088189"
                              base="i1088189"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">28.203-2</xref>(b)(2) with respect to Government securities in book entry form.) Acceptable securities for deposit in escrow are discussed in <xref href="FAR-i1088189.dita#i1088189"
                              base="i1088189"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">28.203-2</xref>. While the offeror is responsible for establishing the escrow account, the terms and conditions must be acceptable to the contracting officer. At a minimum, the escrow account shall provide for the following:</p>
							              <ol id="d1811e51" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1825e55" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The account must provide the contracting officer the sole and unrestricted right to draw upon all or any part of the funds deposited in the account. A written demand for withdrawal shall be sent to the financial institution, after obtaining the concurrence of legal counsel, by the contracting officer with a copy to the offeror/contractor and to the surety. Within the time period specified in the demand, the financial institution would pay the Government the amount demanded up to the amount on deposit. If any dispute should arise between the Government and the offeror/contractor, the surety, or the subcontractors or suppliers with respect to the offer or contract, the financial institution would be required, unless precluded by order of a court of competent jurisdiction, to disburse monies to the Government as directed by the contracting officer.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1825e64" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The financial institution would be authorized to release to the individual surety all or part of the balance of the escrow account, including any accrued interest, upon receipt of written authorization from the contracting officer.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1825e73" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The Government would not be responsible for any costs attributable to the establishment, maintenance, administration, or any other aspect of the account.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1825e82" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The financial institution would not be liable or responsible for the interpretation of any provisions or terms and conditions of the solicitation or contract.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1825e91" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The financial institution would provide periodic account statements to the contracting officer.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1825e101" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The terms of the escrow account could not be amended without the consent of the contracting officer.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1825e112" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                A lien on real property, subject to the restrictions in <xref href="FAR-i1088189.dita#i1088189"
                              base="i1088189"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">28.203-2</xref> and <xref href="FAR-i1088221.dita#i1088221"
                              base="i1088221"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">28.203-3</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
