<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="id1617MD0I01J"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">35.016</ph> Broad agency announcement.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2252e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2266e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">General.</i>This paragraph prescribes procedures for the use of the broad agency announcement (BAA) with Peer or Scientific Review (see <xref href="FAR-i1120068.dita#i1120068"
                        base="i1120068"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">6.102</xref>(d)(2)) for the acquisition of basic and applied research and that part of development not related to the development of a specific system or hardware procurement. BAA’s may be used by agencies to fulfill their requirements for scientific study and experimentation directed toward advancing the state-of-the-art or increasing knowledge or understanding rather than focusing on a specific system or hardware solution. The BAA technique shall only be used when meaningful proposals with varying technical/scientific approaches can be reasonably anticipated.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2266e32" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The BAA, together with any supporting documents, shall-</p>
					          <ol id="d2252e38" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2266e42" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Describe the agency’s research interest, either for an individual program requirement or for broadly defined areas of interest covering the full range of the agency’s requirements;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2266e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Describe the criteria for selecting the proposals, their relative importance, and the method of evaluation;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2266e60" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Specify the period of time during which proposals submitted in response to the BAA will be accepted; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2266e69" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Contain instructions for the preparation and submission of proposals.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2266e80" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The availability of the BAA must be publicized through the Governmentwide point of entry (GPE) and, if authorized pursuant to <xref href="FAR-i1120403.dita#i1120403"
                        base="i1120403"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  5.5</xref>, may also be published in noted scientific, technical, or engineering periodicals. The notice must be published no less frequently than annually.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2266e92" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Proposals received as a result of the BAA shall be evaluated in accordance with evaluation criteria specified therein through a peer or scientific review process. Written evaluation reports on individual proposals will be necessary but proposals need not be evaluated against each other since they are not submitted in accordance with a common work statement.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2266e101" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The primary basis for selecting proposals for acceptance shall be technical, importance to agency programs, and fund availability. Cost realism and reasonableness shall also be considered to the extent appropriate.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2266e111" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Synopsis under <xref href="FAR-i1120661.dita#i1120661"
                        base="i1120661"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  5.2</xref>, Synopses of Proposed Contract Actions, of individual contract actions based upon proposals received under the BAA is not required. The notice published pursuant to paragraph (c) of this section fulfills the synopsis requirement.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
