<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i1072818"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">45.602-3</ph> Screening.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">The screening period begins upon the plant clearance
officer’s acceptance of an inventory disposal schedule. The plant
clearance officer shall determine whether standard or special screening
is appropriate and initiate screening actions.</p>
         <ol id="d2632e16" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2646e20" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Standard
screening</i>. The standard screening period is 46 days.</p>
               <ol id="d2632e29" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e33" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">First
through twentieth day-Screening by the contracting agency</i>. The
contracting agency has 20 days to screen property reported on the
inventory disposal schedule for: other use within the agency; transfer
of educationally useful equipment to other Federal agencies that
have expressed a need for the property; and transfer of educationally
useful equipment to schools and nonprofit organizations if a Federal
agency has not expressed a need for the property. Excess personal
property, meeting the conditions of <xref href="FAR-i1072848.dita#i1072848"
                              base="i1072848"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">45.603</xref>, may be abandoned,
destroyed, or donated to public bodies. No later than the 21st day,
the plant clearance officer shall submit four copies of the revised
schedules and <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/report-excess-personal-property"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">Standard Form (SF) 120</xref>,
Report of Excess Personal Property, or an electronic equivalent
to GSA (see 41 CFR 102-36.215).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Twenty-first
through forty-sixth day (21 days concurrent screening plus 5 days
donation processing).-</p>
                     <ol id="d2632e57" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e61" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Screening by other Federal agencies</i>.
GSA will normally honor requests for transfers of property on a
first-come-first-served basis through the 41st day. When a request
is honored, the GSA regional office shall promptly transmit to the
plant clearance officer an approved transfer order that includes
shipping instructions.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e73" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Screening
for possible donation</i>. Screening for donation is also completed
during days 21 through 41. Property is not available for allocation
to donees until after the completion of screening. Days 42 through
46 are reserved for GSA to make such allocation.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e87" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Screening
period transfer request</i>. If an agency receives an intra-agency
transfer request during the screening periods described in paragraph
(a)(2) of this <ph class="- topic/ph ">section,</ph> the
plant clearance officer shall request GSA approval to withdraw the
item from the inventory disposal schedule.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d2646e104" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                   Special
screening requirements.-</p>
               <ol id="d2632e107" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e114" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Special tooling and special
test equipment without commercial components</i>. Agencies shall
follow the procedures in paragraph (a) of this <ph class="- topic/ph ">section.</ph> This property
owned by the Department of Defense (DoD) or the National Aeronautics
and Space Administration (NASA) may be screened for reutilization
only within these agencies.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e129" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                         Special
test equipment with commercial components.-</p>
                     <ol id="d2632e129" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e139" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               Agencies
shall complete the screening required by paragraph (a) of this <ph class="- topic/ph ">section.</ph> If an agency has
no further need for the property and the contractor has not expressed an
interest in using or acquiring the property by annotating the inventory
disposal schedule, the plant clearance officer shall forward the
inventory disposal schedule to the GSA regional office that serves
the region in which the property is located.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e151" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               If the
contractor has expressed an interest in using the property on another
Government contract, the plant clearance officer shall contact the
contracting officer for that contract. If the contracting officer
concurs with the proposed use, the contracting officer for the contract
under which the property is accountable shall transfer the property’s
accountability to that contract. If the contracting officer does
not concur with the proposed use, the plant clearance officer shall
deny the contractor’s request and shall continue the screening process.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e160" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                               If the
property is contractor-acquired or produced, and the contractor
or subcontractor has expressed an interest in acquiring the property,
and no other party expresses an interest during agency or GSA screening,
the property may be sold to the contractor or subcontractor at acquisition
cost.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e171" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Printing
equipment</i>. Agencies shall report all excess printing equipment
to the Public Printer, <ph class="- topic/ph ">Government Publishing Office,</ph> 732
North Capitol Street, NW, Washington, DC 20401, after screening
within the agency (see <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">44 U.S.C. 312</xref>).
If the Public Printer does not express a need for the equipment
within 21 days, the agency shall submit the report to GSA for further
use and donation screening as described in paragraph (a) of this <ph class="- topic/ph ">section.</ph>
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e192" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Non-nuclear
hazardous materials, hazardous wastes, and classified items</i>.
These items shall be screened in accordance with agency procedures.
Report non-nuclear hazardous materials to GSA if the agency has
no requirement for them.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d2646e204" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Nuclear
materials</i>. The possession, use, and transfer of certain nuclear
materials are subject to the regulatory controls of the Nuclear
Regulatory Commission (NRC). Contracting activities shall screen
excess nuclear materials in the following categories:</p>
                     <ol id="d2632e198" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e217" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">By-product
material</i>. Any radioactive material (except special nuclear material)
yielded in or made radioactive by exposure to the radiation incident
to producing or using special nuclear material.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e229" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Source
material</i>. Uranium or thorium, or any combination thereof, in
any physical or chemical form; or ores that contain by weight one-twentieth
of 1 percent (0.05 percent) or more of uranium, thorium, or any
combination thereof. Source material does not include special nuclear
material.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d2646e241" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Special
nuclear material</i>. Plutonium, Uranium 233, Uranium enriched in
the isotope 233 or in the isotope 235, any other material that the
NRC determines to be special nuclear material (but not including
source material); or any material artificially enriched by any nuclear
material.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
