<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="i1084587"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">31.201-6</ph> Accounting for unallowable
costs.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1925e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1939e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                   Costs that are expressly unallowable
or mutually agreed to be unallowable, including mutually agreed
to be unallowable directly associated costs, shall be identified
and excluded from any billing, claim, or proposal applicable to
a Government contract. A directly associated cost is any cost that
is generated solely as a result of incurring another cost, and that
would not have been incurred had the other cost not been incurred.
When an unallowable cost is incurred, its directly associated costs
are also unallowable.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1939e26" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                   Costs that
specifically become designated as unallowable or as unallowable
directly associated costs of unallowable costs as a result of a
written decision furnished by a contracting officer shall be identified
if included in or used in computing any billing, claim, or proposal
applicable to a Government contract. This identification requirement
applies also to any costs incurred for the same purpose under like
circumstances as the costs specifically identified as unallowable under
either this paragraph or paragraph (a) of this subsection.</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1939e35" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
               </p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                         The practices
for accounting for and presentation of unallowable costs must be
those described in 48 CFR 9904.405, Accounting for Unallowable Costs.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e54" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                         Statistical
sampling is an acceptable practice for contractors to follow in
accounting for and presenting unallowable costs provided the criteria
in paragraphs (c)(2)(i), (c)(2)(ii), and (c)(2)(iii) of this subsection
are met:</p>
                     <ol id="d1925e51" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1939e64" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                               The statistical sampling results
in an unbiased sample that is a reasonable representation of the
sampling universe.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1939e73" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                               Any large
dollar value or high risk transaction is separately reviewed for
unallowable costs and excluded from the sampling process.</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1939e82" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                               The statistical
sampling permits audit verification.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e93" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                         For any
indirect cost in the selected sample that is subject to the penalty
provisions at 42.709, the amount projected to the sampling universe
from that sampled cost is also subject to the same penalty provisions.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e102" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                         Use of
statistical sampling methods for identifying and segregating unallowable
costs should be the subject of an advance agreement under the provisions
of <xref href="FAR-i1086218.dita#i1086218"
                              base="i1086218"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">31.109</xref> between the contractor
and the cognizant administrative contracting officer or Federal
official. The advance agreement should specify the basic characteristics
of the sampling process. The cognizant administrative contracting
officer or Federal official shall request input from the cognizant
auditor before entering into any such agreements.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e114" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                         In the
absence of an advance agreement, if an initial review of the facts
results in a challenge of the statistical sampling methods by the
contracting officer or the contracting officer’s representative,
the burden of proof shall be on the contractor to establish that
such a method meets the criteria in paragraph (c)(2) of this subsection.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1939e125" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                   If a directly
associated cost is included in a cost pool that is allocated over
a base that includes the unallowable cost with which it is associated,
the directly associated cost shall remain in the cost pool. Since
the unallowable costs will attract their allocable share of costs
from the cost pool, no further action is required to assure disallowance
of the directly associated costs. In all other cases, the directly
associated costs, if material in amount, must be purged from the
cost pool as unallowable costs.</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p id="d1939e134" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
               </p>
               <ol id="d1925e134" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e144" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                         In
determining the materiality of a directly associated cost, consideration
should be given to the significance of-</p>
                     <ol id="d1925e144" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1939e154" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                               The actual
dollar amount,</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1939e163" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                               The cumulative
effect of all directly associated costs in a cost pool, and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d1939e172" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                               The
ultimate effect on the cost of Government contracts.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e183" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                         Salary
expenses of employees who participate in activities that generate
unallowable costs shall be treated as directly associated costs
to the extent of the time spent on the proscribed activity, provided
the costs are material in accordance with paragraph (e)(1) of this
subsection (except when such salary expenses are, themselves, unallowable). The
time spent in proscribed activities should be compared to total
time spent on company activities to determine if the costs are material.
Time spent by employees outside the normal working hours should
not be considered except when it is evident that an employee engages
so frequently in company activities during periods outside normal
working hours as to indicate that such activities are a part of
the employee’s regular duties.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d1939e192" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                         When a
selected item of cost under <xref href="FAR-i1084681.dita#i1084681"
                              base="i1084681"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">31.205</xref> provides
that directly associated costs be unallowable, such directly associated
costs are unallowable only if determined to be material in amount
in accordance with the criteria provided in paragraphs (e)(1) and
(e)(2) of this subsection, except in those situations where allowance
of any of the directly associated costs involved would be considered
to be contrary to public policy.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
