<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2">
   <concept id="id1897F0DI0UI"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">4.2101</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p id="id1989H200023" class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart—</p>
         <p id="id1989H2005FY" class="- topic/p ">“Covered foreign country” means The People’s
Republic of China.</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">“Covered telecommunications equipment or services” means–</p>
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e30" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Telecommunications
equipment produced by Huawei Technologies Company or ZTE Corporation,
(or any subsidiary or affiliate of such entities);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         For the
purpose of public safety, security of Government facilities, physical
security surveillance of critical infrastructure, and other national
security purposes, video surveillance and telecommunications equipment
produced by Hytera Communications Corporation, Hangzhou Hikvision
Digital Technology Company, or Dahua Technology Company (or any
subsidiary or affiliate of such entities);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Telecommunications
or video surveillance services provided by such entities or using
such equipment; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e57" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Telecommunications
or video surveillance equipment or services produced or provided
by an entity that the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with
the Director of National Intelligence or the Director of the Federal
Bureau of Investigation, reasonably believes to be an entity owned
or controlled by, or otherwise connected to, the government of a
covered foreign country.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p id="id1989H200XHC" class="- topic/p ">“Critical technology” means–</p>
         <ol class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e79" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Defense
articles or defense services included on the United States Munitions
List set forth in the International Traffic in Arms Regulations
under subchapter M of chapter I of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e88" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Items included
on the Commerce Control List set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part
774 of the Export Administration Regulations under subchapter C
of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, and controlled-</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d322e98" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                               Pursuant
to multilateral regimes, including for reasons relating to national
security, chemical and biological weapons proliferation, nuclear
nonproliferation, or missile technology; or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p id="d322e107" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                               For reasons
relating to regional stability or surreptitious listening;</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e118" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Specially
designed and prepared nuclear equipment, parts and components, materials,
software, and technology covered by part 810 of title 10, Code of
Federal Regulations (relating to assistance to foreign atomic energy
activities);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e127" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Nuclear
facilities, equipment, and material covered by part 110 of title
10, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to export and import of
nuclear equipment and material);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e136" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Select
agents and toxins covered by part 331 of title 7, Code of Federal
Regulations, part 121 of title 9 of such Code, or part 73 of title
42 of such Code; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p id="d322e146" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                          Emerging
and foundational technologies controlled pursuant to section 1758
of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (50 U.S.C. 4817).</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p id="id1989H300SBU" class="- topic/p ">“Substantial or essential component” means
any component necessary for the proper function or performance of
a piece of equipment, system, or service.</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
