<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1078709"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">36.513</ph> Accident prevention.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2311e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2325e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1048913.dita#i1048913"
                        base="i1048913"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.236-13</xref>, Accident Prevention, in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price construction contract or a fixed-price dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements contract is contemplated and the contract amount is expected to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold. The contracting officer may insert the clause in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price construction or a fixed-price contract for dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements is contemplated and the contract amount is expected to be at or below the simplified acquisition threshold. If the contract will involve work of a long duration or hazardous nature, the contracting officer shall use the clause with its AlternateI.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2325e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the clause or the clause with its AlternateI in solicitations and contracts when a contract for services to be performed at Government facilities (see 48 CFR Part37) is contemplated, and technical representatives advise that special precautions are appropriate.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2325e38" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer should inform the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), or other cognizant Federal, State, or local officials, of instances where the contractor has been notified to take immediate action to correct serious or imminent dangers.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
