<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  ">
	  <concept id="i1055928"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.222-31</ph> Construction Wage Rate Requirements-Price Adjustment (Percentage Method).</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3318e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1098137.dita#i1098137"
                     base="i1098137"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">22.407</xref>(f)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Construction Wage Rate Requirements-Price Adjustment (Percentage Method) (Aug 2018)</p>
			      <ol id="d3300e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3318e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The wage determination issued under the Construction Wage Rate Requirements statute by the Administrator, Wage and Hour <term class="- topic/term ">Division, U.S</term>. Department of Labor, that is effective for an option to extend the term of the contract, will apply to that option period.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3318e41" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contracting Officer will adjust the portion of the contract price or contract unit price(s) containing the labor costs subject to the Construction Wage Rate Requirements statute to provide for an increase in wages and fringe benefits at the exercise of each option to extend the term of the contract in accordance with the following procedures:</p>
					          <ol id="d3300e44" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3318e51" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contracting Officer has determined that the portion of the contract price or contract unit price(s) containing labor costs subject to the Construction Wage Rate Requirements statute is __________ [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer insert percentage rate</i>] percent.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3318e63" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contracting Officer will increase the portion of the contract price or contract unit price(s) containing the labor costs subject to the Construction Wage Rate Requirements statute by the percentage rate published in _____________ [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer insert publication</i>].</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3318e77" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contracting Officer will make the price adjustment at the exercise of each option to extend the term of the contract. This adjustment is the only adjustment that the Contracting Officer will make to cover any increases in wages and benefits as a result of-</p>
					          <ol id="d3300e80" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3318e87" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Incorporation of the Department of Labor’s wage determination applicable at the exercise of the option to extend the term of the contract;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3318e96" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Incorporation of a wage determination otherwise applied to the contract by operation of law; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3318e105" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                An increase in wages and benefits resulting from any other requirement applicable to workers subject to the Construction Wage Rate Requirements statute.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
