<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1077593"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">37.304</ph> Contract clauses.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2388e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2399e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049144.dita#i1049144"
                        base="i1049144"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.237-4</xref>, Payment by Government to Contractor, in solicitations and contracts solely for dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements whenever the contracting officer determines that the Government shall make payment to the contractor in addition to any title to property that the contractor may receive under the contract. If the contracting officer determines that all material resulting from the dismantling or demolition work is to be retained by the Government, use the basic clause with its AlternateI.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2399e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049158.dita#i1049158"
                        base="i1049158"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.237-5</xref>, Payment by Contractor to Government in solicitations and contracts for dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements whenever the contractor is to receive title to dismantled or demolished property and a net amount of compensation is due to the Government, except if the contracting officer determines that it would be advantageous to the Government for the contractor to pay in increments and the Government to transfer title to the contractor for increments of property only upon receipt of those payments.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2399e41" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049169.dita#i1049169"
                        base="i1049169"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.237-6</xref>, Incremental Payment by Contractor to Government, in solicitations and contracts for dismantling, demolition, or removal of improvements if (l)the contractor is to receive title to dismantled or demolished property and a net amount of compensation is due the Government, and (2)the contracting officer determines that it would be advantageous to the Government for the contractor to pay in increments, and for the Government to transfer title to the contractor for increments of property only upon receipt of those payments. This determination may be appropriate, for example, if it encourages greater competition or participation of small business concerns.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
