<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="id1617MD0H0N1"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">32.1009</ph> Title.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2170e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2184e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Since the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1050610.dita#i1050610"
                        base="i1050610"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.232-32</xref>, Performance-Based Payments, gives the Government title to the property described in paragraph (f) of the clause, the contracting officer shall ensure that the Government title is not compromised by other encumbrances. Ordinarily, the contracting officer, in the absence of reason to believe otherwise, may rely upon the contractor’s certification contained in the payment request.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2184e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the contracting officer becomes aware of any arrangement or condition that would impair the Government’s title to the property affected by the Performance-Based Payments clause, the contracting officer shall require additional protective provisions.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2184e38" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The existence of any such encumbrance is a violation of the contractor’s obligations under the contract, and the contracting officer may, if necessary, suspend or reduce payments under the terms of the Performance-Based Payments clause covering failure to comply with a material requirement of the contract. In addition, if the contractor fails to disclose an existing encumbrance in the certification, the contracting officer should consult with legal counsel concerning possible violation of <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html"
                        class="- topic/xref ">31 U.S.C.3729</xref>, the False Claims Act.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
