<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="id1617ME000MF"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">47.205</ph> Availability of term contracts and basic ordering agreements for transportation or for transportation-related services.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2733e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2747e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            All Government agencies may contract for transportation or for transportation-related services and execute basic ordering agreements (BOA’s) (see <xref href="FAR-i1103566.dita#i1103566"
                        base="i1103566"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  16.7</xref>) unless agency regulations prescribe otherwise. However, it is generally more economical and efficient for most agencies to make use of term contracts and basic ordering agreements that have been executed by agencies that employ personnel experienced in contracting for transportation or for transportation-related services. The Department of Defense (DoD) and the General Services Administration (GSA) contract for transportation or for transportation-related services on behalf of other activities and agencies. For instance, GSA awards term contracts for services such as local drayage, office moves, and ocean-freight forwarding (see <xref href="FAR-i1071455.dita#i1071455"
                        base="i1071455"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">47.105</xref> for assistance).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2747e32" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Agencies may obtain transportation or transportation-related services for which the cost does not exceed the simplified acquisition threshold if term contracts or basic ordering agreements are not available.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
