<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1051688"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.230-3</ph> Disclosure and Consistency of Cost Accounting Practices.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3466e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1087135.dita#i1087135"
                     base="i1087135"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">30.201-4</xref>(b)(1)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Disclosure and Consistency of Cost Accounting Practices (Oct 2015)</p>
			      <ol id="d3448e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3466e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contractor, in connection with this contract, shall-</p>
					          <ol id="d3448e35" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3466e39" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Comply with the requirements of 48 CFR 9904.401, Consistency in Estimating, Accumulating, and Reporting Costs; 48 CFR 9904.402, Consistency in Allocating Costs Incurred for the Same Purpose; 48 CFR 9904.405, Accounting for Unallowable Costs; and 48 CFR 9904.406, Cost Accounting Standard-Cost Accounting Period, in effect on the date of award of this contract as indicated in 48 CFR Part9904.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3466e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                
								                <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">(CAS-covered Contracts Only)</i> If it is a business unit of a company required to submit a Disclosure Statement, disclose in writing its cost accounting practices as required by 48 CFR 9903.202-1 through 9903.202-5. If the Contractor has notified the Contracting Officer that the Disclosure Statement contains trade secrets and commercial or financial information which is privileged and confidential, the Disclosure Statement shall be protected and shall not be released outside of the Government.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3466e60" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                
							              </p>
							              <ol id="d3448e66" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3466e70" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Follow consistently the Contractor’s cost accounting practices. A change to such practices may be proposed, however, by either the Government or the Contractor, and the Contractor agrees to negotiate with the Contracting Officer the terms and conditions under which a change may be made. After the terms and conditions under which the change is to be made have been agreed to, the change must be applied prospectively to this contract, and the Disclosure Statement, if affected, must be amended accordingly.</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3466e79" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The Contractor shall, when the parties agree to a change to a cost accounting practice and the Contracting Officer has made the finding required in 48 CFR 9903.201-6(c), that the change is desirable and not detrimental to the interests of the Government, negotiate an equitable adjustment as provided in the Changes clause of this contract. In the absence of the required finding, no agreement may be made under this contract clause that will increase costs paid by the United States.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3466e90" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Agree to an adjustment of the contract price or cost allowance, as appropriate, if the Contractor or a subcontractor fails to comply with the applicable CAS or to follow any cost accounting practice, and such failure results in any increased costs paid by the United States. Such adjustment shall provide for recovery of the increased costs to the United States together with interest thereon computed at the annual rate established under section 6621(a)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code of1986 (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">26 U.S.C.6621(a)(2)</xref>), from the time the payment by the United States was made to the time the adjustment is effected.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3466e104" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the parties fail to agree whether the Contractor has complied with an applicable CAS, rule, or regulation as specified in 48 CFR 9903 and 9904 and as to any cost adjustment demanded by the United States, such failure to agree will constitute a dispute under <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. chapter 71</xref>, Contract Disputes.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3466e116" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contractor shall permit any authorized representatives of the Government to examine and make copies of any documents, papers, and records relating to compliance with the requirements of this clause.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3466e125" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contractor shall include in all negotiated subcontracts, which the Contractor enters into, the substance of this clause, except paragraph (b), and shall require such inclusion in all other subcontracts of any tier, except that-</p>
					          <ol id="d3448e131" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3466e135" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the subcontract is awarded to a business unit which pursuant to 48 CFR 9903.201-2 is subject to other types of CAS coverage, the substance of the applicable clause set forth in subsection <xref href="FAR-i1087135.dita#i1087135"
                              base="i1087135"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">30.201-4</xref> of the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be inserted.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3466e147" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                This requirement shall apply only to negotiated subcontracts in excess of $750,000.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3466e156" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The requirement shall not apply to negotiated subcontracts otherwise exempt from the requirement to include a CAS clause as specified in 48 CFR 9903.201-1.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
