<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1064634"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.103</ph> Identification of provisions and clauses.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d3015e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3032e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Whenever any FAR provision or clause is used without deviation in a solicitation or contract, whether it is incorporated by reference or in full text, it shall be identified by number, title, and date. This identification shall also be used if the FAR provision or clause is used with an authorized deviation, except that the contracting officer shall then insert “(DEVIATION)” after the date. Solicited firms and contractors will be advised of the meaning of this insertion through the use of the (1)provision at <xref href="FAR-i1045335.dita#i1045335"
                        base="i1045335"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.252-5</xref>, Authorized Deviations in Provisions, or (2)clause at <xref href="FAR-i1045348.dita#i1045348"
                        base="i1045348"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.252-6</xref>, Authorized Deviations in Clauses. The above mentioned provision and clause are prescribed in <xref href="FAR-i1064684.dita#i1064684"
                        base="i1064684"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.107</xref>(e) and (f).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3032e35" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Any provision or clause that supplements the FAR whether it is incorporated by reference or in full text shall be clearly identified by number, title, date, and name of the regulation. When a supplemental provision or clause is used with an authorized deviation, insert “(DEVIATION)” after the name of the regulation.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3032e44" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            A provision or clause of the type described in <xref href="FAR-i1064507.dita#i1064507"
                        base="i1064507"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.101</xref>(b)(2)(i)(C) shall be identified by the title, date, and the name of the agency or suborganization within the agency that developed it.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3032e56" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Except for provisions or clauses covered by <xref href="#i1064634"
                        base="i1064634"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.103</xref>(c), the following hypothetical examples illustrate how a provision or clause that supplements the FAR shall be identified when it is incorporated in solicitations and/or contracts by reference or in full text:</p>
					          <ol id="d3015e65" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3032e69" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If <xref href="FAR-i1111055.dita#i1111055"
                              base="i1111055"
                              outputclass="fm:Part"
                              class="- topic/xref ">part  14</xref>(Sealed Bidding) of the X Agency Acquisition Regulation, published in the <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Federal Register</i> and codified as Chapter99 in 48 CFR, prescribes the use of a provision entitled “Bid Envelopes,” dated October1983, and that provision is sequentially the first provision or clause appearing in Section52.214 of the X Agency Acquisition Regulation, then the identification of that provision shall be “9952.214-70-Bid Envelopes (<term class="- topic/term ">Oct</term>1983).”</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3032e87" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Assume that Y, a major organizational element of the X Agency, is authorized to issue the Y Acquisition Regulation, which is not published in the <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Federal Register</i> and codified in 48 CFR. If <xref href="FAR-i1079251.dita#i1079251"
                              base="i1079251"
                              outputclass="fm:Part"
                              class="- topic/xref ">part  36</xref>(Construction and Architect-Engineer Contracts) of the Y Acquisition Regulation prescribes the use of a clause entitled “Refrigerated Display Cases,” dated March1983, pertaining to a specialized type of construction work, and that clause is sequentially the second provision or clause appearing in Section52.236 of the Y Acquisition Regulation, then the identification of that clause shall be “52.236-71-Refrigerated Display Cases (<term class="- topic/term ">Mar</term>1983)-Y Acquisition Regulation.”</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
