<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept id="i52_219-8"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.219-8</ph> Utilization of Small Business Concerns.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3262e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1100497.dita#i1100497"
                     base="i1100497"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">19.708</xref>(a)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Utilization of Small Business Concerns (Oct 2018)</p>
			      <ol id="d3244e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3262e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>. As used in this contract—</p>
					          <p id="d3262e38" class="- topic/p ">“HUBZone small business concern” means a small business concern, certified by the Small Business Administration, that appears on the List of Qualified HUBZone Small Business Concerns maintained by the Small Business Administration.</p>
					          <p id="d3262e41" class="- topic/p ">“Service-disabled veteran-owned small business concern”—</p>
					          <ol id="d3244e50" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Means a small business concern-</p>
							              <ol id="d3244e60" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e58" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Not less than 51 percent of which is owned by one or more service-disabled veterans or, in the case of any publicly owned business, not less than 51 percent of the stock of which is owned by one or more service-disabled veterans; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e67" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The management and daily business operations of which are controlled by one or more service-disabled veterans or, in the case of a service-disabled veteran with permanent and severe disability, the spouse or permanent caregiver of such veteran.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e78" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Service-disabled veteran means a veteran, as defined in <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title38-section101&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">38 U.S.C.101(2)</xref>, with a disability that is service-connected, as defined in <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title38-section101&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">38 U.S.C.101(16)</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
					          <p id="d3262e92" class="- topic/p ">“Small business concern” means a small business as defined pursuant to Section 3 of the Small Business Act and relevant regulations promulgated pursuant thereto.</p>
					          <p id="d3262e96" class="- topic/p ">“Small disadvantaged business concern”, consistent with 13 CFR 124.1002, means a small business concern under the size standard applicable to the acquisition, that-</p>
					          <ol id="d3244e104" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e103" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Is at least 51 percent unconditionally and directly owned (as defined at 13 CFR 124.105) by-</p>
							              <ol id="d3244e114" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e113" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    One or more socially disadvantaged (as defined at 13 CFR 124.103) and economically disadvantaged (as defined at 13 CFR 124.104) individuals who are citizens of the United States; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e122" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Each individual claiming economic disadvantage has a net worth not exceeding $750,000 after taking into account the applicable exclusions set forth at 13 CFR 124.104(c)(2); and</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e133" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The management and daily business operations of which are controlled (as defined at 13.CFR 124.106) by individuals, who meet the criteria in paragraphs (1)(i) and (ii) of this definition.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
					          <p id="d3262e141" class="- topic/p ">“Veteran-owned small business concern” means a small business concern-</p>
					          <ol id="d3244e194" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e148" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Not less than 51 percent of which is owned by one or more veterans (as defined at <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title38-section101&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">38 U.S.C.101(2)</xref>) or, in the case of any publicly owned business, not less than 51 percent of the stock of which is owned by one or more veterans; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e160" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The management and daily business operations of which are controlled by one or more veterans.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
					          <p id="d3262e168" class="- topic/p ">“Women-owned small business concern” means a small business concern-</p>
					          <ol id="d3244e221" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e175" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                That is at least 51 percent owned by one or more women, or, in the case of any publicly owned business, at least 51 percent of the stock of which is owned by one or more women; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e184" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Whose management and daily business operations are controlled by one or more women.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3262e195" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            It is the policy of the United States that small business concerns, veteran-owned small business concerns, service-disabled veteran-owned small business concerns, HUBZone small business concerns, small disadvantaged business concerns, and women-owned small business concerns shall have the maximum practicable opportunity to participate in performing contracts let by any Federal agency, including contracts and subcontracts for subsystems, assemblies, components, and related services for major systems. It is further the policy of the United States that its prime contractors establish procedures to ensure the timely payment of amounts due pursuant to the terms of their subcontracts with small business concerns, veteran-owned small business concerns, service-disabled veteran-owned small business concerns, HUBZone small business concerns, small disadvantaged business concerns, and women-owned small business concerns.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3262e204" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The Contractor hereby agrees to carry out this policy in the awarding of subcontracts to the fullest extent consistent with efficient contract performance. The Contractor further agrees to cooperate in any studies or surveys as may be conducted by the United States Small Business Administration or the awarding agency of the United States as may be necessary to determine the extent of the Contractor's compliance with this clause.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3262e213" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
					          </p>
					          <ol id="d3244e272" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e223" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor may accept a subcontractor's written representations of its size and socioeconomic status as a small business, small disadvantaged business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled veteran-owned small business, or a women-owned small business if the subcontractor represents that the size and socioeconomic status representations with its offer are current, accurate, and complete as of the date of the offer for the subcontract.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e232" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor may accept a subcontractor's representations of its size and socioeconomic status as a small business, small disadvantaged business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled veteran-owned small business, or a women-owned small business in the System for Award Management (SAM) if–</p>
							              <ol id="d3244e291" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e242" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The subcontractor is registered in SAM; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e251" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The subcontractor represents that the size and socioeconomic status representations made in SAM are current, accurate and complete as of the date of the offer for the subcontract.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e262" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor may not require the use of SAM for the purposes of representing size or socioeconomic status in connection with a subcontract.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e271" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                In accordance with 13 CFR 121.411, 124.1015, 125.29, 126.900, and 127.700, a contractor acting in good faith is not liable for misrepresentations made by its subcontractors regarding the subcontractor's size or socioeconomic status.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3262e280" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The Contractor shall confirm that a subcontractor representing itself as a HUBZone small business concern is certified by SBA as a HUBZone small business concern by accessing the System for Award <term class="- topic/term ">Management</term> or by contacting the SBA. Options for contacting the SBA include-</p>
							              <ol id="d3244e339" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e293" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    HUBZone small business database search application web page at <xref href="http://dsbs.sba.gov/dsbs/search/dsp_searchhubzone.cfm"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">http://dsbs.sba.gov/dsbs/search/dsp_searchhubzone.cfm</xref>; or <xref href="http://www.sba.gov/hubzone"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">http://www.sba.gov/hubzone</xref>;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e308" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    In writing to the Director/HUB, U.S. Small Business Administration, 409 3 rd Street, SW., Washington, DC 20416; or</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d3262e317" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The SBA HUBZone Help Desk at <xref href="mailto:hubzone@sba.gov"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">hubzone@sba.gov</xref>.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofprovision">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
