<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1082458"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">32.504</ph> Subcontracts under prime contracts providing progress payments.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d2109e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2123e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Subcontracts may include either performance-based payments, provided they meet the criteria in <xref href="FAR-i1080969.dita#i1080969"
                        base="i1080969"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.1003</xref>, or progress payments, provided they meet the criteria in <xref href="FAR-i1082047.dita#i1082047"
                        base="i1082047"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  32.5</xref> for customary progress payments, but not both. Subcontracts for commercial purchases may include commercial item purchase financing terms, provided they meet the criteria in <xref href="FAR-i1083117.dita#i1083117"
                        base="i1083117"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.202-1</xref>.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2123e35" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contractor’s requests for progress payments may include the full amount of commercial item purchase financing payments, performance-based payments, or progress payments to a subcontractor, whether paid or unpaid, provided that unpaid amounts are limited to amounts determined due and that the contractor will pay-</p>
					          <ol id="d2109e41" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2123e45" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                In accordance with the terms and conditions of a subcontract or invoice; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2123e54" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Ordinarily within 30 days of the submission of the contractor’s progress payment request to the Government.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2123e65" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the contractor is considering making unusual progress payments to a subcontractor, the parties will be guided by the policies in <xref href="FAR-i1082080.dita#i1082080"
                        base="i1082080"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.501-2</xref>. If the Government approves unusual progress payments for the subcontract, the contracting officer must issue a contract modification to specify the new rate in paragraph (j)(6) of the clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049841.dita#i1049841"
                        base="i1049841"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.232-16</xref>, Progress Payments, in the prime contract. This will allow the contractor to include the progress payments to the subcontractor in the cost basis for progress payments by the Government. This modification is not a deviation and does not require the clearance prescribed in <xref href="FAR-i1082119.dita#i1082119"
                        base="i1082119"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.502-2</xref>(b).</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2123e83" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            The contractor has a duty to ensure that financing payments to subcontractors conform to the standards and principles prescribed in paragraph (j) of the Progress Payments clause in the prime contract. Although the contracting officer should, to the extent appropriate, review the subcontract as part of the overall administration of progress payments in the prime contract, there is no special requirement for contracting officer review or consent merely because the subcontract includes financing payments, except as provided in paragraph (c) of this section. However, the contracting officer must ensure that the contractor has installed the necessary management control systems, including internal audit procedures.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2123e92" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            When financing payments are in the form of progress payments, the Progress Payments clause at <xref href="FAR-i1049841.dita#i1049841"
                        base="i1049841"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.232-16</xref> requires that the subcontract include the substance of the Progress Payments clause in the prime contract, modified to indicate that the contractor, not the Government, awards the subcontract and administers the progress payments. The following exceptions apply to wording modifications:</p>
					          <ol id="d2109e101" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2123e105" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The subcontract terms on title to property under progress payments shall provide for vesting of title in the Government, not the contractor, as in paragraph (d) of the Progress Payments clause in the prime contract. A reference to the contractor may, however, be substituted for “Government” in paragraph (d)(2)(iv) of the clause.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2123e114" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                In the subcontract terms on reports and access to records, the contractor shall not delete the references to “Contracting Officer” and “Government” in adapting paragraph (g) of the Progress Payments clause in the contract, but may expand the terms as follows:</p>
							              <ol id="d2109e120" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d2123e124" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The term “Contracting Officer” may be changed to “Contracting Officer or Prime Contractor.”</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d2123e133" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    The term “the Government” may be changed to “the Government or Prime Contractor.”</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d2123e144" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The subcontract special terms regarding default shall include paragraph (h) of the Progress Payments clause in the contract through its subdivision(i). The rest of paragraph (h) is optional.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2123e156" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            When financing payments are in the form of performance-based payments, the Performance-Based Payments clause at <xref href="FAR-i1050610.dita#i1050610"
                        base="i1050610"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.232-32</xref> requires that the subcontract terms include the substance of the Performance-Based Payments clause, modified to indicate that the contractor, not the Government, awards the subcontract and administers the performance-based payments, and include appropriately worded modifications similar to those noted in paragraph (e) of this section.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d2123e168" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            When financing payments are in the form of commercial item purchase financing, the subcontract must include a contract financing clause structured in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1083258.dita#i1083258"
                        base="i1083258"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">32.206</xref>.</p>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
