<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1048123"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">52.242-17</ph> Government Delay of Work.</title>
		    <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p id="d3599e13" class="- topic/p ">As prescribed in <ph class="- topic/ph ">
					          <xref href="FAR-i1074542.dita#i1074542"
                     base="i1074542"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">42.1305</xref>(c)</ph>, insert the following clause in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price contract is contemplated for supplies other than commercial or modified-commercial items. The clause use is optional when a fixed-price contract is contemplated for services, or for supplies that are commercial or modified-commercial items.</p>
			      <p outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p ">Government Delay of Work (Apr 1984)</p>
			      <ol id="d3582e25" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3599e29" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            If the performance of all or any part of the work of this contract is delayed or interrupted (1)by an act of the Contracting Officer in the administration of this contract that is not expressly or impliedly authorized by this contract, or (2)by a failure of the Contracting Officer to act within the time specified in this contract, or within a reasonable time if not specified, an adjustment (excluding profit) shall be made for any increase in the cost of performance of this contract caused by the delay or interruption and the contract shall be modified in writing accordingly. Adjustment shall also be made in the delivery or performance dates and any other contractual term or condition affected by the delay or interruption. However, no adjustment shall be made under this clause for any delay or interruption to the extent that performance would have been delayed or interrupted by any other cause, including the fault or negligence of the Contractor, or for which an adjustment is provided or excluded under any other term or condition of this contract.</p>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d3599e38" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            A claim under this clause shall not be allowed-</p>
					          <ol id="d3582e44" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3599e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                For any costs incurred more than 20 days before the Contractor shall have notified the Contracting Officer in writing of the act or failure to act involved; and</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d3599e57" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Unless the claim, in an amount stated, is asserted in writing as soon as practicable after the termination of the delay or interruption, but not later than the day of final payment under the contract.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
			      <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
