<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.2"
      domains="(topic task)                            (topic concept)                            (topic concept glossentry)                            (topic concept glossgroup)                            (topic reference)                            (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)                            (topic abbrev-d)                            a(props deliveryTarget)                            (topic equation-d)                            (topic hazard-d)                            (topic hi-d)                            (topic indexing-d)                            (topic markup-d)                            (topic mathml-d)                            (topic pr-d)                            (topic relmgmt-d)                            (topic sw-d)                            (topic svg-d)                            (topic ui-d)                            (topic ut-d)                            (topic markup-d xml-d)                            (topic task strictTaskbody-c)   ">
	  <concept id="i1108639"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">15.306</ph> Exchanges with offerors after receipt of proposals.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <ol id="d896e13" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d910e17" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Clarifications and award without discussions.</p>
					          <ol id="d896e23" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e27" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Clarifications are limited exchanges, between the Government and offerors, that may occur when award without discussions is contemplated.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e36" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If award will be made without conducting discussions, offerors may be given the opportunity to clarify certain aspects of proposals (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i>the relevance of an offeror’s past performance information and adverse past performance information to which the offeror has not previously had an opportunity to respond) or to resolve minor or clerical errors.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e48" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Award may be made without discussions if the solicitation states that the Government intends to evaluate proposals and make award without discussions. If the solicitation contains such a notice and the Government determines it is necessary to conduct discussions, the rationale for doing so shall be documented in the contract file (see the provision at <xref href="FAR-i1059069.dita#i1059069"
                              base="i1059069"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.215-1</xref>) (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C.2305(b)(4)(A)(ii)</xref> and <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C. 3703(a)(2)</xref>).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d910e68" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Communications with offerors before establishment of the competitive range</i>. Communications are exchanges, between the Government and offerors, after receipt of proposals, leading to establishment of the competitive range. If a competitive range is to be established, these communications-</p>
					          <ol id="d896e77" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e81" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall be limited to the offerors described in paragraphs(b)(1)(i) and (b)(1)(ii) of this section and-</p>
							              <ol id="d896e87" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d910e91" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Shall be held with offerors whose past performance information is the determining factor preventing them from being placed within the competitive range. Such communications shall address adverse past performance information to which an offeror has not had a prior opportunity to respond; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d910e100" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    May only be held with those offerors (other than offerors under paragraph (b)(1)(i) of this section) whose exclusion from, or inclusion in, the competitive range is uncertain;</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e111" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                May be conducted to enhance Government understanding of proposals; allow reasonable interpretation of the proposal; or facilitate the Government’s evaluation process. Such communications shall not be used to cure proposal deficiencies or material omissions, materially alter the technical or cost elements of the proposal, and/or otherwise revise the proposal. Such communications may be considered in rating proposals for the purpose of establishing the competitive range;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e120" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Are for the purpose of addressing issues that must be explored to determine whether a proposal should be placed in the competitive range. Such communications shall not provide an opportunity for the offeror to revise its proposal, but may address-</p>
							              <ol id="d896e126" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d910e130" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Ambiguities in the proposal or other concerns (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> perceived deficiencies, weaknesses, errors, omissions, or mistakes (see <xref href="FAR-i1109856.dita#i1109856"
                                    base="i1109856"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">14.407</xref>)); and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d910e145" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Information relating to relevant past performance; and</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e156" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Shall address adverse past performance information to which the offeror has not previously had an opportunity to comment.</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d910e167" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            Competitive range.</p>
					          <ol id="d896e173" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e177" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Agencies shall evaluate all proposals in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1108601.dita#i1108601"
                              base="i1108601"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.305</xref>(a), and, if discussions are to be conducted, establish the competitive range. Based on the ratings of each proposal against all evaluation criteria, the contracting officer shall establish a competitive range comprised of all of the most highly rated proposals, unless the range is further reduced for purposes of efficiency pursuant to paragraph (c)(2) of this section.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e189" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                After evaluating all proposals in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1108601.dita#i1108601"
                              base="i1108601"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.305</xref>(a) and paragraph (c)(1) of this section, the contracting officer may determine that the number of most highly rated proposals that might otherwise be included in the competitive range exceeds the number at which an efficient competition can be conducted. Provided the solicitation notifies offerors that the competitive range can be limited for purposes of efficiency (see <xref href="FAR-i1059069.dita#i1059069"
                              base="i1059069"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.215-1</xref>(f)(4)), the contracting officer may limit the number of proposals in the competitive range to the greatest number that will permit an efficient competition among the most highly rated proposals (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C.2305(b)(4)</xref> and <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C.3703</xref>).</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e210" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If the contracting officer, after complying with paragraph (d)(3) of this section, decides that an offeror’s proposal should no longer be included in the competitive range, the proposal shall be eliminated from consideration for award. Written notice of this decision shall be provided to unsuccessful offerors in accordance with <xref href="FAR-i1105684.dita#i1105684"
                              base="i1105684"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.503</xref>.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e222" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Offerors excluded or otherwise eliminated from the competitive range may request a debriefing (see <xref href="FAR-i1105749.dita#i1105749"
                              base="i1105749"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.505</xref> and <xref href="FAR-i1105784.dita#i1105784"
                              base="i1105784"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.506</xref>).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d910e239" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Exchanges with offerors after establishment of the competitive range</i>. Negotiations are exchanges, in either a competitive or sole source environment, between the Government and offerors, that are undertaken with the intent of allowing the offeror to revise its proposal. These negotiations may include bargaining. Bargaining includes persuasion, alteration of assumptions and positions, give-and-take, and may apply to price, schedule, technical requirements, type of contract, or other terms of a proposed contract. When negotiations are conducted in a competitive acquisition, they take place after establishment of the competitive range and are called discussions.</p>
					          <ol id="d896e248" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e252" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Discussions are tailored to each offeror’s proposal, and must be conducted by the contracting officer with each offeror within the competitive range.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e261" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                The primary objective of discussions is to maximize the Government’s ability to obtain best value, based on the requirement and the evaluation factors set forth in the solicitation.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e270" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                At a minimum, the contracting officer must, subject to paragraphs(d)(5) and (e) of this section and <xref href="FAR-i1108714.dita#i1108714"
                              base="i1108714"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.307</xref>(a), indicate to, or discuss with, each offeror still being considered for award, deficiencies, significant weaknesses, and adverse past performance information to which the offeror has not yet had an opportunity to respond. The contracting officer also is encouraged to discuss other aspects of the offeror’s proposal that could, in the opinion of the contracting officer, be altered or explained to enhance materially the proposal’s potential for award. However, the contracting officer is not required to discuss every area where the proposal could be improved. The scope and extent of discussions are a matter of contracting officer judgment.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e282" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                In discussing other aspects of the proposal, the Government may, in situations where the solicitation stated that evaluation credit would be given for technical solutions exceeding any mandatory minimums, negotiate with offerors for increased performance beyond any mandatory minimums, and the Government may suggest to offerors that have exceeded any mandatory minimums (in ways that are not integral to the design), that their proposals would be more competitive if the excesses were removed and the offered price decreased.</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e291" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                If, after discussions have begun, an offeror originally in the competitive range is no longer considered to be among the most highly rated offerors being considered for award, that offeror may be eliminated from the competitive range whether or not all material aspects of the proposal have been discussed, or whether or not the offeror has been afforded an opportunity to submit a proposal revision (see <xref href="FAR-i1108714.dita#i1108714"
                              base="i1108714"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.307</xref>(a) and <xref href="FAR-i1105684.dita#i1105684"
                              base="i1105684"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">15.503</xref>(a)(1)).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <p id="d910e308" class="- topic/p ">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
                  
						            
						            <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Limits on exchanges</i>. Government personnel involved in the acquisition shall not engage in conduct that-</p>
					          <ol id="d896e317" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e321" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Favors one offeror over another;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e330" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Reveals an offeror’s technical solution, including unique technology, innovative and unique uses of commercial items, or any information that would compromise an offeror’s intellectual property to another offeror;</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e339" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Reveals an offeror’s price without that offeror’s permission. However, the contracting officer may inform an offeror that its price is considered by the Government to be too high, or too low, and reveal the results of the analysis supporting that conclusion. It is also permissible, at the Government’s discretion, to indicate to all offerors the cost or price that the Government’s price analysis, market research, and other reviews have identified as reasonable (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C.2102</xref> and 2107);</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e351" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Reveals the names of individuals providing reference information about an offeror’s past performance; or</p>
						            </li>
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d910e360" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Knowingly furnishes source selection information in violation of <xref href="FAR-i1124683.dita#i1124683"
                              base="i1124683"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">3.104</xref> and <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/browse.xhtml;jsessionid=114A3287C7B3359E597506A31FC855B3"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">41 U.S.C.2102</xref> and 2107).</p>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
