<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita xmlns:ditaarch="http://dita.oasis-open.org/architecture/2005/"
      domains="(topic task)              (topic concept)              (topic concept glossentry)              (topic concept glossgroup)              (topic reference)              (topic troubleshooting++task) (topic task)              (topic abbrev-d)              a(props deliveryTarget)              (topic equation-d)              (topic hazard-d)              (topic hi-d)              (topic indexing-d)              (topic markup-d)              (topic mathml-d)              (topic pr-d)              (topic relmgmt-d)              (topic sw-d)              (topic svg-d)              (topic ui-d)              (topic ut-d)              (topic markup-d xml-d)              (topic task strictTaskbody-c)  "
      ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3">
	  <concept id="i1096035"
            ditaarch:DITAArchVersion="1.3"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
		    <title class="- topic/title ">
			      <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">22.1301</ph> Definitions.</title>
		    <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
			      <p class="- topic/p ">As used in this subpart-</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Active duty wartime or campaign badge veteran” means a veteran who served on active duty in the U.S. military, ground, naval, or air service, during a war or in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized under the laws administered by the Department of Defense.</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Armed Forces service medal veteran” means any veteran who, while serving on active duty in the U.S. military, ground, naval, or air service, participated in a United States military operation for which an Armed Forces service medal was awarded pursuant to Executive Order 12985 (61 FR 1209).</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Disabled veteran” means-</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">(1) A veteran of the U.S. military, ground, naval, or air service, who is entitled to compensation (or who, but for the receipt of military retired pay, would be entitled to compensation) under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; or</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">(2) A person who was discharged or released from active duty because of a service-connected disability.</p>
			      <p class="- topic/p ">“Executive and senior management” means-</p>
			      <ol id="d1433e35" class="- topic/ol ">
				        <li class="- topic/li ">
					          <ol id="d1433e39" class="- topic/ol ">
						            <li class="- topic/li ">
							              <p id="d1447e43" class="- topic/p ">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
                        
								                Any employee-</p>
							              <ol id="d1433e49" class="- topic/ol ">
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1447e53" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Compensated on a salary basis at a rate of not less than $455 per week (or $380 per week, if employed in American Samoa by employers other than the Federal Government), exclusive of board, lodging, or other facilities;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1447e62" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Whose primary duty consists of the management of the enterprise in which the individual is employed or of a customarily recognized department or subdivision thereof;</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1447e71" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Who customarily and regularly directs the work of two or more other employees; and</p>
								                </li>
								                <li class="- topic/li ">
									                  <p id="d1447e80" class="- topic/p ">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
                              
										                    Who has the authority to hire or fire other employees or whose suggestions and recommendations as to the hiring or firing and as to the advancement and promotion or any other change of status of other employees will be given particular weight; or</p>
									                  <p id="d1447e86" class="- topic/p ">(2) Any employee who owns at least a bona fide 20-percent equity interest in the enterprise in which the employee is employed, regardless of whether the business is a corporate or other type of organization, and who is actively engaged in its management.</p>
									                  <p id="d1447e89" class="- topic/p "/>
									                  <p id="d1447e91" class="- topic/p ">“Protected veteran” means a veteran who is protected under the non-discrimination and affirmative action provisions of 38 U.S.C. 4212; specifically, a veteran who may be classified as a “disabled veteran,” “recently separated veteran,” “active duty wartime or campaign badge veteran,” or an “Armed Forces service medal veteran,” as defined by this section.</p>
									                  <p id="d1447e94" class="- topic/p ">“Qualified disabled veteran” means a disabled veteran who has the ability to perform the essential functions of the employment positions with or without reasonable accommodation.</p>
									                  <p id="d1447e98" class="- topic/p ">“Recently separated veteran” means any veteran during the three-year period beginning on the date of such veteran’s discharge or release from active duty in the U.S. military, ground, naval, or air service.</p>
									                  <p id="d1447e101" class="- topic/p ">“United States”, means the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and Wake Island.</p>
								                </li>
							              </ol>
						            </li>
					          </ol>
				        </li>
			      </ol>
		    </conbody>
	  </concept>
</dita>
