<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_11_204" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">11.204</ph> 
         Solicitation provisions.
      </title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d645e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d672e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert the provision at <xref href="52.211-1.dita#FAR_52_211_1"
                        base="i1062722"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.211-1</xref>, Availability of Specifications Listed in the GSA Index of Federal Specifications, Standards and Commercial Item Descriptions, FPMR Part 101-29, in solicitations that cite specifications listed in the Index that are not furnished with the solicitation.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d672e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> The contracting officer shall insert the provision at <xref href="52.211-2.dita#FAR_52_211_2"
                        base="i1062734"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.211-2</xref>, Availability of Defense Specifications, Standards, and Data Item Descriptions in the Acquisition Streamlining and Standardization Information System (ASSIST) website, in solicitations that cite specifications available in ASSIST that are not furnished with the solicitation. </p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d672e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert a provision substantially the same as the provision at <xref href="52.211-3.dita#FAR_52_211_3"
                        base="i1062754"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.211-3</xref>, Availability of Specifications Not Listed in the GSA Index of Federal Specifications, Standards and Commercial Item Descriptions, in solicitations that cite specifications that are not listed in the Index and are not furnished with the solicitation, but may be obtained from a designated source.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d672e34">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            The contracting officer shall insert a provision substantially the same as the provision at <xref href="52.211-4.dita#FAR_52_211_4"
                        base="i1062768"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.211-4</xref>, Availability for Examination of Specifications Not Listed in the GSA Index of Federal Specifications, Standards and Commercial Item Descriptions, in solicitations that cite specifications that are not listed in the Index and are available for examination at a specified location.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
