<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_13_306" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">13.306</ph> SF 44, Purchase Order-Invoice-Voucher.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p id="d786e8" class="- topic/p ">The <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/us-government-purchase-order-invoice-voucher"
                  format="html"
                  scope="external"
                  class="- topic/xref ">SF 44</xref>, Purchase Order-Invoice-Voucher, is a multipurpose pocket-size purchase order form designed primarily for on-the-spot, over-the-counter purchases of supplies and nonpersonal services while away from the purchasing office or at isolated activities. It also can be used as a receiving report, invoice, and public voucher.</p>
         <ol id="d765e22" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            This form may be used if all of the following conditions are satisfied:</p>
               <ol id="d765e32" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                The amount of the purchase is at or below the micro-purchase threshold, except for purchases made under unusual and compelling urgency or in support of contingency operations. Agencies may establish higher dollar limitations for specific activities or items.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                The supplies or services are immediately available.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
								                One delivery and one payment will be made.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
								                Its use is determined to be more economical and efficient than use of other simplified acquisition procedures.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e41">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            General procedural instructions governing the form’s use are printed on the form and on the inside front cover of each book of forms.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e46">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            Since there is, for all practical purposes, simultaneous placement of the order and delivery of the items, clauses are not required for purchases using this form.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d792e51">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            Agencies shall provide adequate safeguards regarding the control of forms and accounting for purchases.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
