<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_14_409_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">14.409-1</ph> Award of unclassified contracts.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d854e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d854e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e15">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                The contracting officer shall as a minimum (subject to any restrictions in <xref href="Subpart_9.4.dita#FAR_Subpart_9_4"
                              base="i1115147"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  9.4</xref>)-</p>
                     <ol id="d854e36" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e24">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
										                    Notify each unsuccessful bidder in writing or electronically within threedays after contract award, that its bid was not accepted. "Day," for purposes of the notification process, means calendar day, except that the period will run until a day which is not a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e29">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
										                    Extend appreciation for the interest the unsuccessful bidder has shown in submitting a bid; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e34">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
                              
										                    When award is made to other than a low bidder, state the reason for rejection in the notice to each of the unsuccessful low bidders.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e39">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                For acquisitions covered by the World Trade Organization Government Procurement Agreement or a Free Trade Agreement (see <xref href="25.408.dita#FAR_25_408"
                              base="i1092833"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">25.408</xref>(a)(5)), agencies must include in notices given unsuccessful bidders from World Trade Organization Government Procurement Agreement or Free Trade Agreement countries-</p>
                     <ol id="d854e78" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e48">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
										                    The dollar amount of the successful bid; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e53">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
										                    The name and address of the successful bidder.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e58">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            Information included in paragraph (a)(2) of this subsection shall be provided to any unsuccessful bidder upon request except when multiple awards have been made and furnishing information on the successful bids would require so much work as to interfere with normal operations of the contracting office. In such circumstances, only information concerning location of the abstract of offers need be given.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e63">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            When a request is received concerning an unclassified invitation from an inquirer who is neither a bidder nor a representative of a bidder, the contracting officer should make every effort to furnish the names of successful bidders and, if requested, the prices at which awards were made. However, when such requests require so much work as to interfere with the normal operations of the contracting office, the inquirer will be advised where a copy of the abstract of offers may be seen.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d881e68">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            Requests for records shall be governed by agency regulations implementing <xref href="Subpart_24.2.dita#FAR_Subpart_24_2"
                        base="i1093980"
                        outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subpart  24.2</xref>.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
