<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_14_402_3" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">14.402-3</ph> Postponement of openings.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d829e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d856e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            A bid opening may be postponed even after the time scheduled for bid opening (but otherwise in accordance with <xref href="14.208.dita#FAR_14_208"
                        base="i1110854"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">14.208</xref>) when-</p>
               <ol id="d829e26" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d856e19">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                The contracting officer has reason to believe that the bids of an important segment of bidders have been delayed in the mails, or in the communications system specified for transmission of bids, for causes beyond their control and without their fault or negligence (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> flood, fire, accident, weather conditions, strikes, or Government equipment blackout or malfunction when bids are due); or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d856e27">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Emergency or unanticipated events interrupt normal governmental processes so that the conduct of bid opening as scheduled is impractical.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d856e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            At the time of a determination to postpone a bid opening under paragraph (a)(1) of this section, an announcement of the determination shall be publicly posted. If practical before issuance of a formal amendment of the invitation, the determination shall be otherwise communicated to prospective bidders who are likely to attend the scheduled bid opening.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d856e37">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            In the case of paragraph (a)(2) of this section, and when urgent Government requirements preclude amendment of the solicitation as prescribed in <xref href="14.208.dita#FAR_14_208"
                        base="i1110854"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">14.208</xref>, the time specified for opening of bids will be deemed to be extended to the same time of day specified in the solicitation on the first work day on which normal Government processes resume. In such cases, the time of actual bid opening shall be deemed to be the time set for bid opening for the purpose of determining "late bids" under <xref href="14.304.dita#FAR_14_304"
                        base="i1110200"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">14.304</xref>. A note should be made on the abstract of bids or otherwise added to the file explaining the circumstances of the postponement.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
