<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_15_504" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">15.504</ph> Award to successful offeror.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">The contracting officer shall award a contract to the successful offeror by furnishing the executed contract or other notice of the award to that offeror.</p>
         <ol id="d930e16" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d958e12">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            If the award document includes information that is different than the latest signed proposal, as amended by the offeror’s written correspondence, both the offeror and the contracting officer shall sign the contract award.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d958e17">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            When an award is made to an offeror for less than all of the items that may be awarded and additional items are being withheld for subsequent award, each notice shall state that the Government may make subsequent awards on those additional items within the proposal acceptance period.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d958e22">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            If the Optional Form (OF) 307, Contract Award, <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/awardcontract"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">Standard Form (SF) 26</xref>, Award/Contract, or <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/solicitation-offer-and-award"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">SF 33</xref>, Solicitation, Offer and Award, is not used to award the contract, the first page of the award document shall contain the Government’s acceptance statement from Block 15 of that form, exclusive of the Item 3 reference language, and shall contain the contracting officer’s name, signature, and date. In addition, if the award document includes information that is different than the signed proposal, as amended by the offeror’s written correspondence, the first page shall include the contractor’s agreement statement from Block14 of the OF 307 and the signature of the contractor’s authorized representative.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
