<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_16_203_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">16.203-1</ph> Description.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d964e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d992e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            A fixed-price contract with economic price adjustment provides for upward and downward revision of the stated contract price upon the occurrence of specified contingencies. Economic price adjustments are of three general types:</p>
               <ol id="d964e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d992e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Adjustments based on established prices.</i> These price adjustments are based on increases or decreases from an agreed-upon level in published or otherwise established prices of specific items or the contract end items.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d992e23">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Adjustments based on actual costs of labor or material</i>. These price adjustments are based on increases or decreases in specified costs of labor or material that the contractor actually experiences during contract performance.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d992e30">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Adjustments based on cost indexes of labor or material</i>. These price adjustments are based on increases or decreases in labor or material cost standards or indexes that are specifically identified in the contract.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d992e37">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            The contracting officer may use a fixed-price contract with economic price adjustment in conjunction with an award-fee incentive (see <xref href="16.404.dita#FAR_16_404"
                        base="i1104523"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">16.404</xref>) and performance or delivery incentives (see <xref href="16.402-2.dita#FAR_16_402_2"
                        base="i1104460"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">16.402-2</xref> and <xref href="16.402-3.dita#FAR_16_402_3"
                        base="i1104470"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">16.402-3</xref>) when the award fee or incentive is based solely on factors other than cost. The contract type remains fixed-price with economic price adjustment when used with these incentives.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
