<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_19_1503" xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">19.1503</ph> 
         Status.
      </title>
      <conbody>
         <ol id="d1251e13">
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1286e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  Status as an EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program is determined by the Small Business Administration in accordance with <xref href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/part-127"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external">13 CFR part 127</xref>.
               </p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1286e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> For a WOSB that seeks a WOSB or EDWOSB set-aside or sole-source contract, the contracting officer shall verify that the offeror—</p>
               <ol id="d1251e32">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1286e24">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Is registered in the System for Award Management (SAM); and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1286e29">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Is designated as a certified EDWOSB or WOSB concern in SAM (see 19.1505(d) for set aside procedures). Pending applications for certification are only in the Dynamic Small Business Search (DSBS) at <i>
                           <xref href="https://web.sba.gov/pro-net/search/dsp_dsbs.cfm"
                                 format="html"
                                 scope="external">https://web.sba.gov/​pro-net/​search/​dsp_​dsbs.cfm</xref>.</i>
                     </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1286e39">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> If there is a decision issued by SBA as a result of a current eligibility examination finding that the concern did not qualify as an EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program, the contracting officer may terminate the contract, and shall not exercise any option, or award further task or delivery orders. Agencies shall not count or include the award toward the small business goals for an EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program and must update FPDS from the date of award to reflect the final SBA decision. </p>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1286e114">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> A joint venture may be considered an EDWOSB concern or WOSB concern eligible under the WOSB Program if the EDWOSB or WOSB participant is certified in SAM (see section 19.1505(d) for set-aside procedures) and the joint venture meets the requirements of <xref href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.506"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external">13 CFR 127.506</xref>. </p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p> </p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
