<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_19_201" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">19.201</ph> General policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1130e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> It is the policy of the Government
to provide maximum practicable opportunities in its acquisitions
to small business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled
veteran-owned small business, HUBZone small business, small disadvantaged
business, and women-owned small business concerns. Such concerns
must also have the maximum practicable opportunity to participate
as subcontractors in the contracts awarded by any executive agency,
consistent with efficient contract performance. The Small Business
Administration (SBA) counsels and assists small business concerns
and assists contracting personnel to ensure that a fair proportion
of contracts for supplies and services is placed with small business.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> Heads of
contracting activities are responsible for effectively implementing
the small business programs within their activities, including achieving
program goals. They are to ensure that contracting and technical
personnel maintain knowledge of small business program requirements
and take all reasonable action to increase participation in their
activities’ contracting processes by these businesses.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> The Small
Business Act requires each agency with contracting authority to
establish an Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization
(see section 15(k) of the Small Business Act). For the Department
of Defense, in accordance with section 904 of <xref href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/PLAW-109publ163/html/PLAW-109publ163.htm"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">Public Law 109-163</xref> (<xref href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title10-section144&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C. 144</xref> note),
the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization has been
redesignated as the Office of Small Business Programs. Management
of the office is the responsibility of an officer or employee of
the agency who, in carrying out the purposes of the Act—</p>
               <ol id="d1130e44" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e32">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Is
known as the Director of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business
Utilization, or for the Department of Defense, the Director of the Office of
Small Business Programs;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e37">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>Is appointed
by the agency head;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e42">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Is responsible
to and reports directly to the agency head or the deputy to the
agency head (except that for the Department of Defense, the Director
of the Office of Small Business Programs reports to the Secretary
or the Secretary’s designee);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>Is responsible
for the agency carrying out the functions and duties in sections
8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small Business Act;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e52">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph> Works with
the SBA procurement center representative (PCR) (or, if a PCR is
not assigned, see <xref href="19.402.dita#FAR_19_402"
                              base="i1101041"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.402</xref>(a))
to identify proposed solicitations that involve bundling and work
with the agency acquisition officials and SBA to revise the acquisition
strategies for such proposed solicitations to increase the probability
of participation by small businesses;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e60">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>Assists
small business concerns in obtaining payments under their contracts,
late payment interest penalties, or information on contractual payment
provisions;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e65">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph> Has supervisory
authority over agency personnel to the extent that their functions
and duties relate to sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44 of the Small
Business Act;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e70">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>Assigns
a small business technical advisor to each contracting activity
within the agency to which the SBA has assigned a representative
(see 19.402)—</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e76">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>Who
is a full-time employee of the contracting activity, well qualified,
technically trained, and familiar with the supplies or services
contracted for by the activity; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e81">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>Whose principal
duty is to assist the SBA's assigned representative in performing
functions and duties relating to sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44
of the Small Business Act;</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e86">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(9)</ph> Cooperates
and consults on a regular basis with the SBA in carrying out the
agency's functions and duties in sections 8, 15, 31, 36, and 44
of the Small Business Act;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e91">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(10)</ph> Makes recommendations in
                        accordance with agency procedures as to whether a
                        particular acquisition should be awarded under subpart <xref href="Subpart_19.5.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_5" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.5</xref> as a small
                        business set-aside, under subpart <xref href="Subpart_19.8.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_8" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.8</xref> as a section
                        8(a) award, under subpart <xref href="Subpart_19.13.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_13"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.13</xref> as a HUBZone
                        set-aside, under subpart <xref href="Subpart_19.14.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_14"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.14</xref> as a
                        set-aside
                        service-disabled veteran-owned small business (SDVOSB) concerns
                        eligible under the SDVOSB Program, or under subpart <xref href="Subpart_19.15.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_15"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">19.15</xref> as a set-aside
                        for economically disadvantaged women-owned small
                        business (EDWOSB) concerns or women-owned small business
                        (WOSB) concerns eligible under the WOSB Program;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e96">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(11)</ph> Conducts
annual reviews to assess the—</p>
                     <ol id="d1130e218" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e102">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Extent to
which small businesses are receiving a fair share of Federal procurements,
including contract opportunities under the programs administered
under the Small Business Act;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e107">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Adequacy
of consolidated or bundled contract documentation and justifications;
and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e112">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph> Actions
taken to mitigate the effects of necessary and justified consolidation
or bundling on small businesses.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e118">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(12)</ph> Provides
a copy of the assessment made under paragraph (c)(11) of this section
to the Agency Head and SBA Administrator;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e123">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(13)</ph>Provides
to the chief acquisition officer and senior procurement executive
advice and comments on acquisition strategies, market research,
and justifications related to consolidation of contract requirements;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e128">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(14)</ph> When
notified by a small business concern prior to the award of a contract
that the small business concern believes that a solicitation, request
for proposal, or request for quotation unduly restricts the ability
of the small business concern to compete for the award–</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e134">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Submits the
notification by the small business concern to the contracting officer
and, if necessary, recommends ways in which the solicitation, request
for proposal, or request for quotation may be altered to increase
the opportunity for competition; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e139">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Informs the advocate for competition of such agency (as established under 41 U.S.C 1705 or 
                                 <xref href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title10-section3249&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                                    format="html"
                                    scope="external"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">10 U.S.C. 3249</xref>) of such notification;</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e150">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(15)</ph> Ensures
agency purchases using the Governmentwide purchase card that are
greater than the micro-purchase threshold and less than the simplified
acquisition threshold were made in compliance with the Small Business
Act and were properly recorded in accordance with <xref href="Subpart_4.6.dita#FAR_Subpart_4_6"
                              base="i1122770"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  4.6</xref> in the
Federal Procurement Data System;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e158">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(16)</ph> Assists
small business contractors and subcontractors in finding resources
for education and training on compliance with contracting regulations;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e163">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(17)</ph> Reviews
all subcontracting plans required by <xref href="19.702.dita#FAR_19_702"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.702</xref>(a)
to ensure the plan provides maximum practicable opportunity for
small business concerns to participate in the performance of the
contract; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e171">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(18)</ph> Performs
other duties listed at <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title15-section644(k)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              scope="external"
                              format="html">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e179">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> Small
business specialists shall be appointed and act in accordance with
agency regulations.</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e185">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> The contracting activity shall
coordinate with the small business specialist as early in the acquisition
planning process as practicable, but no later than 30 days before
the issuance of a solicitation, or prior to placing an order without a
solicitation when the acquisition meets the dollar thresholds set
forth at <xref href="7.107-4.dita#FAR_7_107_4"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.107-4</xref>(a)(1). See also <xref href="7.104.dita#FAR_7_104"
                              base="i1118917"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.104</xref>(d).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e196">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The small
business specialist shall notify the agency's Director of the Office
of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization, and for the Department
of Defense, the Director of the Office of Small Business Programs,
when the criteria relating to substantial bundling at <xref href="7.107-4.dita#FAR_7_107_4"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.107-4</xref>(a)(1)
are met.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1159e204">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> The small
business specialist shall coordinate with the contracting activity
and the SBA PCR on all determinations and findings required by <xref href="7.107.dita#FAR_7_107"
                              base="i1119141"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">7.107</xref> for consolidation
or bundling of contract requirements.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
