<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_19_708" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">19.708</ph> Contract clauses.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1193e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						             Insert the clause at <xref href="52.219-8.dita#FAR_52_219_8"
                        base="i1057444"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.219-8</xref>, Utilization of Small Business Concerns, in solicitations and contracts when the contract amount is expected to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold unless-</p>
               <ol id="d1193e26" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e19">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                 A personal services contract is contemplated (see <xref href="37.104.dita#FAR_37_104"
                              base="i1077856"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">37.104</xref>); or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e27">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                 The contract, together with all of its subcontracts, will be performed entirely outside of the United States and its outlying areas.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d1193e59" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e37">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Insert the clause at <xref href="52.219-9.dita#FAR_52_219_9"
                              base="i1057444"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.219-9</xref>, Small Business Subcontracting Plan, in solicitations and contracts that offer subcontracting possibilities, are expected to exceed <ph rev="FAC 2025-06 October 1, 2025" class="- topic/ph "><?FM MARKER [CaseNumber] FAR Case 2024-001?>$900,000 ($2 million<?FM MARKER [Why] Amend section 19.708 in paragraph (b)(1) by removing “$750,000 ($1.5 million” and adding “$900,000 ($2 million” in its place.?></ph> for construction of any public facility), and are required to include the clause at <xref href="52.219-8.dita#FAR_52_219_8"
                              base="i1057444"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.219-8</xref>, Utilization of Small Business Concerns, unless the acquisition is set aside or is to be accomplished under the 8(a) program. When-</p>
                     <ol id="d1193e79" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e49">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
										                     Contracting by sealed bidding rather than by negotiation, the contracting officer shall use the clause with its Alternate I;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e54">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
										                     Contracting by negotiation, and subcontracting plans are required with initial proposals as provided for in <xref href="19.705-2.dita#FAR_19_705_2"
                                    base="i1100344"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">19.705-2</xref>(d), the contracting officer shall use the clause with its Alternate II;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e62">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph>
										                     The contract action will not be reported in the Federal Procurement Data System pursuant to <xref href="4.606.dita#FAR_4_606"
                                    base="i1122901"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">4.606</xref>(c)(5), or (c)(6), the contracting officer shall use the clause with its Alternate III; or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e70">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph>
										                     Incorporating a subcontracting plan due to a modification as provided for in <xref href="19.702.dita#FAR_19_702"
                                    base="i1100224"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">19.702</xref>(a)(1)(iii), the contracting officer shall use the clause with its Alternate IV.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e78">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                 Insert the clause at <xref href="52.219-16.dita#FAR_52_219_16"
                              base="i1057758"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.219-16</xref>, Liquidated Damages-Subcontracting Plan, in all solicitations and contracts containing the clause at <xref href="52.219-9.dita#FAR_52_219_9"
                              base="i1057444"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.219-9</xref>, Small Business Subcontracting Plan, or the clause with its Alternate I, II, III, or IV.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e89">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d1193e161" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e94">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                 The contracting officer may, when contracting by negotiation, insert in solicitations and contracts a clause substantially the same as the clause at <xref href="52.219-10.dita#FAR_52_219_10"
                              base="i1057667"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.219-10</xref>, Incentive Subcontracting Program, when a subcontracting plan is required (see <xref href="19.702.dita#FAR_19_702"
                              base="i1100224"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">19.702</xref>), and inclusion of a monetary incentive is, in the judgment of the contracting officer, necessary to increase subcontracting opportunities for small business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled veteran-owned small business, HUBZone small business, small disadvantaged business, and women-owned small business concerns, and is commensurate with the efficient and economical performance of the contract; unless the conditions in paragraph (c)(3) of this section are applicable. The contracting officer may vary the terms of the clause as specified in paragraph (c)(2) of this section.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e105">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                 Various approaches may be used in the development of small business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled veteran-owned small business, HUBZone small business, small disadvantaged business, and women-owned small business concerns’ subcontracting incentives. They can take many forms, from a fully quantified schedule of payments based on actual subcontract achievement to an award-fee approach employing subjective evaluation criteria (see paragraph (c)(3) of this section). The incentive should not reward the contractor for results other than those that are attributable to the contractor’s efforts under the incentive subcontracting program.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1225e110">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                 As specified in paragraph (c)(2) of this section, the contracting officer may include small business, veteran-owned small business, service-disabled veteran-owned small business, HUBZone small business, small disadvantaged business, and women-owned small business subcontracting as one of the factors to be considered in determining the award fee in a cost-plus-award-fee contract; in such cases, however, the contracting officer shall not use the clause at <xref href="52.219-10.dita#FAR_52_219_10"
                              base="i1057667"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.219-10</xref>, Incentive Subcontracting Program.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
