<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_1008_2" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">22.1008-2</ph> Successorship with
incumbent contractor collective bargaining agreement.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1387e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> Early in the acquisition cycle,
the contracting officer shall determine whether <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> affects
the new acquisition. The contracting officer shall determine whether
there is a predecessor contract covered by the Service Contract Labor
Standards statute and, if so, whether the incumbent prime contractor
or its subcontractors and any of their employees have a collective
bargaining agreement.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> provides
that a successor contractor must pay wages and fringe benefits (including
accrued wages and benefits and prospective increases) to service
employees at least equal to those agreed upon by a predecessor contractor under
the following conditions:</p>
               <ol id="d1387e38" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> The services to be furnished under
the proposed contract will be substantially the same as services
being furnished by an incumbent contractor whose contract the proposed
contract will succeed.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The services
will be performed in the same locality.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> The incumbent
prime contractor or subcontractor is furnishing such services through
the use of service employees whose wages and fringe benefits are
the subject of one or more collective bargaining agreements.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e41">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> The application
of <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> is
subject to the following limitations:</p>
               <ol id="d1387e80" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e50">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              scope="external"
                              format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> will
not apply if the incumbent contractor enters into a collective bargaining
agreement for the first time and the agreement does not become effective
until after the expiration of the incumbent’s contract.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e57">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> If the
incumbent contractor enters into a new or revised collective bargaining
agreement during the period of the incumbent’s performance on the
current contract, the terms of the new or revised agreement shall
not be effective for the purposes of <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              scope="external"
                              format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> under
the following conditions:</p>
                     <ol id="d1387e105" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e66">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                           </p>
                           <ol id="d1387e115" class="- topic/ol ">
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e71">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(A)</ph> In
sealed bidding, the contracting agency receives notice of the terms
of the collective bargaining agreement less than 10 days before
bid opening and finds that there is not reasonable time still available
to notify bidders (see <xref href="22.1012-2.dita#FAR_22_1012_2"
                                          outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">22.1012-2</xref>(a)); or</p>
                              </li>
                              <li class="- topic/li ">
                                 <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e79">
                                    <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(B)</ph> For contractual
actions other than sealed bidding, the contracting agency receives
notice of the terms of the collective bargaining agreement after
award, provided that the start of performance is within 30 days
of award (see <xref href="22.1012-2.dita#FAR_22_1012_2"
                                          outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                          class="- topic/xref ">22.1012-2</xref>(b)); and</p>
                              </li>
                           </ol>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e87">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> The contracting
officer has given both the incumbent contractor and its employees’
collective bargaining agent timely written notification of the applicable
acquisition dates (see <xref href="22.1010.dita#FAR_22_1010"
                                    base="i1096936"
                                    outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                                    class="- topic/xref ">22.1010</xref>).</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e95">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d1387e170" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e100">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> If <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              scope="external"
                              format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> applies,
the contracting officer shall obtain a copy of any collective bargaining
agreement between an incumbent contractor or subcontractor and its
employees. Obtaining a copy of an incumbent contractor’s collective
bargaining agreement may involve coordination with the administrative
contracting officer responsible for administering the predecessor
contract. (Paragraph (m) of the clause at <xref href="52.222-41.dita#FAR_52_222_41"
                              base="i1056332"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.222-41</xref>, Service Contract
Labor Standards, requires the incumbent prime contractor to furnish
the contracting officer a copy of each collective bargaining agreement.)</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e111">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> If the
contracting officer has timely received the collective bargaining
agreement, the contracting officer may use the Wage Determinations at <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">SAM.gov</i>
                         website
to prepare a wage determination referencing the agreement and incorporate
that wage determination, attached to a complete copy of the collective
bargaining agreement, into the successor contract action. In using
the Wage Determinations
at <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">SAM.gov</i>
                         process, it is not necessary to submit a
copy of the collective bargaining agreement to the Department of
Labor unless requested to do so.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e122">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> The contracting
officer may also use the e98 process on Wage Determinations at <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">SAM.gov</i>
                         to
request that the Department of Labor prepare the cover wage determination.
The Department of Labor’s response to the e98 may include a request
for the contracting officer to submit a complete copy of the collective
bargaining agreement. Any questions regarding the applicability
of the Service Contract Labor Standards statute to a collective
bargaining agreement should be directed to the agency labor advisor.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e130">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d1387e215" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e135">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title41-section6707(c)&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                              scope="external"
                              format="html">41 U.S.C. 6707(c)</xref> will
not apply if the Secretary of Labor determines (i) after a hearing,
that the wages and fringe benefits in the predecessor contractor’s
collective bargaining agreement are substantially at variance with
those which prevail for services of a similar character in the locality,
or (ii) that the wages and fringe benefits in the predecessor contractor’s
collective bargaining agreement are not the result of arm’s length
negotiations (see <xref href="22.1013.dita#FAR_22_1013"
                              base="i1096985"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">22.1013</xref> and <xref href="22.1021.dita#FAR_22_1021"
                              base="i1097053"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">22.1021</xref>). The Department
of Labor (DOL) has concluded that contingent collective bargaining
agreement provisions that attempt to limit a contractor’s obligations
by means such as requiring issuance of a wage determination by the
DOL, requiring inclusion of the wage determination in the contract,
or requiring the Government to adequately reimburse the contractor,
generally reflect a lack of arm’s length negotiations.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e148">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> If the
contracting officer’s review (see <xref href="22.1013.dita#FAR_22_1013"
                              base="i1096985"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">22.1013</xref>) indicates that
monetary provisions of the collective bargaining agreement may be
substantially at variance or may not have been reached as a result
of arm’s length bargaining, the contracting officer shall immediately
contact the agency labor advisor to consider if further action is
warranted.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e156">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph> If the
services are being furnished at more than one location and the collectively
bargained wage rates and fringe benefits are different at different
locations or do not apply to one or more locations, the contracting
officer shall identify the locations to which the agreements apply.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e161">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph> If the
collective bargaining agreement does not apply to all service employees
under the contract, the contracting officer shall access Wage Determinations at <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">SAM.gov</i>
                   to
obtain the prevailing wage determination for those service employee classifications
that are not covered by the collective bargaining agreement. The
contracting officer shall separately list in the solicitation and
contract the service employee classifications-</p>
               <ol id="d1387e267" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e170">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Subject
to the collective bargaining agreement; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1423e175">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Not subject
to any collective bargaining agreement.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
