<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_22_1021" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">22.1021</ph> Request for hearing.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1406e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            A contracting agency or other interested party may request a hearing on an issue presented in <xref href="22.1013.dita#FAR_22_1013"
                        base="i1096985"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">22.1013</xref>(a). To obtain a hearing for the contracting agency, the contracting officer shall submit a written request through appropriate channels (ordinarily the agency labor advisor) to—</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e17">Administrator, Wage and Hour Division </p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e19">U.S. Department of Labor</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e21">Washington, DC 20210</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e24">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            A request for a substantial variance hearing shall include sufficient data to show that the rates at issue vary substantially from those prevailing for similar services in the locality. The request shall also include-</p>
               <ol id="d1406e38" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e30">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                The number of the wage determinations at issue;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e35">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                The name of the contracting agency whose contract is involved;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e40">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                A brief description of the services to be performed under the contract;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e45">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
								                The status of the procurement and any estimated procurement dates, such as bid opening, contract award, and commencement date of the contract or its follow-up option period;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e50">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
								                A statement of the applicant’s case, setting forth in detail the reasons why the applicant believes that a substantial variance exists with respect to some or all of the wages and/or fringe benefits;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e55">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
								                Names and addresses (to the extent known) of interested parties; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e60">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
								                Any other data required by the Administrator.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e65">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            A request for an arm’s length hearing shall include-</p>
               <ol id="d1406e114" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e71">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                A statement of the applicant’s case, setting forth in detail the reasons why the applicant believes that the wages and fringe benefits contained in the collective bargaining agreement were not reached as a result of arm’s length negotiations;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e76">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                A statement regarding the status of the procurement and any estimated procurement dates, such as bid opening, contract award, and commencement date of the contract or its follow-up option period; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e81">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                Names and addresses (to the extent known) of interested parties.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e86">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            Unless the Administrator determines that extraordinary circumstances exist, the Administrator will not consider requests for a hearing unless received as follows:</p>
               <ol id="d1406e153" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e92">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                For sealed bid contracts, more than 10 days before the award of the contract; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1442e97">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                For negotiated contracts and for contracts with provisions exceeding the initial term by option, before the commencement date of the contract or the follow-up option period.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
