<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_24_102" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">24.102</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1577e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1599e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The Act requires that when an agency contracts for the design, development, or operation of a system of records on individuals on behalf of the agency to accomplish an agency function the agency must apply the requirements of the Act to the contractor and its employees working on the contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1599e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            An agency officer or employee may be criminally liable for violations of the Act. When the contract provides for operation of a system of records on individuals, contractors and their employees are considered employees of the agency for purposes of the criminal penalties of the Act.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1599e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            If a contract specifically provides for the design, development, or operation of a system of records on individuals on behalf of an agency to accomplish an agency function, the agency must apply the requirements of the Act to the contractor and its employees working on the contract. The system of records operated under the contract is deemed to be maintained by the agency and is subject to the Act.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1599e25">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            Agencies, which within the limits of their authorities, fail to require that systems of records on individuals operated on their behalf under contracts be operated in conformance with the Act may be civilly liable to individuals injured as a consequence of any subsequent failure to maintain records in conformance with the Act.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
