<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_25_1002" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">25.1002</ph> Use of foreign currency.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1673e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1695e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Unless an international agreement or the WTO GPA (see <xref href="25.408.dita#FAR_25_408"
                        base="i1092833"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">25.408</xref>(a)(4)) requires a specific currency, contracting officers must determine whether solicitations for contracts to be entered into and performed outside the United States will require submission of offers in U.S. currency or a specified foreign currency. In unusual circumstances, the contracting officer may permit submission of offers in other than a specified currency.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1695e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            To ensure a fair evaluation of offers, solicitations generally should require all offers to be priced in the same currency. However, if the solicitation permits submission of offers in other than a specified currency, the contracting officer must convert the offered prices to U.S. currency for evaluation purposes. The contracting officer must use the current market exchange rate from a commonly used source in effect as follows:</p>
               <ol id="d1673e35" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1695e24">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                For acquisitions conducted using sealed bidding procedures, on the date of bid opening.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1695e29">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                For acquisitions conducted using negotiation procedures-</p>
                     <ol id="d1673e54" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1695e35">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
										                    On the date specified for receipt of offers, if award is based on initial offers; otherwise</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d1695e40">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
										                    On the date specified for receipt of final proposal revisions.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1695e45">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            If a contract is priced in foreign currency, the agency must ensure that adequate funds are available to cover currency fluctuations to avoid a violation of the Anti-Deficiency Act (31 U.S.C. 1341, 1342, 1511-1519).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
