<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_27_203_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">27.203-1</ph> General.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1727e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1750e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Unauthorized disclosure of classified subject matter, whether in patent applications or resulting from the issuance of a patent, may be a violation of <xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title18-section792&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">18 U.S.C. 792</xref>, <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">et seq</i>. (Chapter 37-Espionage and Censorship), and related statutes, and may be contrary to the interests of national security.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1750e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Upon receipt of a patent application under paragraph (a) or (b) of the clause at <xref href="52.227-10.dita#FAR_52_227_10"
                        base="i1052317"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.227-10</xref>, Filing of Patent Applications-Classified Subject Matter, the contracting officer shall ascertain the proper security classification of the patent application. If the application contains classified subject matter, the contracting officer shall inform the contractor how to transmit the application to the United States Patent Office in accordance with procedures provided by legal counsel. If the material is classified "Secret" or higher, the contracting officer shall make every effort to notify the contractor within 30 days of the Government’s determination, pursuant to paragraph (a) of the clause.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1750e29">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            Upon receipt of information furnished by the contractor under paragraph (d) of the clause at <xref href="52.227-10.dita#FAR_52_227_10"
                        base="i1052317"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.227-10</xref>, the contracting officer shall promptly submit that information to legal counsel in order that the steps necessary to ensure the security of the application will be taken.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1750e37">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            The contracting officer shall act promptly on requests for approval of foreign filing under paragraph (c) of the clause at <xref href="52.227-10.dita#FAR_52_227_10"
                        base="i1052317"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.227-10</xref> in order to avoid the loss of valuable patent rights of the Government or the contractor.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
