<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_27_402" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">27.402</ph> Policy.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d1751e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1774e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            To carry out their missions and programs, agencies acquire or obtain access to many kinds of data produced during or used in the performance of their contracts. Agencies require data to-</p>
               <ol id="d1751e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1774e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Obtain competition among suppliers;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1774e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Fulfill certain responsibilities for disseminating and publishing the results of their activities;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1774e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                Ensure appropriate utilization of the results of research, development, and demonstration activities including the dissemination of technical information to foster subsequent technological developments;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1774e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
								                Meet other programmatic and statutory requirements; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d1774e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
								                Meet specialized acquisition needs and ensure logistics support.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d1774e41">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Contractors may have proprietary interests in data. In order to prevent the compromise of these interests, agencies shall protect proprietary data from unauthorized use and disclosure. The protection of such data is also necessary to encourage qualified contractors to participate in and apply innovative concepts to Government programs. In light of these considerations, agencies shall balance the Government’s needs and the contractor’s legitimate proprietary interests.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
