<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_32_112_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">32.112-1</ph> Subcontractor assertions of nonpayment.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2029e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> In accordance with Section 806(a)(4) of Pub.L.102-190, as amended by Sections2091 and 8105 of Pub.L.103-355 (<xref href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title10-section4601&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        format="html"
                        scope="external">10 U.S.C. 4601 note</xref> prec.), upon the assertion by a subcontractor or supplier of a Federal contractor that the subcontractor or supplier has not been paid in accordance with the payment terms of the subcontract, purchase order, or other agreement with the prime contractor, the contracting officer may determine-</p>
               <ol id="d2029e26" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e19">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                For a construction contract, whether the contractor has made-</p>
                     <ol id="d2029e36" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e25">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
										                    Progress payments to the subcontractor or supplier in compliance with Chapter 39 of Title 31, United States Code (Prompt Payment Act); or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e30">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
										                    Final payment to the subcontractor or supplier in compliance with the terms of the subcontract, purchase order, or other agreement with the prime contractor;</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e35">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                For a contract other than construction, whether the contractor has made progress payments, final payments, or other payments to the subcontractor or supplier in compliance with the terms of the subcontract, purchase order, or other agreement with the prime contractor; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e40">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                For any contract, whether the contractor’s certification of payment of a subcontractor or supplier accompanying its payment request to the Government is accurate.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e45">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            If, in making the determination in paragraphs (a)(1) and (2) of this subsection, the contracting officer finds the prime contractor is not in compliance, the contracting officer may-</p>
               <ol id="d2029e86" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e51">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Encourage the contractor to make timely payment to the subcontractor or supplier; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e56">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                If authorized by the applicable payment clauses, reduce or suspend progress payments to the contractor.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2054e61">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            If the contracting officer determines that a certification referred to in paragraph (a)(3) of this subsection is inaccurate in any material respect, the contracting officer shall initiate administrative or other remedial action.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
