<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_32_503_3" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">32.503-3</ph> Initiation of progress payments and review of accounting system.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2095e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2120e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            For contractors that the administrative contracting officer (ACO) has found by previous experience or recent audit review (within the last 12 months) to be-</p>
               <ol id="d2095e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2120e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                Reliable, competent, and capable of satisfactory performance;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2120e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Possessed of an adequate accounting system and controls; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2120e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                In sound financial condition, progress payments in amounts requested by the contractor should be approved as a matter of course.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2120e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            For all other contractors, the ACO shall not approve progress payments before determining (1) that (i) the contractor will be capable of liquidating any progress payments or (ii) the Government is otherwise protected against loss by additional protective provisions, and (2) that the contractor’s accounting system and controls are adequate for proper administration of progress payments. The services of the responsible audit agency or office should be used to the greatest extent practicable. However, if the auditor so advises, a complete audit may not be necessary.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
