<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_36_501" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">36.501</ph> Performance of work by the contractor.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2299e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2324e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> To assure adequate interest in and supervision of all work involved in larger projects, the contractor shall be required to perform a significant part of the contract work with its own forces. The contract shall express this requirement in terms of a percentage that reflects the minimum amount of work the contractor must perform with its own forces. This percentage is (1) as high as the contracting officer considers appropriate for the project, consistent with customary or necessary specialty subcontracting and the complexity and magnitude of the work, and (2) ordinarily not less than 12 percent unless a greater percentage is required by law or agency regulation. Specialties such as plumbing, heating, and electrical work are usually subcontracted, and should not normally be considered in establishing the amount of work required to be performed by the contractor.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2324e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> The contracting officer shall insert the clause at <xref href="52.236-1.dita#FAR_52_236_1"
                        base="i1048785"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.236-1</xref>, Performance of Work by the Contractor, in solicitations and contracts, except those awarded pursuant to <xref href="Subpart_19.5.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_5"
                        base="i1100723"
                        outputclass="fm:Subparts"
                        class="- topic/xref ">subparts 19.5</xref>, <xref href="Subpart_19.8.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_8"
                        base="i1099848"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.8</xref>, <xref href="Subpart_19.13.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_13"
                        base="i1099552"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.13</xref>, <xref href="Subpart_19.14.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_14"
                        base="i1099391"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.14</xref>, or <xref href="Subpart_19.15.dita#FAR_Subpart_19_15"
                        base="i1099174"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.15</xref> when a fixed-price construction contract is contemplated and the contract amount is expected to exceed <ph rev="FAC 2025-06 October 1, 2025" class="- topic/ph ">$2 million</ph>. The contracting officer may insert the clause in solicitations and contracts when a fixed-price construction contract is contemplated and the contract amount is expected to be <ph rev="FAC 2025-06 October 1, 2025" class="- topic/ph "><?FM MARKER [CaseNumber] FAR Case 2024-001?>$2 million<?FM MARKER [Why] Amend section 36.501 in paragraph (b) by removing “$1.5 million” wherever it appears and adding “$2 million” in their places, respectively.?></ph> or less.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
