<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_36_602_5" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">36.602-5</ph> Short selection process for contracts not to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p id="d2364e8" class="- topic/p ">When authorized by the agency, either or both of the short processes described in this subsection may be used to select firms for contracts not expected to exceed the simplified acquisition threshold. Otherwise, the procedures prescribed in <xref href="36.602-3.dita#FAR_36_602_3"
                  base="i1078384"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">36.602-3</xref> and <xref href="36.602-4.dita#FAR_36_602_4"
                  base="i1078397"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">36.602-4</xref> shall be followed.</p>
         <ol id="d2334e28" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2359e18">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Selection by the board.</i> The board shall review and evaluate architect-engineer firms in accordance with <xref href="36.602-3.dita#FAR_36_602_3"
                        base="i1078384"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">36.602-3</xref>, except that the selection report shall serve as the final selection list and shall be provided directly to the contracting officer. The report shall serve as an authorization for the contracting officer to commence negotiations in accordance with <xref href="36.606.dita#FAR_36_606"
                        base="i1078482"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">36.606</xref>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2359e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Selection by the chairperson of the board.</i> When the board decides that formal action by the board is not necessary in connection with a particular selection, the following procedures shall be followed:</p>
               <ol id="d2334e59" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2359e39">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                The chairperson of the board shall perform the functions required in <xref href="36.602-3.dita#FAR_36_602_3"
                              base="i1078384"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">36.602-3</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2359e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                The agency head or designated selection authority shall review the report and approve it or return it to the chairperson for appropriate revision.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2359e52">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
								                Upon receipt of an approved report, the chairperson of the board shall furnish the contracting officer a copy of the report which will serve as an authorization for the contracting officer to commence negotiations in accordance with <xref href="36.606.dita#FAR_36_606"
                              base="i1078482"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">36.606</xref>.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
