<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_4_403" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">4.403</ph> Responsibilities of contracting officers.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d210e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Presolicitation phase</i>. Contracting officers shall review all proposed solicitations to determine whether access to classified information may be required by offerors, or by a contractor during contract performance.</p>
               <ol id="d210e26" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e18">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                If access to classified information of another agency may be required, the contracting officer shall-</p>
                     <ol id="d210e36" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e24">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
										                    Determine if the agency is covered by the NISP; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e29">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
										                    Follow that agency’s procedures for determining the security clearances of firms to be solicited.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e34">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                If the classified information required is from the contracting officer’s agency, the contracting officer shall follow agency procedures.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e39">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Solicitation phase</i>. Contracting officers shall-</p>
               <ol id="d210e80" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e47">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Ensure that the classified acquisition is conducted as required by the NISP or agency procedures, as appropriate; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e52">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Include-</p>
                     <ol id="d210e99" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e58">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
										                    An appropriate Security Requirements clause in the solicitation (see 4.404); and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e63">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
										                    As appropriate, in solicitations and contracts when the contract may require access to classified information, a requirement for security safeguards in addition to those provided in the clause (52.204-2, Security Requirements).</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e68">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Award phase</i>. Contracting officers shall inform contractors and subcontractors of the security classifications and requirements assigned to the various documents, materials, tasks, subcontracts, and components of the classified contract as identified in the requirement documentation as follows:</p>
               <ol id="d210e140" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e76">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Nondefense agencies that have industrial security services agreements with DoD, and DoD components, shall use the Contract Security Classification Specification, DD Form 254. The contracting officer, or authorized agency representative, is the approving official for the DD Form 254 associated with the prime contract and shall ensure the DD Form 254 is properly prepared, distributed by and coordinated with requirements and security personnel in accordance with agency procedures, see <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref "
                              base="FAR_4_402"
                              href="4.402.dita#FAR_4_402">4.402</xref>(d)(1).</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d212e84">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Contracting officers in agencies not covered by the NISP shall follow agency procedures.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
