<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_43_101" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">43.101</ph> Definitions.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d2594e8"> As used in this part— </p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_43.101"
               xtrc="d2584e18"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Administrative change</i> means a unilateral (see <xref href="43.103.dita#FAR_43_103"
                  base="i1074036"
                  outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                  class="- topic/xref ">43.103</xref>(b)) contract change, in writing, that does not affect the substantive rights of the parties (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.</i>, a change in the paying office or the appropriation data).</p>
         <p class="- topic/p ">
            <i outputclass="Term"
               xtrf="_43.101"
               xtrc="d2584e30"
               class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Effective date</i>-<ol id="d2558e28" class="- topic/ol ">
               <li class="- topic/li ">
                  <ol id="d2558e32" class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d2584e28">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> For a solicitation amendment, change order, or administrative change, the effective date shall be the issue date of the amendment, change order, or administrative change.</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d2584e33">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> For a supplemental agreement, the effective date shall be the date agreed upon by the contracting parties.</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d2584e38">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> For a modification issued as a confirming notice of termination for the convenience of the Government, the effective date of the confirming notice shall be the same as the effective date of the initial notice.</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d2584e43">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> For a modification converting a termination for default to a termination for the convenience of the Government, the effective date shall be the same as the effective date of the termination for default.</p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d2584e48">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph> For a modification confirming the termination contracting officer’s previous letter determination of the amount due in settlement of a contract termination for convenience, the effective date shall be the same as the effective date of the previous letter determination.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </li>
            </ol>
         </p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
