<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_44_202_1" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">44.202-1</ph> Responsibilities.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d2582e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2608e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The cognizant administrative contracting officer (ACO) is responsible for consent to subcontracts, except when the contracting officer retains the contract for administration or withholds the consent responsibility from delegation to the ACO. In such cases, the contract administration office should assist the contracting office in its evaluation as requested.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2608e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            The contracting officer responsible for consent shall review the contractor’s notification and supporting data to ensure that the proposed subcontract is appropriate for the risks involved and consistent with current policy and sound business judgment.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2608e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            Designation of specific subcontractors during contract negotiations does not in itself satisfy the requirements for advance notification or consent pursuant to the clause at <xref href="52.244-2.dita#FAR_52_244_2"
                        base="i1048325"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.244-2</xref>. However, if, in the opinion of the contracting officer, the advance notification or consent requirements were satisfied for certain subcontracts evaluated during negotiations, the contracting officer shall identify those subcontracts in paragraph (j) of the clause at <xref href="52.244-2.dita#FAR_52_244_2"
                        base="i1048325"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.244-2</xref>.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
