<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_46_104" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">46.104</ph> Contract administration office responsibilities.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p ">When a contract is assigned for administration to the contract administration office cognizant of the contractor’s plant, that office, unless specified otherwise, shall-</p>
         <ol id="d2648e16" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e12">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Develop and apply efficient procedures for performing Government contract quality assurance actions under the contract in accordance with the written direction of the contracting office;</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e17">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Perform all actions necessary to verify whether the supplies or services conform to contract quality requirements;</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e22">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            Maintain, as part of the performance records of the contract, suitable records reflecting-</p>
               <ol id="d2648e44" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e28">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
								                The nature of Government contract quality assurance actions, including, when appropriate, the number of observations made and the number and type of defects; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e33">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
								                Decisions regarding the acceptability of the products, the processes, and the requirements, as well as action to correct defects.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e38">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            Implement any specific written instructions from the contracting office;</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e43">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
						            Report to the contracting office any defects observed in design or technical requirements, including contract quality requirements; and</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d2674e48">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
						            Recommend any changes necessary to the contract, specifications, instructions, or other requirements that will provide more effective operations or eliminate unnecessary costs (see <xref href="46.103.dita#FAR_46_103"
                        base="i1072516"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">46.103</xref>(c)).</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
