<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_5_503" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">5.503</ph> Procedures.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d347e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d361e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            General.</p>
               <ol id="d347e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d361e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Orders for paid advertisements may be placed directly with the media or through an advertising agency. Contracting officers shall give small, small disadvantaged, women-owned, veteran-owned, HUBZone, and service-disabled veteran-owned small business concerns maximum opportunity to participate in these acquisitions.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d361e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                The contracting officer shall use the <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/solicitationcontractorder-commercial-items"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">SF 1449</xref> for paper solicitations. The <xref href="https://www.gsa.gov/forms-library/solicitationcontractorder-commercial-items"
                              format="html"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">SF 1449</xref> shall be used to make awards or place orders unless the award/order is made by using electronic commerce or by using the Governmentwide commercial purchase card for micropurchases.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d361e32">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Rates.</i> Advertisements may be paid for at rates not over the commercial rates charged private individuals, with the usual discounts (44 U.S.C. 3703).</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d361e42">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Proof of advertising.</i> Every invoice for advertising shall be accompanied by a copy of the advertisement or an affidavit of publication furnished by the publisher, radio or television station, or advertising agency concerned (44 U.S.C. 3703). Paying offices shall retain the proof of advertising until the Government Accountability Office settles the paying office’s account.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d361e52">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Payment.</i> Upon receipt of an invoice supported by proof of advertising, the contracting officer shall attach a copy of the written authority (see <xref href="5.502.dita#FAR_5_502"
                        base="i1120411"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">5.502</xref>(a)) and submit the invoice for payment under agency procedures.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
