<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_247_58" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.247-58</ph> Loading, Blocking, and Bracing of Freight Car Shipments.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3736e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="47.305-15.dita#FAR_47_305_15"
                     base="i1070774"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">47.305-15</xref>(a)(2)</ph>, insert the following clause in solicitations and contracts when supplies may be shipped in carload lots by rail:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3736e15">Loading, Blocking, and Bracing of Freight Car Shipments <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3692e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3736e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            Upon receipt of shipping instructions, as provided in this contract, the supplies to be included in any carload shipment by rail shall be loaded, blocked, and braced by the Contractor in accordance with the standards published by the Association of American Railroads and effective at the time of shipment.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3736e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Shipments, for which the Association of American Railroads has published no such standards, shall be loaded, blocked, and braced in accordance with standards established by the shipper as evidenced by written acceptance of an authorized representative of the carrier.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3736e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The Contractor shall be liable for payment of any damage to any supplies caused by the failure to load, block, and brace in accordance with acceptable standards set forth herein.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3736e36">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            A copy of the appropriate pamphlet of the Association of American Railroads may be obtained from that Association.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
