<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_219_28"
            xtrc="VFI GFI"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept ">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.219-28</ph>
         Postaward Small Business Program Rerepresentation.
      </title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e8">As prescribed
in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref base="i1101433"
                     href="19.309.dita#FAR_19_309"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">19.309</xref>(c)(1)</ph>, insert
the following clause:</p>
         <p id="d3302e15" outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" class="- topic/p "> Postaward Small Business Program Rerepresentation (Jan 2025) </p>
         <ol id="d3264e27" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e19">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>.
As used in this clause—</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e25">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.219-28"
                     xtrc="d5e28"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Long-term contract</i> means
a contract of more than five years in duration, including options.
However, the term does not include contracts that exceed five years
in duration because the period of performance has been extended
for a cumulative period not to exceed six months under the clause
at <xref base="i1057214"
                        href="52.217-8.dita#FAR_52_217_8"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">52.217-8</xref>, Option to Extend
Services, or other appropriate authority.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e32">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.219-28"
                     xtrc="d5e37"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Small
business concern</i>— <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e38">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                           
                           
                           
                           
                           Means
                              a concern, including its affiliates, that is
                              independently owned and operated, not dominant in
                              its field of operation, and qualified as a small
                              business under the criteria in <xref format="html"
                                 href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/part-121"
                                 scope="external"
                                 class="- topic/xref ">13 CFR part
                                 121</xref> and the size standard in paragraph
                              (d) of this
                              clause.
                        </p>
                     </li>
                     <li class="- topic/li ">
                        <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e43">
                           <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                           <i outputclass="Term"
                              xtrf="_52.219-28"
                              xtrc="d5e54"
                              class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Affiliates</i>,
as used in this definition, means business concerns, one of whom
directly or indirectly controls or has the power to control the
others, or a third party or parties control or have the power to
control the others. In determining whether affiliation exists, consideration
is given to all appropriate factors including common ownership,
common management, and contractual relationships. SBA determines
affiliation based on the factors set forth at 13 CFR 121.103.</p>
                     </li>
                  </ol>
               </p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e50">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                   If the
Contractor represented that it was any of the small business concerns
identified in <xref href="19.000.dita#FAR_19_000"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.000</xref>(a)(3) prior to
award of this contract, the Contractor shall rerepresent its size
and socioeconomic status according to paragraph (f) of this clause or,
if applicable, paragraph (h) of this clause, upon occurrence of
any of the following:</p>
               <ol id="d3264e67" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e59">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Within 30 days after execution
of a novation agreement or within 30 days after modification of
the contract to include this clause, if the novation agreement was
executed prior to inclusion of this clause in the contract.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e64">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         Within
30 days after a merger or acquisition that does not require a novation
or within 30 days after modification of the contract to include
this clause, if the merger or acquisition occurred prior to inclusion
of this clause in the contract.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e69">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         For long-term
contracts-</p>
                     <ol id="d3264e95" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e75">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                               Within 60 to 120 days prior to
the end of the fifth year of the contract; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e80">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                              
                              
                              
                               Within
60 to 120 days prior to the date specified in the contract for exercising
any option thereafter.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e85">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  If the Contractor represented its status as any of the small business concerns identified at 19.000(a)(3) prior to award of this contract, the Contractor shall rerepresent its size and socioeconomic status according to paragraph (f) of this clause or, if applicable, paragraph (h) of this clause, for the NAICS code assigned to an order (except that paragraphs (c)(1) through (3) of this clause do not apply to an order issued under a Federal Supply Schedule contract at subpart 8.4)—
               </p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3319e98">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        Set aside exclusively for a small business concern identified at 19.000(a)(3) that is issued under an unrestricted multiple-award contract, unless the order is issued under the reserved portion of an unrestricted multiple-award contract ( e.g., an order set aside for a woman-owned small business under a multiple-award contract that is not set-aside, unless the order is issued under the reserved portion of the multiple-award contract);
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3319e104">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        Issued under a multiple-award contract set aside for small businesses that is further set aside for a specific socioeconomic category that differs from the underlying multiple-award contract ( e.g., an order set aside for a HUBZone small business concern under a multiple-award contract that is set aside for small businesses);
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3319e110">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        Issued under the part of the multiple-award contract that is set aside for small businesses that is further set aside for a specific socioeconomic category that differs from the underlying set-aside part of the multiple-award contract ( e.g., an order set aside for a WOSB concern under the part of the multiple-award contract that is partially set aside for small businesses); and
                     </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3319e116">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        When the Contracting Officer explicitly requires it for an order issued under a multiple-award contract, including for an order issued under a Federal Supply Schedule contract (see 8.405-5(b) and 19.301-2(b)(2)).
                     </p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e93">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                   The Contractor
shall rerepresent its size status in accordance with the size standard
in effect at the time of this rerepresentation that corresponds
to the North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) code(s)
assigned to this contract. The small business size standard corresponding
to this NAICS code(s) can be found at <xref format="html"
                        href="https://www.sba.gov/document/support--table-size-standards"
                        scope="external"
                        class="- topic/xref ">https://www.sba.gov/document/support--table-size-standards</xref>.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e101">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                   The small business size standard for a Contractor providing an end item that it does not manufacture, process, or produce itself, for a contract other than a construction or service contract, is 500 employees, or 150 employees for information technology value-added resellers under NAICS code 541519, if the acquisition— </p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e107">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        Was set aside for small business
and has a value above the simplified acquisition threshold;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e112">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        Used the
HUBZone price evaluation preference regardless of dollar value,
unless the Contractor waived the price evaluation preference; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e117">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                        Was an
8(a), HUBZone, service-disabled veteran-owned, economically disadvantaged
women-owned, or women-owned small business set-aside or sole-source
award regardless of dollar value.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e122">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>  Except as provided in paragraph (h) of this clause, the Contractor shall make the representation(s) required by paragraphs (b) and (c) of this clause by validating or updating all its representations in the Representations and Certifications section of the System for Award Management (SAM) and its other data in SAM, as necessary, to ensure that they reflect the Contractor's current status. The Contractor shall notify the contracting officer in writing within the timeframes specified in paragraph (b) of this clause, or with its offer for an order (see paragraph (c) of this clause), that the data have been validated or updated, and provide the date of the validation or update.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e127">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(g)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                   If the
Contractor represented that it was other than a small business concern
prior to award of this contract, the Contractor may, but is not
required to, take the actions required by paragraphs (f) or (h)
of this clause.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e132">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(h)</ph>
                  
                  
                  
                   If the
Contractor does not have representations and certifications in SAM,
or does not have a representation in SAM for the NAICS code applicable
to this contract, the Contractor is required to complete the following
rerepresentation and submit it to the contracting office, along
with the contract number and the date on which the rerepresentation
was completed:</p>
               <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e138">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
                        
                         The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e154"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e157"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a small business concern under <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d1e239"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">NAICS Code _____</cite> assigned to <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d1e242"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">contract number _____</cite>.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e149">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                          [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Complete only if the Contractor represented itself as a small business concern in paragraph (h)(1) of this clause</i>.] The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e172"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e175"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not, a small disadvantaged business concern as defined in <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">13 CFR 124.1001</ph>. </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e166">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                          [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Complete only if the Contractor represented itself as a small business concern in paragraph (h)(1) of this clause.</i>] The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e193"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e196"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a women-owned small business concern.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e180">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                          Women-owned small business (WOSB) joint venture eligible under the WOSB Program. The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e267"
                              xtrf="GFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e270"
                              xtrf="GFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a joint venture that complies with the requirements of <xref format="html"
                              href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.506#p-127.506(a)"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">13 CFR 127.506(a)</xref> through <xref format="html"
                              href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.506#p-127.506(c)"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">(c)</xref>. [<cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d1e300"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">
                           <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">The Contractor shall enter the name and unique entity identifier of each party to the joint venture:</i> __</cite>.] </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e220">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                         Economically disadvantaged women-owned small business (EDWOSB) joint venture. The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d1e301"
                              xtrf="GFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d1e276"
                              xtrf="GFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a joint venture that complies with the requirements of <xref format="html"
                              href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.506#p-127.506(a)"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">13 CFR 127.506(a)</xref> through <xref format="html"
                              href="https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-13/section-127.506#p-127.506(c)"
                              scope="external"
                              class="- topic/xref ">(c)</xref>. [<cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d1e324"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">
                           <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">The Contractor shall enter the name and unique entity identifier of each party to the joint venture:</i> __</cite> .] </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e260">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                          [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Complete only if the Contractor represented itself as a small business concern in paragraph (h)(1) of this clause.</i> ] The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e300"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e303"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a veteran-owned small business concern.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e274">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                          [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Complete only if the Contractor represented itself as a veteran-owned small business concern in paragraph (h)(6) of this clause.</i>] The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e318"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_d77e321"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a service-disabled veteran-owned small business concern.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3309e264">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Service-disabled veteran-owned small business (SDVOSB) joint venture eligible under the SDVOSB Program</i>. The Contractor represents that it <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_wdg_g5l_d1c"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_mtr_h5l_d1c"
                              class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not an SDVOSB joint venture eligible under the SDVOSB Program that complies with the requirements of 13 CFR 128.402. [<cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                              xtrf="VFI"
                              xtrc="52.219-28_e4q_k5l_d1c"
                              class="- topic/cite ">
                           <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">The Contractor shall enter the name and unique entity identifier of each party to the joint venture</i>: __.</cite>] </p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e288">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(9)</ph>
                        
                        
                        
                         [ <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Complete
only if the Contractor represented itself as a small business concern
in paragraph (h)(1) of this clause.</i> ] The Contractor represents
that—</p>
                     <ol class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e297">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph>
                              
                              
                               It <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d77e343"
                                    xtrf="VFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d77e346"
                                    xtrf="VFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a HUBZone small business concern listed, on the date of this representation, on the List of Qualified HUBZone Small Business Concerns maintained by the Small Business Administration, and no material changes in ownership and control, principal office, or HUBZone employee percentage have occurred since it was certified in accordance with 13 CFR part 126; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e308">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph>
                               It <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d77e355"
                                    xtrf="VFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is, <cite outputclass="Checkbox"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d77e358"
                                    xtrf="VFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">□</cite> is not a HUBZone joint venture that complies with the requirements of 13 CFR part 126, and the representation in paragraph (h)(8)(i) of this clause is accurate for each HUBZone small business concern participating in the HUBZone joint venture. [<cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d25e281"
                                    xtrf="VFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">
                                 <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">The Contractor shall enter the names of each of the HUBZone small business concerns participating in the HUBZone joint venture: _____.</i>
                              </cite>] Each HUBZone small business concern participating in the HUBZone joint venture shall submit a separate signed copy of the HUBZone representation.</p>
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e324" outputclass="List4">[<cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d1e411"
                                    xtrf="VFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">
                                 <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contractor to sign and date and insert authorized signer's name and title.____________________________</i>
                              </cite>] </p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
         <section outputclass="Alternate" class="- topic/section "><?FM MARKER [Alt] Start?>
            <p class="- topic/p " id="d3300e333">
               <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Alternate
I</i>
               <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Mar 2020)</ph>. As prescribed
in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
                  <xref base="i1101433"
                        href="19.309.dita#FAR_19_309"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref ">19.309</xref>
               </ph>(c)(2), substitute
the following paragraph (h)(1) for paragraph (h)(1) of the basic
clause:</p>
            <p id="id203KC0R04AX" outputclass="List1" class="- topic/p ">(h)(1)
The Contractor represents its small business size status for each
one of the NAICS codes assigned to this contract.</p>
            <table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0" class="- topic/table ">
               <tgroup cols="2"
                       colsep="0"
                       outputclass="Notitle_norule"
                       rowsep="0"
                       class="- topic/tgroup ">
                  <colspec colname="1"
                           colnum="1"
                           colsep="0"
                           colwidth="50*"
                           rowheader="headers"
                           class="- topic/colspec "/>
                  <colspec colname="2"
                           colnum="2"
                           colsep="0"
                           colwidth="50*"
                           rowheader="headers"
                           class="- topic/colspec "/>
                  <thead class="- topic/thead ">
                     <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                        <entry colname="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">NAICS Code</b>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <b class="+ topic/ph hi-d/b ">Small business concern
(yes/no)</b>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                     </row>
                  </thead>
                  <tbody class="- topic/tbody ">
                     <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                        <entry colname="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d25e330"
                                    xtrf="GFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">________________________________</cite>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d25e334"
                                    xtrf="GFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">________________________________</cite>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                     </row>
                     <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                        <entry colname="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d25e339"
                                    xtrf="GFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">________________________________</cite>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d25e343"
                                    xtrf="GFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">________________________________</cite>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                     </row>
                     <row rowsep="0" class="- topic/row ">
                        <entry colname="1" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d25e348"
                                    xtrf="GFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">________________________________</cite>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2" class="- topic/entry ">
                           <p outputclass="Ctr" class="- topic/p ">
                              <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                                    xtrc="52.219-28_d25e352"
                                    xtrf="GFI"
                                    class="- topic/cite ">________________________________</cite>
                           </p>
                        </entry>
                     </row>
                  </tbody>
               </tgroup>
            </table>
            <p class="- topic/p ">[<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Contracting Officer to insert NAICS codes.</i>]</p>
            <?FM MARKER [Alt] End?>
         </section>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
