<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_242_17" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.242-17</ph> Government Delay
of Work.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3625e8">As prescribed
in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="42.1305.dita#FAR_42_1305"
                     base="i1074542"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">42.1305</xref>(c)</ph>, insert
the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3625e15" outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps">Government Delay of
Work <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3582e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3625e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> If
the performance of all or any part of the work of this contract
is delayed or interrupted (1)by an act of the Contracting Officer
in the administration of this contract that is not expressly or
impliedly authorized by this contract, or (2)by a failure of the
Contracting Officer to act within the time specified in this contract,
or within a reasonable time if not specified, an adjustment (excluding
profit) shall be made for any increase in the cost of performance
of this contract caused by the delay or interruption and the contract
shall be modified in writing accordingly. Adjustment shall also
be made in the delivery or performance dates and any other contractual
term or condition affected by the delay or interruption. However,
no adjustment shall be made under this clause for any delay or interruption
to the extent that performance would have been delayed or interrupted
by any other cause, including the fault or negligence of the Contractor,
or for which an adjustment is provided or excluded under any other
term or condition of this contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3625e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> A claim
under this clause shall not be allowed-</p>
               <ol id="d3582e44" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3625e32">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> For any costs
incurred more than 20 days before the Contractor shall have notified
the Contracting Officer in writing of the act or failure to act
involved; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3625e37">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Unless
the claim, in an amount stated, is asserted in writing as soon as
practicable after the termination of the delay or interruption,
but not later than the day of final payment under the contract.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
