<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_209_11" xtrc="VFI">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.209-11</ph> Representation by Corporations Regarding Delinquent Tax Liability or a Felony Conviction under any Federal Law.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="provision">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3132e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF">
               <xref href="9.104-7.dita#FAR_9_104_7" outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly">9.104-7</xref>(d)</ph>, insert the following provision:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3132e15">Representation by Corporations Regarding Delinquent Tax Liability or a Felony Conviction under any Federal Law <ph outputclass="SmCaps">(Feb 2016)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3098e25">
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3132e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            As required by sections 744 and 745 of Division E of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015 (Pub. L. 113-235), and similar provisions, if contained in subsequent appropriations acts, the Government will not enter into a contract with any corporation that–</p>
               <ol id="d3098e41">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3132e27">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Has any unpaid Federal tax liability that has been assessed, for which all judicial and administrative remedies have been exhausted or have lapsed, and that is not being paid in a timely manner pursuant to an agreement with the authority responsible for collecting the tax liability, where the awarding agency is aware of the unpaid tax liability, unless an agency has considered suspension or debarment of the corporation and made a determination that suspension or debarment is not necessary to protect the interests of the Government; or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3132e32">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Was convicted of a felony criminal violation under any Federal law within the preceding 24 months, where the awarding agency is aware of the conviction, unless an agency has considered suspension or debarment of the corporation and made a determination that this action is not necessary to protect the interests of the Government.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3132e37">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            The Offeror represents that–</p>
               <ol id="d3098e74">
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3132e43">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> It is <cite outputclass="Checkbox" xtrc="52.209-11_d1e77" xtrf="VFI">□</cite> is not <cite outputclass="Checkbox" xtrc="52.209-11_d1e80" xtrf="VFI">□</cite> a corporation that has any unpaid Federal tax liability that has been assessed, for which all judicial and administrative remedies have been exhausted or have lapsed, and that is not being paid in a timely manner pursuant to an agreement with the authority responsible for collecting the tax liability; and</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3132e54">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> It is <cite outputclass="Checkbox" xtrc="52.209-11_d1e92" xtrf="VFI">□</cite> is not <cite outputclass="Checkbox" xtrc="52.209-11_d1e95" xtrf="VFI">□</cite> a corporation that was convicted of a felony criminal violation under a Federal law within the preceding 24 months.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofprovision">(End of provision)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
