<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_216_20"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            xtrc="GFI">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.216-20</ph> Definite Quantity.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3248e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     href="16.506.dita#FAR_16_506"
                     base="i1104242"
                     class="- topic/xref ">16.506</xref>(c)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3248e15">Definite Quantity <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Oct 1995)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3213e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3248e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            This is a definite-quantity, indefinite-delivery contract for the supplies or services specified, and effective for the period stated, in the Schedule.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3248e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            The Government shall order the quantity of supplies or services specified in the Schedule, and the Contractor shall furnish them when ordered. Delivery or performance shall be at locations designated in orders issued in accordance with the Ordering clause and the Schedule.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3248e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            Except for any limitations on quantities in the Order Limitations clause or in the Schedule, there is no limit on the number of orders that may be issued. The Government may issue orders requiring delivery to multiple destinations or performance at multiple locations.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3248e36">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            Any order issued during the effective period of this contract and not completed within that time shall be completed by the Contractor within the time specified in the order. The contract shall govern the Contractor’s and Government’s rights and obligations with respect to that order to the same extent as if the order were completed during the contract’s effective period; provided, that the Contractor shall not be required to make any deliveries under this contract after <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                        xtrc="52.216-20_d3236e60"
                        class="- topic/cite "
                        xtrf="GFI">________________ [<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">insert date</i>]</cite>.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
