<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_247_57"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            xtrc="GFI">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.247-57</ph> Transportation Transit Privilege Credits.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body  concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3735e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     href="47.305-13.dita#FAR_47_305_13"
                     base="i1070753"
                     class="- topic/xref ">47.305-13</xref>(b)(4)</ph>, insert the following clause in solicitations and contracts when supplies are of such a nature, or when it is the custom of the trade, that offerors may have potential transit credits available and the Government may reduce transportation costs through the use of transit credits:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3735e15">Transportation Transit Privilege Credits <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3691e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3735e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            If the offeror has established with regulated common carriers transit privileges that can be applied to the supplies when shipped from the original source, the offeror is invited to propose to use these credits for shipping the supplies to the designated Government destinations. The offeror will ship these supplies under commercial bills of lading, paying all remaining transportation charges connected with the shipment, subject to reimbursement by the Government in an amount equal to the remaining charges but not exceeding the amount quoted by the offeror.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3735e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            After loading on the carrier’s equipment and acceptance by the carrier, these shipments under paid commercial bills of lading will move for the account of and at the risk of the Government (unless, pursuant to the Changes clause, the office administering the contract directs use of Government bills of lading).</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3735e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The amount quoted below by the offeror represents the transportation costs in cents per 100 pounds (freight rate) for full carload/truckload shipments of the supplies from offeror’s original source, via offeror’s transit plant or point, to the Government destination(s) including the carrier’s transit privilege charge, less the applicable transit credit (<i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">i.e.,</i> the amount (rate) initially paid to the carrier for shipment from original source to offeror’s transit plant or point).</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3735e39">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            The rate per CWT quoted will be used by the Government to evaluate the offered f.o.b. origin price unless a lower rate is applicable on the date of bid opening (or closing date specified for receipt of offers). To have the offer evaluated on this basis, the offeror must insert below the remaining transportation charges that the offeror agrees to pay, including any transit charges, subject to reimbursement by the Government, as explained in this clause, to destinations listed in the Schedule as follows:</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3735e43">Rate Per CWT in Cents: <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                        xtrc="52.247-57_d3715e66"
                        class="- topic/cite "
                        xtrf="GFI">________________</cite> To Destination: <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                        xtrc="52.247-57_d3715e69"
                        class="- topic/cite "
                        xtrf="GFI">_______________________</cite>
               </p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p outputclass="Endofclause" class="- topic/p ">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
