<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_226_7" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.226-7</ph> Drug-Free Workplace.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref base="i1094597"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref "
                     href="26.506.dita#FAR_26_506">26.506</xref>
            </ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3377e14">Drug-Free Workplace <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(May 2024)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3338e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Definitions</i>. As used in this clause-</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e26">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.223-6"
                     xtrc="d3373e40"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Controlled substance</i> means a controlled substance in schedules I through V of section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (<xref href="http://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid:USC-prelim-title21-section812&amp;num=0&amp;edition=prelim"
                        scope="external"
                        format="html">21 U.S.C. 812</xref>) and as further defined in regulation at <ph outputclass="CFR" class="- topic/ph ">21 CFR 1308.11</ph> - 1308.15.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e36">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.223-6"
                     xtrc="d3373e49"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Conviction</i> means a finding of guilt (including a plea of <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">nolo contendere</i>) or imposition of sentence, or both, by any judicial body charged with the responsibility to determine violations of the Federal or State criminal drug statutes.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e43">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.223-6"
                     xtrc="d3373e58"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Criminal drug statute</i> means a Federal or non-Federal criminal statute involving the manufacture, distribution, dispensing, possession, or use of any controlled substance.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e47">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.223-6"
                     xtrc="d3373e64"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Drug-free workplace</i> means the site(s) for the performance of work done by the Contractor in connection with a specific contract where employees of the Contractor are prohibited from engaging in the unlawful manufacture, distribution, dispensing, possession, or use of a controlled substance.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e51">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.223-6"
                     xtrc="d3373e71"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Employee</i> means an employee of a Contractor directly engaged in the performance of work under a Government contract. "Directly engaged" is defined to include all direct cost employees and any other Contractor employee who has other than a minimal impact or involvement in contract performance.</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e55">
                  <i outputclass="Term"
                     xtrf="_52.223-6"
                     xtrc="d3373e77"
                     class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">Individual</i> means an offeror/contractor that has no more than one employee including the offeror/contractor.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e60">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph> The Contractor, if other than an individual, shall-within 30 days after award (unless a longer period is agreed to in writing for contracts of 30 days or more performance duration), or as soon as possible for contracts of less than 30 days performance duration-</p>
               <ol id="d3338e75" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e66">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> Publish a statement notifying its employees that the unlawful manufacture, distribution, dispensing, possession, or use of a controlled substance is prohibited in the Contractor’s workplace and specifying the actions that will be taken against employees for violations of such prohibition;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e71">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> Establish an ongoing drug-free awareness program to inform such employees about-</p>
                     <ol id="d3338e94" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e77">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> The dangers of drug abuse in the workplace;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e82">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> The Contractor’s policy of maintaining a drug-free workplace;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e87">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph> Any available drug counseling, rehabilitation, and employee assistance programs; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e92">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph> The penalties that may be imposed upon employees for drug abuse violations occurring in the workplace;</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e97">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> Provide all employees engaged in performance of the contract with a copy of the statement required by paragraph (b)(1) of this clause;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e102">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph> Notify such employees in writing in the statement required by paragraph (b)(1) of this clause that, as a condition of continued employment on this contract, the employee will-</p>
                     <ol id="d3338e151" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e108">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Abide by the terms of the statement; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e113">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Notify the employer in writing of the employee’s conviction under a criminal drug statute for a violation occurring in the workplace no later than 5 days after such conviction;</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e118">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph> Notify the Contracting Officer in writing within 10 days after receiving notice under subdivision (b)(4)(ii) of this clause, from an employee or otherwise receiving actual notice of such conviction. The notice shall include the position title of the employee;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e123">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph> Within 30 days after receiving notice under subdivision (b)(4)(ii) of this clause of a conviction, take one of the following actions with respect to any employee who is convicted of a drug abuse violation occurring in the workplace:</p>
                     <ol id="d3338e191" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e129">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Taking appropriate personnel action against such employee, up to and including termination; or</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e134">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Require such employee to satisfactorily participate in a drug abuse assistance or rehabilitation program approved for such purposes by a Federal, State, or local health, law enforcement, or other appropriate agency; and</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e139">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph> Make a good faith effort to maintain a drug-free workplace through implementation of paragraphs (b)(1) through (b)(6) of this clause.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e144">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> The Contractor, if an individual, agrees by award of the contract or acceptance of a purchase order, not to engage in the unlawful manufacture, distribution, dispensing, possession, or use of a controlled substance while performing this contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3377e149">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph> In addition to other remedies available to the Government, the Contractor’s failure to comply with the requirements of paragraph (b) or (c) of this clause may, pursuant to FAR 
                     <xref base="i1094597"
                        outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                        class="- topic/xref "
                        href="26.505.dita#FAR_26_505">26.505</xref>, render the Contractor subject to suspension of contract payments, termination of the contract or default, and suspension or debarment.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
