<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_227_19"
            class="- topic/topic concept/concept "
            xtrc="VFI">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.227-19</ph> Commercial Computer Software License.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="27.409.dita#FAR_27_409"
                     base="i1089472"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">27.409</xref>(g)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3451e15">Commercial Computer Software License <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Dec 2007)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3412e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph> Notwithstanding any contrary provisions contained in the Contractor’s standard commercial license or lease agreement, the Contractor agrees that the Government will have the rights that are set forth in paragraph (b) of this clause to use, duplicate or disclose any commercial computer software delivered under this contract. The terms and provisions of this contract shall comply with Federal laws and the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</p>
            </li>
            <li props="Runin" class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
               </p>
               <ol id="d3412e44" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e31">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph> The commercial computer software delivered under this contract may not be used, reproduced, or disclosed by the Government except as provided in paragraph (b)(2) of this clause or as expressly stated otherwise in this contract.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e36">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph> The commercial computer software may be-</p>
                     <ol id="d3412e63" class="- topic/ol ">
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e42">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(i)</ph> Used or copied for use with the computer(s) for which it was acquired, including use at any Government installation to which the computer(s) may be transferred;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e47">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(ii)</ph> Used or copied for use with a backup computer if any computer for which it was acquired is inoperative;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e52">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iii)</ph> Reproduced for safekeeping (archives) or backup purposes;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e57">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(iv)</ph> Modified, adapted, or combined with other computer software, provided that the modified, adapted, or combined portions of the derivative software incorporating any of the delivered, commercial computer software shall be subject to same restrictions set forth in this contract;</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e62">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(v)</ph> Disclosed to and reproduced for use by support service Contractors or their subcontractors, subject to the same restrictions set forth in this contract; and</p>
                        </li>
                        <li class="- topic/li ">
                           <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e67">
                              <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(vi)</ph> Used or copied for use with a replacement computer.</p>
                        </li>
                     </ol>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e72">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph> If the commercial computer software is otherwise available without disclosure restrictions, the Contractor licenses it to the Government without disclosure restrictions.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e77">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph> The Contractor shall affix a notice substantially as follows to any commercial computer software delivered under this contract:</p>
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3451e81">
                  <term class="- topic/term ">Notice</term>-Notwithstanding any other lease or license agreement that may pertain to, or accompany the delivery of, this computer software, the rights of the Government regarding its use, reproduction and disclosure are as set forth in <cite outputclass="SingleLine"
                        xtrf="VFI"
                        xtrc="52.227-19_d1g_vc4_21c"
                        class="- topic/cite ">Government Contract No.___________________________</cite>.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
