<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_236_23" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.236-23</ph> Responsibility of the Architect-Engineer Contractor.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3573e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="36.609-2.dita#FAR_36_609_2"
                     base="i1078549"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">36.609-2</xref>(b)</ph>, insert the following clause:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3573e15">Responsibility of the Architect-Engineer Contractor <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3529e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3573e21">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            The Contractor shall be responsible for the professional quality, technical accuracy, and the coordination of all designs, drawings, specifications, and other services furnished by the Contractor under this contract. The Contractor shall, without additional compensation, correct or revise any errors or deficiencies in its designs, drawings, specifications, and other services.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3573e26">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            Neither the Government’s review, approval or acceptance of, nor payment for, the services required under this contract shall be construed to operate as a waiver of any rights under this contract or of any cause of action arising out of the performance of this contract, and the Contractor shall be and remain liable to the Government in accordance with applicable law for all damages to the Government caused by the Contractor’s negligent performance of any of the services furnished under this contract.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3573e31">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            The rights and remedies of the Government provided for under this contract are in addition to any other rights and remedies provided by law.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3573e36">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
						            If the Contractor is comprised of more than one legal entity, each such entity shall be jointly and severally liable hereunder.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
