<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_52_247_46" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">52.247-46</ph> Shipping Point(s) Used in Evaluation of F.o.b. Origin Offers.</title>
      <conbody outputclass="clause" class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <p class="- topic/p " id="d3724e8">As prescribed in <ph outputclass="ClauseProvisionXREF" class="- topic/ph ">
               <xref href="47.305-3.dita#FAR_47_305_3"
                     base="i1070563"
                     outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                     class="- topic/xref ">47.305-3</xref>
            </ph>(b)(4)(ii), insert the following provision in f.o.b. origin solicitations when price evaluation for shipments from various shipping points is contemplated:</p>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Ctr_SmCaps" id="d3724e14">Shipping Point(s) Used in Evaluation of F.o.b. Origin Offers <ph outputclass="SmCaps" class="- topic/ph ">(Apr 1984)</ph>
         </p>
         <ol id="d3680e25" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3724e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
						            If more than one shipping point or plant is designated by the offeror and the offeror fails to indicate the quantity per shipping point or plant before bid opening, the Government will evaluate the offer on the basis of delivery of the entire quantity from the point or plant where cost of transportation is most favorable to the Government.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3724e25">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
						            If the offeror, before bid opening (or the closing date specified for receipt of offers) fails to indicate any shipping point or plant, the Government will evaluate the offer on the basis of delivery from the plant at which the contract will be performed, as indicated in the offer. If no plant is indicated in the offer, the offer will be evaluated on the basis of delivery from the Contractor’s business address indicated in the offer.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d3724e30">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
						            If the offeror uses a shipping point other than that which has been used by the Government as a basis for the evaluation of offers, any increase of transportation costs shall be borne by the Contractor and any savings shall revert to the Government.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
         <p class="- topic/p " outputclass="Endofclause">(End of clause)</p>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
