<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_8_707" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">8.707</ph> Prices.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d500e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d515e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            The prices of items on the Procurement List are fair market prices established by the Committee. All prices for supplies ordered under this subpart are f.o.b. origin.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d515e15">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            Prices for supplies are normally adjusted semiannually. Prices for services are normally adjusted annually.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d515e20">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(c)</ph>
                  
						            The Committee may request the agency responsible for acquiring the supplies or service to assist it in establishing or revising the fair market price. The Committee has the authority to establish prices without prior coordination with the responsible contracting office.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d515e25">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(d)</ph>
                  
						            Price changes shall normally apply to all orders received by the AbilityOne participating nonprofit agency on or after the effective date of the change. In special cases, after considering the views of the ordering office, the Committee may make price changes applicable to orders received by the AbilityOne participating nonprofit agency prior to the effective date of the change.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d515e30">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(e)</ph>
                  
						            If an ordering office desires packing, packaging, or marking of supplies other than the standard pack as provided on the Procurement List, any difference in costs shall be included as a separate item on the nonprofit agency’s invoice. The ordering office shall reimburse the nonprofit agency for these costs.</p>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d515e35">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(f)</ph>
                  
						            Ordering offices may make recommendations to the Committee at any time for price revisions for supplies and services on the Procurement List.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
