<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita>
   <concept id="FAR_9_207" class="- topic/topic concept/concept " xtrc="">
      <title class="- topic/title ">
         <ph class="- topic/ph " props="autonumber">9.207</ph> Changes in status regarding qualification requirements.</title>
      <conbody class="- topic/body concept/conbody ">
         <ol id="d564e13" class="- topic/ol ">
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e10">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(a)</ph>
                  
						            The contracting officer shall promptly report to the agency activity which established the qualification requirement any conditions which may merit removal or omission from a QPL, QML, or QBL or affect whether a source should continue to be otherwise identified as meeting the requirement. These conditions exist when-</p>
               <ol id="d564e23" class="- topic/ol ">
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e16">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(1)</ph>
                        
								                Products or services are submitted for inspection or acceptance that do not meet the qualification requirement;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e21">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(2)</ph>
                        
								                Products or services were previously rejected and the defects were not corrected when submitted for inspection or acceptance;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e26">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(3)</ph>
                        
								                A supplier fails to request reevaluation following change of location or ownership of the plant where the product which met the qualification requirement was manufactured (see the clause at <xref href="52.209-1.dita#FAR_52_209_1"
                              base="id165RA01N0KN"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">52.209-1</xref>, Qualification Requirements);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e34">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(4)</ph>
                        
								                A manufacturer of a product which met the qualification requirement has discontinued manufacture of the product;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e39">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(5)</ph>
                        
								                A source requests removal from a QPL, QML, or QBL;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e44">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(6)</ph>
                        
								                A condition of meeting the qualification requirement was violated; <i class="+ topic/ph hi-d/i ">e.g.,</i> advertising or publicity contrary to <xref href="9.204.dita#FAR_9_204"
                              base="i1115894"
                              outputclass="fm:ParaNumOnly"
                              class="- topic/xref ">9.204</xref>(h)(5);</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e55">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(7)</ph>
                        
								                A revised specification imposes a new qualification requirement;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e60">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(8)</ph>
                        
								                Manufacturing or design changes have been incorporated in the qualification requirement;</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e65">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(9)</ph>
                        
								                The source is listed in the System for Award Management Exclusions (see <xref href="Subpart_9.4.dita#FAR_Subpart_9_4"
                              base="i1115147"
                              outputclass="fm:Subpart"
                              class="- topic/xref ">subpart  9.4</xref>); or</p>
                  </li>
                  <li class="- topic/li ">
                     <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e73">
                        <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(10)</ph>
                        
								                Performance of a contract subject to a qualification requirement is otherwise unsatisfactory.</p>
                  </li>
               </ol>
            </li>
            <li class="- topic/li ">
               <p class="- topic/p " id="d591e78">
                  <ph props="autonumber" class="- topic/ph ">(b)</ph>
                  
						            After considering any of the above or other conditions reasonably related to whether a product or source continues to meet the standards specified for qualification, an agency may take appropriate action without advance notification. The agency shall, however, promptly notify the affected parties if a product or source is removed from a QPL, QML, or QBL, or will no longer be identified as meeting the standards specified for qualification. This notice shall contain specific information why the product or source no longer meets the qualification requirement.</p>
            </li>
         </ol>
      </conbody>
   </concept>
</dita>
